<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/AT/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in AT</title>
  <updated>2018-02-07T20:25:56+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-hate-speech-case-should-facebook-process-more-personal-data</id>
      <title>CJEU hate speech case: Should Facebook process more personal data?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-hate-speech-case-should-facebook-process-more-personal-data" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:25:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Austria’s Supreme Court of Justice has referred a case to the Court of Justice of the European Union regarding hate speech on social media platforms. The referral could have a global impact on Facebook – and ultimately on our privacy and freedom of speech.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/success-story-a-win-on-austrian-surveillance-legislation</id>
      <title>Success Story: A win on Austrian surveillance legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/success-story-a-win-on-austrian-surveillance-legislation" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:56:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The security debate in many countries shows an alarming trend towards restrictions of fundamental rights that liberal societies have codified in the past centuries. Particularly in the field of surveillance, recent legislation often goes beyond what has been deemed constitutional by courts and lacks any fact-based justification as to how those measures are supposed to prevent or mitigate serious crime. Advocacy groups rarely achieve a victory in this debate. Hence, it is worth taking a closer look at a recent example from Austria where such legislation was prevented by EDRi member NGO &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://epicenter.works&quot;&gt;epicenter.works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-surveillance-package-in-austria-sparks-resistance</id>
      <title>Proposed surveillance package in Austria sparks resistance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-surveillance-package-in-austria-sparks-resistance" />
      <updated>2017-04-24T02:19:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Epicenter.works reports that the Austrian coalition parties have renegotiated their government programme in January 2017. This new programme contains a so-called “security package” that encompasses the introduction of several new surveillance measures and additional powers for the Austrian security agencies. These changes in the law are to be implemented by June 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/personal-data-of-550000-red-cross-blood-donors-was-breached</id>
      <title>Personal data of 550,000 Red Cross blood donors was breached</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/personal-data-of-550000-red-cross-blood-donors-was-breached" />
      <updated>2016-11-02T19:09:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian Red Cross said its blood donor service has found that registration information of 550,000 donors had been compromised, which the agency blamed on human error by a third-party contractor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The moot issue at this point, which may decide how the breach unfolds, is that nobody knows how many people have the data. The information from 2010 to 2016 was available on the website from Sept. 5 to Oct. 25. this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The database backup, consisting of 1.74GB with about 1.3 million records, contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-red-cross-blood-service-australias-largest-ever-leak-of-personal-data/&quot;&gt;information about blood donors&lt;/a&gt;, such as name, gender, physical address, email address, phone number, date of birth, blood type, country of birth, and previous donations, according to security researcher Troy Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-ministry-of-interiour-wants-to-push-further-on-trojan-u</id>
      <title>Austrian Ministry of Interior wants to push further on trojan usage</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-ministry-of-interiour-wants-to-push-further-on-trojan-u" />
      <updated>2016-09-30T13:02:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Austrias new law on &quot;electronic surveillance by malware&quot; was stopped by the Ministry of Justice as &quot;making no sense&quot; after receiving hard criticism. Now the Ministry of Interior wants further discussion on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-experts-say-internet-surveillance-has-terrorism-like-eff</id>
      <title>Privacy experts say: Internet surveillance has terrorism-like effects</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-experts-say-internet-surveillance-has-terrorism-like-eff" />
      <updated>2016-09-30T13:00:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy experts of austrian &quot;AK Vorrat&quot; published a handbook on evaluation of anti-terror laws in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In their presentation they claim that the expansion of public surveillance and missing checks and balances gives the impression that the state does not behave lawfully online and that this impression has effects like terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-court-refers-facebook-privacy-case-to-european-court</id>
      <title>Austrian court refers Facebook privacy case to European court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-court-refers-facebook-privacy-case-to-european-court" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T17:04:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An attempt by Austrian privacy activist Max Schrems to have a data protection case against Facebook (FB.O) heard as a class action suit moved a step ahead on Monday when Austria&#039;s Supreme Court referred the question to the European Court of Justice (CJEU).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook has questioned the right of Schrems to bring a Europe-wide class action on behalf of tens of thousands of consumers. Schrems is claiming 500 euros ($562) in damages for each of more than 25,000 signatories to his lawsuit, one of a series of European challenges to U.S. technology firms and their handling of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-pirate-party-starts-out-of-the-box-privacy-campaign-bef</id>
      <title>Austrian Pirate Party starts out of the box privacy campaign before elections</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-pirate-party-starts-out-of-the-box-privacy-campaign-bef" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T14:16:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Austria local politicians are slowly trying to increase state surveillance through the new State Protection Act which will increase monitoring. With elections coming up in the Linz region next week the party decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.piratenpartei.at/pressesprecher-des-innenministeriums-johanna-schaut-bei-besonderen-aktivitaeten-nicht-zu/&quot;&gt;advertise their policy&lt;/a&gt;, but not on the regular outfits most political parties prefer.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-court-rejects-facebook-privacy-case</id>
      <title>Austrian court rejects Facebook privacy case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austrian-court-rejects-facebook-privacy-case" />
      <updated>2015-07-01T22:00:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A court in Vienna declines to hear a legal case involving allegations that Facebook has broken EU data privacy laws. The court rejected the case brought by Max Schrems saying that it lacked jurisdiction in the matter.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austria-court-considers-facebook-privacy-case</id>
      <title>Austria court considers Facebook privacy case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/austria-court-considers-facebook-privacy-case" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T18:29:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A court in Austria will rule in the next few weeks whether it has the jurisdiction to hear a class action lawsuit brought against Facebook. Some 25,000 users - led by Austrian law graduate Max Schrems - accuse Facebook of violating European privacy laws in the way it collects and forwards data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-vs-facebook-class-action-attracts-over-60-000-plaintiffs</id>
      <title>Europe vs. Facebook class action attracts over 60 000 plaintiffs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-vs-facebook-class-action-attracts-over-60-000-plaintiffs" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T12:59:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy activist Max Schrems filed suit in front of a court in his home country, Austria, and he asked the public to join him: it was possible for any Facebook user of age who is not located in the USA or Canada to join the legal battle against Facebook’s numerous alleged violations of European privacy laws. This is due to the fact that every Facebook user worldwide, living outside of the US or Canada, has a contract with Facebook Ireland Ltd. Mr. Schrems is claiming 500 Euro in symbolic damages per contributing joint plaintiff for alleged privacy violations such as Facebook contributing to NSA´s PRISM program, Graph Search, the Facebook app or third party tracking via “Like Buttons”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russia-and-austria-take-action-against-use-of-tor</id>
      <title>Russia and Austria take action against use of Tor</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russia-and-austria-take-action-against-use-of-tor" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T16:22:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tor (The Onion Router) is an anonymity network that directs Internet traffic through a worldwide volunteer network that consists of relays, known as nodes, concealing the location and usage details of users, to protect their privacy. It is used for example by journalists and political activists to guarantee the confidentiality of their communications, but can also be used by criminals to hide their tracks from law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
