<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/Global/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in Global</title>
  <updated>2018-02-20T11:59:29+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-top-court-backs-order-for-google-to-remove-firms-website</id>
      <title>Canada&#039;s top court backs order for Google to remove firm&#039;s website from global searches</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-top-court-backs-order-for-google-to-remove-firms-website" />
      <updated>2017-06-29T11:54:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court of Canada has upheld a B.C. court ruling that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/google-ordered-by-b-c-judge-to-block-website-from-search-results-1.2679824&quot;&gt;ordered Google to remove the website&lt;/a&gt; of a company from its global search results.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wikipedia-blocked-in-turkey-turkey-blocks</id>
      <title>Wikipedia blocked in Turkey</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wikipedia-blocked-in-turkey-turkey-blocks" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:59:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Turkey Blocks monitoring network has verified&amp;nbsp;restrictions affecting&amp;nbsp;the Wikipedia online encyclopaedia in Turkey. A block affecting all language editions of the website detected at 8:00AM local time Saturday 29 April, 2017. The loss of availability is consistent with internet filters used to censor content in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/world-wide-web-consortium-abandons-consensus-and-decides-to-stan</id>
      <title>World Wide Web Consortium abandons consensus and decides to standardize DRM</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/world-wide-web-consortium-abandons-consensus-and-decides-to-stan" />
      <updated>2017-09-19T13:35:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;World Wide Web Consortium &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2017/07/07/eschatology-watch.html&quot;&gt;overruled dozens of members&#039; objections&lt;/a&gt; to publishing a DRM standard without a compromise to protect accessibility, security research, archiving, and competition. EFF &lt;a href=&quot;https://boingboing.net/2017/07/12/save-the-web.html&quot;&gt;appealed the decision&lt;/a&gt; which concluded with a deeply divided membership. Only 58.4% of the group voted to go on with publication. This is an unprecedented move in a body that has always operated on consensus and compromise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ntia-approves-iana-transition-proposal</id>
      <title>NTIA approves IANA transition proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ntia-approves-iana-transition-proposal" />
      <updated>2016-06-15T00:54:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Commerce Department’s National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) announced today that the proposal developed by the global Internet multistakeholder community meets the criteria NTIA outlined in March 2014 when it stated its intent to transition the U.S. Government’s stewardship role for the Internet domain name system (DNS) technical functions, known as the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) functions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IANA Stewardship Transition Proposal assessment report is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntia.doc.gov/report/2016/iana-stewardship-transition-proposal-assessment-report&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and more details are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntia.doc.gov/other-publication/2016/q-and-iana-stewardship-transition&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cloud-computing-legislation-in-south-korea</id>
      <title>New cloud computing legislation in South Korea</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cloud-computing-legislation-in-south-korea" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T17:58:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On September 9, 2015, the South Korean Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning (the “MSIP”) established and announced the “Information Protection Measures for Vitalization of Cloud Services” in anticipation that the use of cloud computing would actively increase based on the implementation of the Act on Cloud Computing Advancement and User Protection (the “Cloud Computing Act”) on September 28, 2015. The Cloud Computing Act was legislated in March of this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MSIP plans to push ahead with the following tasks in phases until 2019 in order to alleviate concerns regarding information protection for cloud users and to foster a safe cloud use environment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-apple-is-paving-the-way-to-a-cloud-dictatorship-in-china-hon</id>
      <title>How Apple is paving the way to a ‘cloud dictatorship’ in China</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-apple-is-paving-the-way-to-a-cloud-dictatorship-in-china-hon" />
      <updated>2018-02-20T11:59:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US-based global tech giant Apple Inc. is set to hand over the operation of its iCloud data center in mainland China to a local corporation called Guizhou-Cloud Big Data (GCBD) by February 28, 2018.&amp;nbsp;Once the agreement is signed, GCBD — a company solely owned by the state — would get a key that can access all iCloud user data in China, legally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-gdpr-meets-whois-privacy-which-way-forward</id>
      <title>Europe&#039;s GDPR meets WHOIS privacy: which way forward?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-gdpr-meets-whois-privacy-which-way-forward" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:21:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Europe&#039;s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) will come into effect in May 2018, and with it, a new set of tough penalties for companies that fail to adequately protect the personal data of European users. Amongst those affected are domain name registries and registrars, who are required by ICANN, the global domain name authority, to list the personal information of domain name registrants in publicly-accessible WHOIS directories. ICANN and European registrars have &lt;a href=&quot;http://domainincite.com/22218-amsterdam-refuses-to-publish-whois-records-as-gdpr-row-escalates&quot;&gt;clashed over this long-standing contractual requirement&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/just/document.cfm?doc_id=48839&quot;&gt;does not comply&lt;/a&gt; with European data protection law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was one of the highest profile topics at ICANN&#039;s 60th meeting in Abu Dhabi which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/resources/pages/contractual-compliance-statement-2017-11-02-en&quot;&gt;EFF attended last year&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;with registries and registrars laying the blame on ICANN, either for their liability under the GDPR if they complied with their WHOIS obligations, or for their contractual liability to ICANN if they didn&#039;t. ICANN has recognized this and has progressively, if belatedly, being taking steps to remediate the clash between its own rules, and the data protection principles that European law upholds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mozilla-files-suit-against-fcc-to-protect-net-neutrality-the-moz</id>
      <title>Mozilla files suit against FCC to protect net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mozilla-files-suit-against-fcc-to-protect-net-neutrality-the-moz" />
      <updated>2018-01-20T00:03:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has filed a petition in federal court in Washington, DC against the Federal Communications Commission for its recent decision to overturn the 2015 Open Internet Order.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-year-the-open-internet-came-under-siege-2017-year-in-review</id>
      <title>The year the open Internet came under siege: 2017 year in review</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-year-the-open-internet-came-under-siege-2017-year-in-review" />
      <updated>2018-01-06T11:11:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fight between the Federal Communications Commission’s choice to abandon the principles of net neutrality and the majority of Americans started early in 2017 and continued into the very last month of the year. Check out EFF&#039;s year in review on net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/paradigm-shifts-for-the-decentralized-web-ruben-verborgh</id>
      <title>Paradigm shifts for the decentralized Web</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/paradigm-shifts-for-the-decentralized-web-ruben-verborgh" />
      <updated>2018-02-12T11:07:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The basis of decentralization is that people choose where they store their data. Instead of having to pick between a handful of providers such Google or Facebook, in a decentralized world, there will be many options to pick from—and we are free to create our own.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-repeals-net-neutrality-rules-the-new-york-times</id>
      <title>FCC Repeals Net Neutrality Rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-repeals-net-neutrality-rules-the-new-york-times" />
      <updated>2017-12-20T12:48:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Federal Communications Commission voted on Thursday December 14th 2017 to dismantle rules regulating the businesses that connect consumers to the Internet, granting broadband companies the power to potentially reshape Americans’ online experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/resolution-on-transparency-of-trade-negotiations-endorsed-at-un</id>
      <title>Resolution on transparency of trade negotiations endorsed at UN Internet Governance Forum meeting</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/resolution-on-transparency-of-trade-negotiations-endorsed-at-un" />
      <updated>2017-12-20T13:34:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;EFF&#039;s involvement during the last two Internet Governance Forum meetings led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/igf-dynamic-coalition-trade-and-internet-resolution-transparency&quot;&gt;resolution on transparency&lt;/a&gt; which was drafted in a multistakeholder process and which was endorsed by participants at the meeting by rough consensus.&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;The recommendations are similar to those that EFF and other groups and experts &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/01/does-trumps-withdrawal-tpp-signal-new-approach-trade-agreements&quot;&gt;delivered to the United States Trade Representative&lt;/a&gt; in January this year, which were in turn influenced by the previous year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2016/03/15/brussels_declaration.pdf&quot;&gt;Brussels Declaration on Trade and the Internet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-censorship-detection-tool</id>
      <title>Internet Censorship Detection Tool</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-censorship-detection-tool" />
      <updated>2017-11-14T18:36:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Internet censorship enables governments to manipulate public discourse and erode citizens’ rights. But a five-year-old software program called ooniprobe allows users to fight back, by finding our when, where, and how censorship is occurring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ooniprobe is free and open software designed to detect blocking of Internet websites, messenger apps, censorship circumvention tools, speed and performance of your network, or presence in certain systems in the network which might be responsible for censorship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tool was developed by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://ooni.torproject.org/install/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coe-and-kaspersky-lab-sign-agreement-on-human-rights</id>
      <title>CoE and Kaspersky Lab sign agreement on human rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coe-and-kaspersky-lab-sign-agreement-on-human-rights" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:46:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe (CoE) and Russian antivirus software developer Kaspersky Lab, as well as other IT and Internet companies &lt;a href=&quot;http://tass.com/society/974694&quot;&gt;signed an agreement&lt;/a&gt; during the World Forum for Democracy &#039;on protection of human rights and guaranteeing compliance with laws in the Internet&#039;, according to Kaspersky Lab. The signed agreement is a step of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edoc.coe.int/en/internet/7128-internet-governance-council-of-europe-strategy-2016-2019.html&quot;&gt;CoE Internet Governance Strategy for 2016-2019&lt;/a&gt;. The strategy supports and protects citizens on the Internet, &#039;guaranteeing respect for their rights, ensuring equality and freedom of expression, and combating cybercrime and terrorism,&#039; according to the statement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-jurisdiction-does-icann-belong-to</id>
      <title>What “jurisdiction” does ICANN belong to?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-jurisdiction-does-icann-belong-to" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:36:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How far can ICANN go to escape the nation-state? ICANN 60 (held in Abu Dhabi October 28 – Nov 3rd) made important progress on what has become known as “the jurisdiction issue”. ICANN is taking steps to reduce or eliminate the effect that U.S. sanctions against foreign governments would have on ordinary Internet users and businesses in sanctioned countries. It will also introduce choice of law provisions in their registry and registrar contracts, and open up continuing discussions of whether additional immunities are needed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-to-icanns-registrars-dont-pick-up-the-censors-pen</id>
      <title>EFF to ICANN&#039;s registrars: don&#039;t pick up the censor&#039;s pen</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-to-icanns-registrars-dont-pick-up-the-censors-pen" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:31:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;EFF is speaking out against the increasing use of the domain name system as a mechanism for content censorship during the annual general meeting of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/icann&quot;&gt;ICANN&lt;/a&gt;, the global multi-stakeholder regulatory authority for Internet domain names and IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in August, you may recall that domain name registrars GoDaddy and Google both terminated service to the publisher of the odious Nazi website Daily Stormer, in a move that, while popular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/08/fighting-neo-nazis-future-free-expression&quot;&gt;set a dangerous precedent&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-research-paper-on-content-regulation-and-domain-name-policy</id>
      <title>New research paper on content regulation and domain name policy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-research-paper-on-content-regulation-and-domain-name-policy" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:40:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Should domain name registrars have the right to cancel a domain because they don’t like the content of the website it supports? How many registrars’ terms of service contracts give them this right and how many don’t? Should ICANN’s Registrar Accreditation Agreement ensure registrar neutrality, or is competition sufficient to protect users’ rights?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These questions are explored in a new IGP research paper, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://via.hypothes.is/http://www.internetgovernance.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/AmoralReg-PAPER-final.pdf&quot;&gt;In Search of Amoral Registrars: Content Regulation and Domain Name Policy&lt;/a&gt;“, which examines the Terms of Service from 74 ICANN contracted parties who operate more than 2,300 domain name registrars in order to find out how many have “morality” clauses of the sort that knocked the Daily Stormer off the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/artificial-intelligence-what-are-the-issues-for-digital-rights</id>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence: what are the issues for digital rights?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/artificial-intelligence-what-are-the-issues-for-digital-rights" />
      <updated>2017-10-26T16:42:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You may have a basic understanding of what Artificial Intelligence, or AI, is. But are you familiar with the range of issues it raises for your fundamental rights? Access Now provides a brief overview of the issues at stake.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/togo-internet-shutdown</id>
      <title>Togo Internet shutdown - September 2017</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/togo-internet-shutdown" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T14:57:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 5 September 2017, at about 10am, the government of Togo cut off the Internet. The plan was to limit the threat from a growing number of young people around the country who were mobilising online and talking of toppling the government.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epic-global-coalition-recommend-human-rights-protections-for-cyb</id>
      <title>Global coalition recommend human rights protections for cybercrime proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epic-global-coalition-recommend-human-rights-protections-for-cyb" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T19:39:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EPIC joined European Digital Rights (EDRI) and a coalition of organizations to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/surveillance/cybercrime_2ndprotocol_globalsubmission_e-evidence_20170908.pdf&quot;&gt;advise&lt;/a&gt; the Council of Europe about protecting human rights during trans-national criminal investigations. The &quot;Global Civil Submission&quot; states that a proposed &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://rm.coe.int/terms-of-reference-for-the-preparation-of-%20a-draft-2nd-additional-proto/168072362b&quot;&gt;update&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://rm.coe.int/1680081561&quot;&gt;Convention on Cybercrime&lt;/a&gt; should include compliance with human rights principles and data protection standards for transnational data transfers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-makes-chat-group-administrators-criminally-liable-for-unla</id>
      <title>China makes chat group administrators criminally liable for unlawful messages</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-makes-chat-group-administrators-criminally-liable-for-unla" />
      <updated>2017-09-19T13:38:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New regulations in China will make chat group administrators responsible — and even criminally liable — for messages containing politically sensitive material, rumors and violent or pornographic content. The regulations also demand that all chat room users in mainland China verify their real identity.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinese-man-sentenced-to-prison-for-selling-vpn-software-whats-o</id>
      <title>Chinese man sentenced to prison for selling VPN software</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinese-man-sentenced-to-prison-for-selling-vpn-software-whats-o" />
      <updated>2017-09-05T14:34:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Chinese man running a small-scale website on which he sold VPN software has been sentenced to 9 months in prison.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-judge-says-linkedin-cannot-block-startup-from-public-profile</id>
      <title>U.S. judge says LinkedIn cannot block startup from public profile data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-judge-says-linkedin-cannot-block-startup-from-public-profile" />
      <updated>2017-08-15T16:00:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A U.S. judge on Monday ruled that Microsoft Corp&#039;s LinkedIn unit cannot prevent a startup from accessing public profile data, in a test of how much control a social media site can wield over information its users have deemed to be public.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/brazil-multistakeholder-internet-governance-model-in-crisis</id>
      <title>Brazil: multistakeholder internet governance model in crisis</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/brazil-multistakeholder-internet-governance-model-in-crisis" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T16:46:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Brazilian government is proposing changes in domestic internet governance that would endanger the participation of civil society and the multistakeholder model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On August 8th, the government published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.participa.br/cpgovernancainternet&quot;&gt;call for comments&lt;/a&gt; that would allow important changes in the national Internet Governance Steering Committee (“CGI.br”), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.convergenciadigital.com.br/cgi/cgilua.exe/sys/start.htm?UserActiveTemplate=site&amp;amp;UserActiveTemplate=mobile&amp;amp;UserActiveTemplate=site&amp;amp;infoid=45921&amp;amp;sid=4&quot;&gt;without even first consulting the committee itself&lt;/a&gt;. This has taken the Brazilian internet community by surprise.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deciphering-chinas-vpn-ban</id>
      <title>Deciphering China’s VPN Ban</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deciphering-chinas-vpn-ban" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T15:37:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This weekend Apple took a dispiriting step in the policing of its Chinese mainland App store: the company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/29/technology/china-apple-censorhip.html&quot;&gt;removed&lt;/a&gt; several Virtual Private Network (VPN) applications that allowed users to circumvent the China’s extensive internet censorship apparatus. In effect, the company has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/18/technology/clearing-out-the-app-stores-government-censorship-made-easier.html&quot;&gt;once again&lt;/a&gt; aided the Chinese government in its censorship campaign against its own citizens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-removes-vpn-apps-from-china-store-that-help-internet-users</id>
      <title>Apple removes VPN apps from China store that help Internet users evade censorship</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-removes-vpn-apps-from-china-store-that-help-internet-users" />
      <updated>2017-07-30T00:00:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A number of the most popular foreign virtual-private networks, also known as VPNs, which give users access to the unfiltered internet in China, were no longer accessible on the Apple app store there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russia-requesting-to-review-source-code-of-western-companies-sec</id>
      <title>Russia requesting to review source code of Western companies’ security products</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russia-requesting-to-review-source-code-of-western-companies-sec" />
      <updated>2017-07-29T23:58:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Western technology companies, including Cisco, IBM and SAP, are acceding to demands by Moscow for access to review source code for security products such as firewalls, anti-virus applications and software containing encryption before permitting the products to be imported and sold in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-white-house-just-endorsed-the-fccs-effort-to-roll-back-its-n</id>
      <title>The White House just endorsed the FCC’s effort to roll back its net neutrality rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-white-house-just-endorsed-the-fccs-effort-to-roll-back-its-n" />
      <updated>2017-07-30T00:06:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration has signaled that it stands behind efforts by the Federal Communications Commission and its chairman, Ajit Pai, to roll back the agency&#039;s net neutrality regulations for Internet providers. The FCC is seeking to undo rules that it approved in 2015 that ban the blocking and slowing of websites by Internet providers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/amazon-win-sets-good-precedent</id>
      <title>Amazon win sets good precedent</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/amazon-win-sets-good-precedent" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:38:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a victory for fairness and rule-based Internet governance, an independent review panel has decided that ICANN was wrong to deny retailing giant Amazon, Inc. the top level domain AMAZON. Key elements of the decision were unanimous, particularly the conclusion that the Board “cannot accept GAC consensus advice as conclusive&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/payment-processors-are-profiling-heavy-metal-fans-as-terrorists</id>
      <title>Payment processors are profiling heavy metal fans as terrorists</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/payment-processors-are-profiling-heavy-metal-fans-as-terrorists" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T15:41:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you happen to be a fan of the heavy metal band &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isistheband.com/&quot;&gt;Isis&lt;/a&gt; (an unfortunate name, to be sure), you may have trouble ordering its merchandise online. Last year, Paypal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metalinjection.net/latest-news/paypal-temporarily-suspended-a-dude-for-buying-an-isis-the-band-shirt&quot;&gt;suspended a fan who ordered an Isis t-shirt&lt;/a&gt;, presumably on the false assumption that there was some association between the heavy metal band and the terrorist group ISIS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then last month Internet scholar and activist Sascha Meinrath discovered that entering words such as &quot;ISIS&quot; (or &quot;Isis&quot;), or &quot;Iran&quot;, or (probably) other words from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.treasury.gov/resource-center/sanctions/SDN-List/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;this U.S. government blacklist&lt;/a&gt; in the description field for a Venmo payment will result in an automatic block on that payment, requiring you to complete a pile of paperwork if you want to see your money again. This is even if the full description field is something like &quot;Isis heavy metal album&quot; or &quot;Iran kofta kebabs, yum.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These examples may seem trivial, but they reveal a more serious problem with the trust and responsibility that the Internet places in private payment intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ftc-updates-guidance-on-childrens-privacy-law-includes-connected</id>
      <title>FTC updates guidance on children&#039;s privacy law, includes connected toys</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ftc-updates-guidance-on-childrens-privacy-law-includes-connected" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:46:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Federal Trade Commission has &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/blogs/business-blog/2017/06/ftc-updates-coppa-compliance-plan-business&quot;&gt;updated&lt;/a&gt; its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule-six-step-compliance&quot;&gt;guidance for businesses&lt;/a&gt; on complying with the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/kids/&quot;&gt;Children&#039;s Online Privacy Protection Act&lt;/a&gt;. The new guidance clarifies that connected toys, Internet of Things devices, and other products intended for children must comply with the Act.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-giants-step-up-joint-fight-against-extremist-conten</id>
      <title>Social media giants step up joint fight against extremist content</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-giants-step-up-joint-fight-against-extremist-conten" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:58:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Social media giants Facebook, Google&#039;s YouTube, Twitter and Microsoft said on Monday they were forming a global working group to combine their efforts to remove terrorist content from their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-security-and-due-process-a-new-legal-framework-for-the-c</id>
      <title>Digital security and due process: A new legal framework for the cloud era</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-security-and-due-process-a-new-legal-framework-for-the-c" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:08:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is an abbreviated version of a speech Kent Walker, SVP &amp;amp; General Councel at Google Inc, delivered at The Heritage Foundation in Washington, D.C. It introduces a new framework proposal to balance the needs of Law Enforcement Agencies and Governments to access digital evidence and the protection of citizens privacy, due process and other fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-icann-is-manipulating-its-gdpr-discussions</id>
      <title>How ICANN is manipulating its GDPR discussions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-icann-is-manipulating-its-gdpr-discussions" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:42:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ICANN’s management is now thinking about how to comply with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). ICANN’s Whois policies require registries and registrars to provide indiscriminate public access to personal data about domain name registrants, and thus violate European privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/theres-a-constitutional-right-to-use-social-media-supreme-court</id>
      <title>There’s a constitutional right to use social media, Supreme Court says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/theres-a-constitutional-right-to-use-social-media-supreme-court" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:14:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US Supreme Court on Monday (June 19th, 2017), declared as unconstitutional a 2008 North Carolina law barring registered sex offenders from accessing commercial social media sites where minors may become members or create personal pages or profiles, arguing that &quot;to foreclose access to social media altogether is to prevent the user from engaging in the legitimate exercise of First Amendment rights&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-rapporteur-demands-respect-for-freedom-of-expression-online</id>
      <title>UN Rapporteur demands respect for freedom of expression online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-rapporteur-demands-respect-for-freedom-of-expression-online" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:03:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations (UN) Special Rapporteur on the promotion and protection of the right to freedom of opinion and expression David Kaye has released a new report, which gives an overview of the problems for freedom of expression and opinion in the Telecommunications and Internet Access Sector. The report also provides general recommendations for states and private actors on topics such as digital access, net neutrality, government access to user data, and freedom of expression.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/youtube-clarifies-hate-speech-definition-and-which-videos-wont-b-1</id>
      <title>YouTube clarifies “hate speech” definition and which videos won’t be monetised</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/youtube-clarifies-hate-speech-definition-and-which-videos-wont-b-1" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T19:34:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube-creators.googleblog.com/2017/06/your-content-and-making-money-from.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, YouTube outlined more specific definitions of hate speech and what kinds of incendiary content wouldn&#039;t be eligible for monetization.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fbi-director-comey-backs-new-feinstein-push-for-decrypt-bill-tec</id>
      <title>FBI director Comey backs new push for decrypt bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fbi-director-comey-backs-new-feinstein-push-for-decrypt-bill-tec" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:56:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Answering questions at a Senate oversight committee hearing,&amp;nbsp;FBI Director James Comey has hinted&amp;nbsp;at growing consensus&amp;nbsp;between&amp;nbsp;technology companies and intelligence&amp;nbsp;agencies over the controversial issue of how to access encrypted data. He also supported what appears to be a fresh&amp;nbsp;push&amp;nbsp;by Senator Dianne Feinstein to introduce legislation&amp;nbsp;to enable&amp;nbsp;courts to&amp;nbsp;order access to encrypted devices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-fcc-just-released-a-plan-to-undo-its-own-net-neutrality-rule</id>
      <title>The FCC just released a plan to undo its own net neutrality rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-fcc-just-released-a-plan-to-undo-its-own-net-neutrality-rule" />
      <updated>2017-04-27T16:55:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The proposal from the Chairman of the US Federal Communications Commission, Ajit Pai marks the first step toward&amp;nbsp;undoing&amp;nbsp;a key decision of the Obama era, one that forced Internet providers to behave more like legacy telephone companies. The stricter rules for ISPs had made it illegal to block or slow down websites for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-fcc-wants-to-eliminate-net-neutrality-protections-we-cant-le</id>
      <title>The FCC wants to eliminate net neutrality protections</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-fcc-wants-to-eliminate-net-neutrality-protections-we-cant-le" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:37:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-internet-idUSKBN1790AP&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2017-04-07/republican-said-to-be-readying-plan-to-gut-net-neutrality-rules&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/fcc-chief-ajit-pai-develops-plans-to-roll-back-net-neutrality-rules-1491527590&quot;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt;, FCC Chairman Ajit Pai is planning to gut the FCC’s Open Internet Order, eliminating hard-fought net neutrality protections.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canada-strengthens-net-neutrality-rules-as-us-prepares-to-gut-th</id>
      <title>Canada strengthens net neutrality rules as US prepares to gut them</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canada-strengthens-net-neutrality-rules-as-us-prepares-to-gut-th" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:47:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Canada cracks down on zero-rating while FCC in US allows paid data cap exemptions. Canada is also taking a case-by-case approach to zero-rating instead of banning it outright. But yesterday, the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC) ordered changes to one carrier&#039;s zero-rating program and announced that it will enforce stricter guidelines for determining whether zero-rating programs are discriminatory.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-senate-just-voted-to-undo-landmark-rules-covering-your-inter</id>
      <title>The Senate just voted to undo landmark rules covering your Internet privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-senate-just-voted-to-undo-landmark-rules-covering-your-inter" />
      <updated>2017-03-27T12:19:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;US Senate lawmakers voted on March 22nd, to&amp;nbsp;repeal a historic set of rules aimed at protecting consumers&#039; online data from their own Internet providers, in a move that could make it easier for broadband companies to sell and share their customers&#039; usage information for advertising purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-parliament-votes-in-favor-of-internet-blocking-in-the-cont</id>
      <title>Swiss parliament votes in favor of Internet blocking in the context of online gamling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-parliament-votes-in-favor-of-internet-blocking-in-the-cont" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:43:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to decisions of the Swiss Parliament taken on March 1, 2017, offline and online gambling will be regulated by limiting it to a fixed number of Swiss-based operators only. Foreign online gambling sites will be considered illegal, and Internet service providers will be obliged to block these sites based on IP addresses or domain names. This is the first law in Switzerland which foresees such measures for any purpose. Critics warn about a “slippery slope” of increasing demands for Internet blocking that could even amount to censorship.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unesco-introduces-internet-universality-concept</id>
      <title>UNESCO introduces Internet Universality concept</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unesco-introduces-internet-universality-concept" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T22:28:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This document, proposed by UNESCO’s Secretariat, introduces “Internet Universality”, a draft concept that summarizes UNESCO’s positions on the Internet and which also serves as the framework for a current comprehensive study by UNESCO concerning key Internet-related issues.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/state-department-publishes-open-licensing-playbook-for-federal-a</id>
      <title>State Department publishes open licensing “Playbook” for federal agencies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/state-department-publishes-open-licensing-playbook-for-federal-a" />
      <updated>2017-02-07T20:59:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of State &lt;a href=&quot;https://2009-2017.state.gov/r/pa/prs/ps/2017/01/267125.htm&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eca.state.gov/files/bureau/open_licensing_playbook_final.pdf&quot;&gt;Federal Open Licensing Playbook&lt;/a&gt;, a list of considerations, use cases, and recommendations for federal departments interested in developing and implementing open license requirements on federally-funded grant projects. It is designed to assist federal efforts to maximize the impact of grant funds, and create opportunities for innovation and collaborative practices using federally-funded resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of the nine “plays” contains common features, including a checklist, key questions, and examples of use.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-governance-forum-embarking-on-post-iana-transition-and</id>
      <title>Internet Governance Forum: Embarking on post-IANA transition and taking on trade</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-governance-forum-embarking-on-post-iana-transition-and" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T12:52:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With several big trade negotiation projects in disarray after the election of Donald Trump in the United States, trade critics gathered at the 11th Internet Governance Forum – the longstanding UN-affiliated gathering – in Guadalajara, Mexico. They sensed an opportunity for some frank talk on the attempts to include the internet in e-commerce and telecom chapters.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-ends-anonymity-on-its-internet</id>
      <title>China ends anonymity on its Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-ends-anonymity-on-its-internet" />
      <updated>2016-11-13T11:21:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For years now, China’s government has been pushing Internet users towards real-name registration for some internet services, with varying degrees of success. But with a new cybersecurity law that will go into effect on June 1, 2017, ISPs, Wi-Fi node operators, and any other company that provides Internet access will need to confirm your real identity before they can let you online.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-has-us-under-surveillance-big-business-is-the-new-b</id>
      <title>Social media has us under surveillance – big business is the new Big Brother</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-has-us-under-surveillance-big-business-is-the-new-b" />
      <updated>2016-11-02T18:37:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Admiral has publicised a new service – firstcarquote – which will analyse the Facebook posts of first-time car owners, looking for evidence that they’re the kind of well-organised, conscientious types who will be safe on the roads. If you use a calendar or bookkeeping apps, tend to write in short, coherent sentences and use lots of lists, you’ll look like a safe bet and might qualify for a discount. But if your social media history is chock-full of exclamation marks, with a heavy use of “always” and “never” rather than the more cautious “maybe”, that might suggest you’re a tad on the over-confident, even reckless side – and you’ll have to pay the full rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/harmonization-of-cyberlegislation-in-latin-america</id>
      <title>Harmonization of Cyberlegislation in Latin America</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/harmonization-of-cyberlegislation-in-latin-america" />
      <updated>2016-11-02T13:12:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this publication is to provide up-to-date information on the legal framework of the countries in Latin America as follow-up to the studies in prospects for harmonising cyberlegislation in the region that were published in 2009 and 2010. The study reports progress made by the countries in regard to electronic transactions/electronic signatures, online protection of consumers, protection of personal data, industrial and intellectual property, domain names, cybercrime and security of information, and pending legislation and challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The situation in 20 countries of the region is reviewed, and information is provided on the commitments and responsibilities assumed by the individual countries in regard to cyberlegislation, bearing in mind the regional context, so as to identify the collaborating agencies and the implications, limitations and challenges involved. Reference is made to the many agenices in the region that have generated a wide range of legal instruments and public policies and the need for coordination with the governments of the countries so as to promote progress in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This study can be useful to government personell involved in designing and implementing legislation that will foster development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/missing-the-target-the-human-rights-push-in-icann-goes-off-the-r</id>
      <title>Missing the target: the human rights push in ICANN goes off the rails</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/missing-the-target-the-human-rights-push-in-icann-goes-off-the-r" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:44:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the ICANN accountability reforms, civil society activists pushed to gain a commitment from the corporation to respect fundamental human rights. However, Internet Governance Project believes that the human rights push in ICANN has become badly misdirected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the current direction of Work Stream 2 continues, the human rights effort will at best have no impact on ICANN’s policies and at worst could make ICANN into an even more controlling and intrusive regulatory force than it already is.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-treasury-tells-banks-to-provide-details-on-cyber-attacks</id>
      <title>U.S. Treasury tells banks to provide details on cyber attacks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-treasury-tells-banks-to-provide-details-on-cyber-attacks" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:59:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government on Tuesday told banks to include details about cyber attacks when filing mandatory reports on fraud and money laundering, saying that will help battle digital crimes that pose &quot;a significant threat&quot; to the U.S. financial system.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-report-cites-threats-to-freedom-of-expression</id>
      <title>UN report cites threats to freedom of expression</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-report-cites-threats-to-freedom-of-expression" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T20:01:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A top United Nations official on the freedom of expression &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/71/373&quot;&gt;released a report&lt;/a&gt; citing &quot;severe&quot; threats to freedom of expression worldwide. The report flagged governments cracking down on encryption, blocking websites, suspending communications services, and over-classifying information as key concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-takes-aim-at-cyber-attacks-from-connected-devices-as-recalls</id>
      <title>U.S. takes aim at cyber attacks from connected devices as recalls mount</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-takes-aim-at-cyber-attacks-from-connected-devices-as-recalls" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T14:48:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Obama administration officials sought on Monday to reassure the public that it was taking steps to counter new types of cyber attacks such as the one Friday that rendered Twitter, Spotify, Netflix and dozens of other major websites unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-american-illegally-wiretapped-at-home-by-ethiopian-governmen</id>
      <title>American illegally wiretapped at home by Ethiopian government</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-american-illegally-wiretapped-at-home-by-ethiopian-governmen" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T14:52:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ethiopia must be held accountable in the United States for an illegal malware and digital spying attack on an American citizen, the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/opening-brief-appellant-kidane-v-ethiopia&quot;&gt;told&lt;/a&gt; a federal appeals court today in a case where a foreign government claims it is immune from liability for wiretapping a man’s Skype calls. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Malicious digital surveillance and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/state-sponsored-malware&quot;&gt;malware attacks&lt;/a&gt; against perceived political opponents, dissidents, and journalists have become all-too-common tactics used by governments with poor human rights records, such as &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/03/new-report-ethiopia-examines-shelf-surveillance-state&quot;&gt;Ethiopia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/wp/operation-manul&quot;&gt;Kazakhstan&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/01/vietnamese-malware-gets-personal&quot;&gt;Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;. When foreign governments carry out these digital attacks on Americans in their homes, violating our wiretapping and privacy laws, their victims must be allowed to take them to court, EFF and its co-counsels said in a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/opening-brief-appellant-kidane-v-ethiopia&quot;&gt;filing&lt;/a&gt; at the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-open-access-law-could-be-passed-this-year</id>
      <title>US: Open access law could be passed this year</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-open-access-law-could-be-passed-this-year" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:01:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Under FASTR, the Fair Access to Science and Technology Research Act (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/senate-bill/779&quot;&gt;S. 779&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/house-bill/1477&quot;&gt;H.R. 1477&lt;/a&gt;), every federal agency that spends more than $100 million on grants for research would be required to adopt an open access policy. Although the bill gives each agency some flexibility to develop a policy appropriate to the types of research it funds, each one would require that published research be available to the public no later than 12 months after publication.&lt;p&gt;A previous version of FASTR was first introduced in 2013. FASTR has strong support on both sides of the aisle, but it still hasn&#039;t come up for a vote in either chamber of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-access-week-2016</id>
      <title>Open Access Week 2016</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-access-week-2016" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T14:58:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day of &lt;a href=&quot;http://openaccessweek.org/&quot;&gt;Open Access Week&lt;/a&gt;. EFF is joining &lt;a href=&quot;http://sparcopen.org/&quot;&gt;SPARC&lt;/a&gt; and dozens of other organizations all week to discuss the importance of open access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open access is the practice of making research and other materials freely available online, ideally under licenses that allow anyone to share and adapt them. By removing barriers like subscription fees or institutional connections, open access publishing lets more people participate in science and culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-calls-on-automakers-to-make-cyber-security-a-priority</id>
      <title>U.S. calls on automakers to make cyber security a priority</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-calls-on-automakers-to-make-cyber-security-a-priority" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:12:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Automakers should make shielding the electronic and computer systems of vehicles from hackers a priority, developing layers of protection that can secure a vehicle throughout its life, U.S. regulators said on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/framework-for-improving-critical-infrastructure-cybersecurity</id>
      <title>NIST framework for improving critical infrastructure cybersecurity</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/framework-for-improving-critical-infrastructure-cybersecurity" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:17:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Framework, which was created by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nist.gov/&quot;&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)&lt;/a&gt; through collaboration between industry and government, consists of standards, guidelines, and practices to promote the protection of critical infrastructure. It uses a common language to address and manage cybersecurity risk in a cost-effective way based on business needs without placing additional regulatory requirements on businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Framework focuses on using business drivers to guide cybersecurity activities and considering cybersecurity risks as part of the organization’s risk management processes. It consists of three parts: the Framework Core, the Framework Profile, and the Framework Implementation Tiers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Framework can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sbs.ox.ac.uk/cybersecurity-capacity/system/files/cybersecurity-framework-021214.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/youth-pathways-into-cybercrime</id>
      <title>Study: Pathways into cybercrime</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/youth-pathways-into-cybercrime" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:24:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This white paper by Europol, Middlesex University and UCD Geary Institute for Public Policy was published in October 2016 and draws together existing, recent evidence on online behaviour and associations with criminal and antisocial behaviour amongst young people. Specifically, it was designed to explore the trajectories and pathways that lead to ‘cyber-criminality’ through a series of mixed-methodological endeavours and the integration of theoretical frameworks across criminology and psychology, including cyberpsychology and computer science.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The paper can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sbs.ox.ac.uk/cybersecurity-capacity/system/files/Pathways-White-Paper.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/signal-received-a-grand-jury-subpoena-for-signal-user-data</id>
      <title>Signal received a grand jury subpoena for Signal user data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/signal-received-a-grand-jury-subpoena-for-signal-user-data" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T14:48:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the &quot;first half of 2016&quot; Open Whisper Systems (developers of the Signal messaging platform), received a subpoena from the Eastern District of Virginia requiring them to provide information about two Signal users for a federal grand jury investigation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-data-and-freedom-of-information-complements-or-competitors</id>
      <title>Open data and freedom of information: complements or competitors?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-data-and-freedom-of-information-complements-or-competitors" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:17:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Can open data improve people’s access to information? In this article, Michael Cañares, Regional Research Manager at the Open Data Lab Jakarta looks at how citizens in Banda Aceh used Indonesia’s Freedom of Information Act, and how open data worked to bolster citizen participation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-tech-firms-urge-congress-to-allow-internet-domain-changeover</id>
      <title>U.S. tech firms urge Congress to vote for the IANA oversight transition</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-tech-firms-urge-congress-to-allow-internet-domain-changeover" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T17:01:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Major technology companies including Facebook, Google and Twitter are urging Congress to support a plan for the U.S. government to cede control of the internet&#039;s technical management to the global community, they said in a joint letter dated on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Commerce Department has primary oversight of the internet&#039;s management, largely because it was invented in the United States. Some Republican lawmakers are trying to block the handover to global stakeholders, which include businesses, tech experts and public interest advocates, saying it could stifle online freedom by giving voting rights to authoritarian governments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The years-long plan to transfer oversight of the nonprofit Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers, or ICANN, is scheduled to occur on October 1 unless Congress votes to block the handover.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-anti-counterfeiting-chargeback-project-paying-back-decei</id>
      <title>Canada’s anti-counterfeiting chargeback project: paying back deceived consumers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-anti-counterfeiting-chargeback-project-paying-back-decei" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:42:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Project Chargeback was created as an anti-counterfeiting, anti-piracy initiative. It is having significant success in disrupting the sale of counterfeit and pirated goods over the internet and preventing their entry into the channels of commerce in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project, which is administered by the Canadian Anti-Fraud Center (CAFC), was launched in response to complaints from Canadians receiving counterfeit or questionable goods from e-commerce websites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/justice-dept-group-studying-national-security-threats-of-interne</id>
      <title>U.S. Justice Department group studying Internet of Things threats to national security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/justice-dept-group-studying-national-security-threats-of-interne" />
      <updated>2016-09-11T14:23:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Justice Department has formed a threat analysis team to study potential national security challenges posed by self-driving cars, medical devices and other Internet-connected tools, a senior official said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new group&#039;s goal is to secure the so-called &quot;internet of things&quot; from exploitation by “terrorist threats” and by others who might try to hack devices to cause loss of life or achieve political or economic gain, according to Assistant Attorney General John Carlin, head of the Justice Department’s national security division.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-censors-norways-pm</id>
      <title>Facebook is accused of censorship after deleting iconic Vietnam War photo</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-censors-norways-pm" />
      <updated>2016-09-11T14:37:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aftenposten,&amp;nbsp;Norway&#039;s largest newspaper, criticised Facebook for removing the Pulitzer-prize winning photograph from one of its posts. The newspaper published a series of photographs that &quot;changed the history of warfare&quot;. The 1972 picture by Nick Ut features nine-year old Kim Phuc running away, naked, from napalm bombs. Facebook asked the newspaper to remove or &quot;pixelise&quot; it because of her nudity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The newspaper refused and Facebook took down the post. The newspaper then put the photograph on its front page on Friday (9 September), next to a Facebook logo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/remarks-of-angela-simpson-at-fostering-the-advancement-of-the-in</id>
      <title>Remarks of U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information at fostering the advancement of the Internet of Things workshop</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/remarks-of-angela-simpson-at-fostering-the-advancement-of-the-in" />
      <updated>2016-09-11T14:49:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The article contains the remarks of Angela Simpson Deputy Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information Fostering the Advancement of the Internet of Things Workshop. The workshop&#039;s information will be integrated in the Department of Commerce policy green paper on IoT, which will identify next steps for the Department and recommendations for the next Administration.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-ready-to-hand-over-the-internets-naming-system-bbc-news</id>
      <title>US ready to &#039;hand over&#039; the internet&#039;s naming system</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-ready-to-hand-over-the-internets-naming-system-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2016-08-29T13:03:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US has confirmed it is finally ready to cede power of the internet’s naming system, ending the almost 20-year process to hand over a crucial part of the internet&#039;s governance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-submits-implementation-planning-status-report-to-ntia</id>
      <title>ICANN submits implementation planning status report to NTIA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-submits-implementation-planning-status-report-to-ntia" />
      <updated>2016-08-15T14:33:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ICANN today submitted an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/marby-to-strickling-12aug16-en.pdf&quot;&gt;implementation planning status report&lt;/a&gt; to the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA), in response to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/strickling-to-crocker-09jun16-en.pdf&quot;&gt;request&lt;/a&gt; NTIA made on 9 June 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The implementation planning status report is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/files/iana-stewardship-implementation-planning-status-12aug16-en.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-us-data-pact-launched</id>
      <title>EU-US data pact launched</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-us-data-pact-launched" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:55:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU and US have launched their data transfer pact known as Privacy Shield. The agreement is supposed to protect the privacy of EU nationals when their personal details are transferred to the United States. The pact replaces the 15-year old Safe Harbour agreement, which was invalidated last October by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-council-passed-online-freedom-resolution</id>
      <title>UN council passed online freedom resolution</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-council-passed-online-freedom-resolution" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:46:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A UN resolution entitled &quot;The promotion, protection and enjoyment of human rights on the Internet&quot; effectively extends human rights held offline to the internet. It was passed by consensus, but only after a determined effort by a number of countries, including China and Russia, to pull out key parts of the text.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-net-neutrality-rules-upheld-by-court-of-appeal</id>
      <title>US: Net neutrality rules upheld by Court of Appeal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-net-neutrality-rules-upheld-by-court-of-appeal" />
      <updated>2016-07-25T10:32:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;A U.S. appeals court upheld the Obama administration&#039;s landmark rules barring internet service providers from obstructing or slowing down consumer access to web content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt; The U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit backed the Federal Communications Commission&#039;s so-called net neutrality rules put in place last year to make internet service providers treat all internet traffic equally.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/iana-transition-milestone-reached</id>
      <title>IANA transition milestone reached</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/iana-transition-milestone-reached" />
      <updated>2016-08-15T14:27:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 9 June 2016, NTIA releases a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ntia.doc.gov/files/ntia/publications/combined_iana_stewardship_transition_assessment_report.pdf&quot;&gt;comprehensive evaluation of the proposals&lt;/a&gt; for transitioning the IANA functions to the multistakeholder community.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/will-the-un-kill-the-igf</id>
      <title>Will the UN kill the IGF?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/will-the-un-kill-the-igf" />
      <updated>2016-05-30T11:41:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UN Internet Governance Forum was the most important product of the World Summit on the Information Society (WSIS). It was supposed to serve as a bridge between the private sector-based Internet governance institutions (such as ICANN, IETF, ISOC, and the RIRs) and the world of national governments and the United Nations, a meeting ground where stakeholder silos would dissolve and fruitful dialogue would take place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The multistakeholder basis of the IGF, however, may be breaking down. The UN’s Department of Economic and Social Affairs (DESA) seems to be claiming authority over the IGF as its own project.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-internal-newsletter-released-by-the-intercept</id>
      <title>NSA internal newsletter released by The Intercept</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-internal-newsletter-released-by-the-intercept" />
      <updated>2016-05-24T21:14:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SIDtoday is the internal newsletter for the NSA’s most important division, the Signals Intelligence Directorate. After editorial review, The Intercept is releasing nine years’ worth of newsletters in batches, starting with 2003. The agency’s spies explain a surprising amount about what they were doing, how they were doing it, and why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/community-groups-come-together-across-the-us-to-promote-digital</id>
      <title>Community Groups Come Together Across the U.S. to Promote Digital Rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/community-groups-come-together-across-the-us-to-promote-digital" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:10:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;From coast to coast, in communities large and small, Americans from across the political spectrum&amp;nbsp;are coming together to champion &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/03/launching-efa&quot;&gt;the EFA&#039;s uniting principles&lt;/a&gt;: privacy, creativity, free expression, security, and&amp;nbsp;access to the intellectual commons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/supreme-court-approves-rule-change-that-expands-fbi-computer-sea</id>
      <title>Supreme Court approves rule change that expands FBI computer search powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/supreme-court-approves-rule-change-that-expands-fbi-computer-sea" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:13:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court has adopted amendments to a rule to give judges the authority to issue warrants to remotely search computers whose locations are concealed using technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-every-browser-knows-about-you</id>
      <title>What every Browser knows about you</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-every-browser-knows-about-you" />
      <updated>2016-04-04T15:00:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The link points to a page created by Robin Linus, showing all the information every website can know about every visitor without asking for any specific permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-and-us-release-details-on-trans-atlantic-data-transfer-deal-t</id>
      <title>EU and US release details on Trans-Atlantic Data Transfer Deal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-and-us-release-details-on-trans-atlantic-data-transfer-deal-t" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:23:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;American and European officials released details about a new trans-Atlantic data transfer agreement, prompting a new round of debate about how companies like Google move digital information between the two regions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mass-surveillance-leads-to-self-censorship</id>
      <title>Mass surveillance leads to self-censorship</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mass-surveillance-leads-to-self-censorship" />
      <updated>2016-03-29T23:42:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new study published in Journalism and Mass Communication Quarterly,&amp;nbsp;shows that knowledge of government surveillance causes people to self-censor their dissenting opinions online.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-european-us-data-transfer-pact-agreed-reuters</id>
      <title>EU-US data transfer pact agreed</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-european-us-data-transfer-pact-agreed-reuters" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:23:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European and U.S. negotiators agreed a data pact on Tuesday that should prevent European Union regulators from restricting data transfers by companies such as Google and Amazon across the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-officials-sign-the-tpp-but-its-still-up-to-lawmakers-to-re</id>
      <title>Trade officials sign the TPP but it&#039;s still up to lawmakers to reject it</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-officials-sign-the-tpp-but-its-still-up-to-lawmakers-to-re" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:39:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top officials of countries involved in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;Trans-Pacific Partnership&lt;/a&gt; (TPP) are convening in New Zealand today to sign the final agreement. But for the TPP to actually go into force, countries need to ratify it. Each of the twelve TPP countries have differing procedures for doing this, however due to both political reasons and the terms of stipulated by the TPP, the agreement cannot go into force without the United States&#039; ratification. That&#039;s why it&#039;s so critical that people in the U.S. demand congressional accountability over this deal and &lt;a href=&quot;https://act.eff.org/action/tell-congress-to-vote-no-on-the-tpp&quot;&gt;urge their lawmakers to vote no when the TPP comes before them for approval&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-now-welcomes-human-rights-partnership-between-telcos-and</id>
      <title>Access Now welcomes human rights partnership between telcos and GNI</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-now-welcomes-human-rights-partnership-between-telcos-and" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:51:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GNI is a global, collaborative initiative that works to protect and advance freedom of expression and privacy in the ICT sector. Now, seven telecommunications companies have joined the initiative as observers, a laudable step toward increased accountability for respecting human rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/announcing-a-global-coalition-demanding-security-for-all</id>
      <title>Announcing a global coalition demanding security for all</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/announcing-a-global-coalition-demanding-security-for-all" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T13:43:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Access Now is launching securetheinternet.org — an open letter to world leaders asking for them to support encryption and to avoid mandates that would undermine the security of users and companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter has already been signed by 195 organizations, individuals, trade associations, and companies and represents a global effort to advance digital security.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-largest-buyer-of-domain-names</id>
      <title>China largest buyer of domain names</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-largest-buyer-of-domain-names" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T22:15:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last two years, China has become the largest buyer of domain names, resulting in what is likely the biggest story in domain-name investing since the Internet began.“136 of the 676 2-letter .com domain names are now owned by Chinese registrants, breaking the 20% barrier.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/10th-internet-governance-forum-opens-in-joao-pessoa-brazil</id>
      <title>10th Internet Governance Forum Opens In Joao Pessoa, Brazil</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/10th-internet-governance-forum-opens-in-joao-pessoa-brazil" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:44:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In opening the 10th Internet Governance Forum (IGF) of the United Nations in Joao Pessoa, Brazilian President Dilma Rousseff called for solutions to internet access, but also to address challenges in online human rights, especially privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/domanin-registrars-need-icann-clearance-for-privacy-protection</id>
      <title>Domanin registrars need ICANN clearance for privacy protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/domanin-registrars-need-icann-clearance-for-privacy-protection" />
      <updated>2015-11-02T17:00:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/icann&quot;&gt;The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN)&lt;/a&gt; policies require that domain registrants data be published in a publicly-available WHOIS database. The P&lt;a href=&quot;https://gnso.icann.org/en/issues/raa/ppsai-initial-05may15-en.pdf&quot;&gt;rivacy &amp;amp; Proxy Services Accreditation&lt;/a&gt; policy has been under consultation and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/07/powerful-coalition-letter-highlights-danger-icanns-new-domain-registration&quot;&gt;numerous public figures and experts&lt;/a&gt; provided comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/public-comments/iag-whois-conflicts-privacy-2015-10-05-en&quot;&gt;Another public consultation&lt;/a&gt; that is open until November 17 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/public-comments/iag-whois-conflicts-privacy-2015-10-05-en&quot;&gt;WHOIS Conflicts with Privacy Laws&lt;/a&gt;. The policy essentially provides that ICANN may “allow” a registry or registrar whose obligations to publish WHOIS data are in breach of locally applicable data protection law, to be exempted from those obligations, but only once the local data protection authorities have initiated enforcement proceedings against it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/letter-from-security-internet-experts-to-fcc-requests-mandates-f</id>
      <title>Letter from security &amp; Internet experts to FCC Requests Mandates for Securing and Updating Wi-Fi Devices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/letter-from-security-internet-experts-to-fcc-requests-mandates-f" />
      <updated>2016-02-02T22:12:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than 260 other global network and cybersecurity experts responded to the newly proposed FCC rules laid out in &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapps.fcc.gov%2Fedocs_public%2Fattachmatch%2FFCC-15-92A1.pdf&amp;amp;esheet=51200849&amp;amp;newsitemid=20151014005564&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=ET+Docket+No.+15-170&amp;amp;index=3&amp;amp;md5=665b204ca1bdc16015d5540cf1d3c3e6&quot;&gt;ET Docket No. 15-170&lt;/a&gt; for RF Devices such as Wi-Fi routers by unveiling a new approach to improve the security of these devices and ensure a faster, better, and more secure Internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fhuchra.bufferbloat.net%2F%7Ed%2Ffcc_saner_software_practices.pdf&amp;amp;esheet=51200849&amp;amp;newsitemid=20151014005564&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=letter&amp;amp;index=1&amp;amp;md5=985f8111b0a086ca93b0384f62970e4e&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; was submitted within the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) public comment period on this issue and contained a set of recommendations. For the complete letter and the full list of supporters, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fhuchra.bufferbloat.net%2F%7Ed%2Ffcc_saner_software_practices.pdf&amp;amp;esheet=51200849&amp;amp;newsitemid=20151014005564&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=here&amp;amp;index=4&amp;amp;md5=140a19fad7922faeb62758e57d9076dd&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/snowden-treaty-for-ending-surveillance</id>
      <title>Snowden Treaty for ending surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/snowden-treaty-for-ending-surveillance" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T13:12:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The global advocacy group Avaaz organized the gathering to promote the so-called &quot;Snowden Treaty.&quot; Countries who sign would be required to curtail surveillance of phone calls and online activity, and also agree to provide sanctuary for people who expose illegal domestic spying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The forum was timed to coincide with the United Nations General Assembly. Organizers have said diplomats have shown interest in a draft of the treaty, but have declined to name what countries they represent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-presidency-candidate-jeb-bush-against-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>US presidency candidate Jeb Bush against net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-presidency-candidate-jeb-bush-against-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T14:02:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Bush issued a promise for regulatory reform that includes environment-focused regulations and the net neutrality framework passed early last year. If elected president, Jeb Bush could call for the net neutrality rules to be eradicated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeb Bush campaign page reads: &quot;The Federal Communications Commission’s Net Neutrality rule classifies all Internet Service Providers (ISPs) as &quot;public utilities,&quot; subjecting them to antiquated &quot;common carrier&quot; regulation. Rather than enhancing consumer welfare, these rules prohibit one group of companies (ISPs) from charging another group of companies (content companies) the full cost for using their services. Small broadband operators—like KWISP (475 customers in rural Illinois) and Wisper ISP (8,000 customers near St. Louis, Mo)—have declared under penalty of perjury that the Net Neutrality rule has caused them to cut back on investments to upgrade and expand their networks.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-and-china-in-urgent-negociations-on-cybersecurity</id>
      <title>US and China in urgent negociations on cybersecurity</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-and-china-in-urgent-negociations-on-cybersecurity" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T11:37:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United States and China have been engaged in urgent negotiations on a cybersecurity agreement and may announce the terms when the Chinese president Xi Jinping arrives in Washington on Thursday. The agreement could address cyber attacks on power stations, cellphone networks and hospitals, according to unidentified officials cited by the New York Times on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama called last Wednesday for an international framework to prevent the internet from being &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/sep/16/obama-china-cybersecurity-weaponise-the-internet-xi-jinping-visit&quot;&gt;“weaponised”&lt;/a&gt; as a tool of national aggression, while holding out the prospect of a forceful US response to China over hacking attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-successful-was-the-new-international-cloud-standard-iso-2701</id>
      <title>How successful was the new international cloud standard ISO 27018?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-successful-was-the-new-international-cloud-standard-iso-2701" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T17:57:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last summer, the International Standards Organisation (ISO) and the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) published &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iso.org/iso/catalogue_detail.htm?csnumber=61498&quot;&gt;ISO 27018&lt;/a&gt;, the first privacy-specific international standard for cloud services. The new standard specifies the roles of a data controller and a data processor in maintaining the security and privacy of personally identifiable information (“PII”) stored in a public cloud environment. In contrast to existing information security standards that it builds on, such as ISO 27001 and ISO 27002, ISO 27018 is specifically tailored to cloud computing services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=89e3bd5d-d6d9-4ece-bc37-bd396f3c232b&amp;amp;utm_source=Lexology+Daily+Newsfeed&amp;amp;utm_medium=HTML+email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Lexology+subscriber+daily+feed&amp;amp;utm_content=Lexology+Daily+Newsfeed+2015-09-22&amp;amp;utm_term=&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; analyses how successful was the new standard and what were the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-asks-for-security-policies-from-american-companies</id>
      <title>China asks for security policies from American companies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-asks-for-security-policies-from-american-companies" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:52:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government distributed a document to some American tech companies earlier this summer, in which it asked the companies to promise they would not harm China’s national security and would store Chinese user data within the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter also asks the American companies to ensure their products are “secure and controllable,” a catchphrase that industry groups said could be used to force companies to build so-called back doors — which allow third-party access to systems — provide encryption keys or even hand over source code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/09/science/china-flexes-tech-muscles-before-state-visit-with-meeting-of-industry-giants.html&quot;&gt;Beijing has also planned a tech forum&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle between China’s Internet czar, Lu Wei, and tech companies including Apple, Facebook, IBM, Google and Uber.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-digital-watch-newsletter-issue-3-sept-2015</id>
      <title>Digital Watch Newsletter for September 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-digital-watch-newsletter-issue-3-sept-2015" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T13:57:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third issue of Digital Watch is summarising developments in digital politics over the summer months of July and August, with a special focus on Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this issue you can find an analysis of WSIS+10 non-paper submissions. More than 80 submissions for non-papers were made to the WSIS+10 process prior to the High-Level Meeting of the General Assembly in December. The documents were analysed in order to provide an overview of the main themes addressed, their relevance by stakeholder group, and the most frequently used words.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time you can find what went up and what went down in our Internet governance barometer as well as information on the recent decisions by courts and regulators continue to confirm that operating across the ubiquitous Internet can expose Internet corporations to the jurisdictions of countries other than the country in which they are headquartered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read or download the Geneva Digital Watch here:&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.giplatform.org/sites/default/files/DWnewsletterSept.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt; Issue 3, September 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-transfer-of-internet-oversight-to-be-delayed</id>
      <title>US transfer of Internet oversight to be delayed</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-transfer-of-internet-oversight-to-be-delayed" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T00:31:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The transfer of the technical functions of the Internet was first scheduled for September 2015, however the process will be delayed. &lt;a title=&quot;The post.&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ntia.doc.gov/blog/2015/update-iana-transition&quot;&gt;In a blog post&lt;/a&gt;, a Commerce Department official said that the plan to move to international management needed more work. As a result, he said, the department would renew its contract with ICANN for at least a year — with an option to renew for an additional three years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-considers-banning-privacy-services</id>
      <title>ICANN considers banning privacy services</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-considers-banning-privacy-services" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:23:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) is proposing a new Internet policy which comes at the expense of human rights, especially privacy and freedom of speech. The proposed rules are addressed to companies that provide WHOIS privacy/proxy services (which restrict access to domain registrant information) and limit their availability to individuals only, denying this service to organisations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-issues-surrounding-iana-trademarks</id>
      <title>The issues surrounding IANA trademarks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-issues-surrounding-iana-trademarks" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:12:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest controversies surrounding the IANA stewardship transition revolves around the fate of the IANA trademark and domain name (IANA.ORG). Both of these assets are currently owned by ICANN. But the IANA stewardship transition has raised questions about who or what should be their proper home. This article explains why this matters and what would be the implications for the IANA transition.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-meeting-report-new-domains-process-under-review-and-names</id>
      <title>ICANN meeting report: new domains process under review and names proposal for IANA transition ready</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-meeting-report-new-domains-process-under-review-and-names" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:06:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experts at last week’s meeting of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) in Buenos Aires reached a milestone with a final proposal from the ICANN working group for the transition of internet control away from the United States. But global governance without oversight remains difficult, as the ongoing review of the introduction of new generic top-level domains aptly illustrates.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/join-the-privacy-campaign-no-personal-information-in-the-publicl</id>
      <title>Join the global privacy campaign: no personal information in the publicly searchable WHOIS directory</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/join-the-privacy-campaign-no-personal-information-in-the-publicl" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:30:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A global&lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;http://www.savedomainprivacy.org/&quot;&gt; campaign&lt;/a&gt; to prevent ICANN&#039;s inclusion of domain owners&#039; personal information in the publicly searchable WHOIS directory has been launched. Users concerned about privacy are encouraged to &lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;http://www.savedomainprivacy.org/sign-the-petition/&quot;&gt;sign the online petition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:comments-ppsai-initial-05may15@icann.org&quot;&gt;email comments&lt;/a&gt; directly to ICANN before July 7, 2015. ICANN has already received nearly 8000 emails protesting the removal of WHOIS privacy protections. ICANN &lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;http://gnso.icann.org/en/issues/raa/ppsai-initial-05may15-en.pdf&quot;&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; that no changes will be made until all public comments are reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.savedomainprivacy.org&quot;&gt;www.savedomainprivacy.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/iana-transition-slipping-technical-communities-ask-for-phases</id>
      <title>IANA transition not on schedule</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/iana-transition-slipping-technical-communities-ask-for-phases" />
      <updated>2015-06-19T22:35:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Preparations for transitioning the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) out of United States oversight do not appear to be on track for the 30 September deadline. As a result, cautious pressure is mounting from the internet protocol numbers administration and protocol standardisation bodies to consider at least a “phased implementation” of the transition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://buenosaires53.icann.org/en/&quot;&gt;53rd meeting&lt;/a&gt; of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) in Buenos Aires, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ianacg.org/&quot;&gt;IANA stewardship coordination group&lt;/a&gt; (ICG) tried to readjust the timeline for the reform of IANA function oversight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/who-has-your-back-government-data-requests-2015-electronic-front</id>
      <title>EFF annual report on government data requests</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/who-has-your-back-government-data-requests-2015-electronic-front" />
      <updated>2015-06-19T20:52:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) has released the annual “Who’s Got Your Back” report. For four years, EFF documented the practices of major Internet companies and service providers, judging their publicly available policies, and highlighting best practices. Over the course of the first four reports, EFF watched a transformation take place among the practices of major technology companies. Please see the major findings in the 2015 report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/who-has-your-back-government-data-requests-2015?hs=true#results-summary&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download the complete &lt;i&gt;Who Has Your Back? 2015: Protecting Your Data From Government Requests&lt;/i&gt; report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2015/06/18/who_has_your_back_2015_protecting_your_data_from_government_requests_20150618.pdf&quot;&gt;as a PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-to-require-https-for-all-government-websites</id>
      <title>US to require HTTPS for all government websites</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-to-require-https-for-all-government-websites" />
      <updated>2015-06-09T15:06:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US government is mandating the use of the HTTPS security protocol on all of its public websites and web services by the end of 2016.&lt;a href=&quot;https://https.cio.gov/&quot;&gt; Deploying HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; will authenticate communications with government websites and encrypt the data sent back and forth, which will help protect against snooping and imposter websites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/presentations-from-global-internet-policy-observatory-workshop</id>
      <title>Presentations from Global Internet Policy Observatory workshop</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/presentations-from-global-internet-policy-observatory-workshop" />
      <updated>2015-06-08T23:13:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The workshop &quot;Co-designing GIPO platform&quot; took place in Sofia on the 4th June. Over 40 participants from a variety of countries attended the presentations and took part in three workshop sessions led by keynote speakers, where they debated on specific questions related to the development of the GIPO platform.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-review-of-wsis-intensifies-questions-about-icann-board-role-i</id>
      <title>WSIS review and IANA handover status progress</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-review-of-wsis-intensifies-questions-about-icann-board-role-i" />
      <updated>2015-06-03T09:57:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations review of implementation of the 2005 World Summit on the Information Society (WSIS) is well underway, while efforts to meet the September target for the IANA handover are intensifying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although not a policymaking event, the 25-29 May WSIS Forum resulted in a set of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itu.int/net4/wsis/forum/2015/Outcomes/&quot;&gt;outcomes&lt;/a&gt; that will be sent on to the UN Commission on Science and Technology for Development (CSTD). The event included a dedicated panel to the IANA transition which can be consulted here: “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itu.int/net4/wsis/forum/2015/Agenda/Session/269&quot;&gt;IANA Stewardship Transition – A Live Example of a Multi-Stakeholder Process&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-expert-launches-robust-defence-of-online-anonymity-and-encryp</id>
      <title>UN expert launches robust defence of online anonymity and encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-expert-launches-robust-defence-of-online-anonymity-and-encryp" />
      <updated>2015-06-13T20:28:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, David Kaye, the UN Special Rapporteur on freedom of expression published a major report on encryption and anonymity in the digital age. ARTICLE 19 welcomes the report as a major step forward for the protection of the rights to free expression and privacy online. We call on governments to review their laws, policies and practices and bring them in line with the Special Rapporteur’s recommendations as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-domestic-phone-spying-program-illegal-by-appeals-court</id>
      <title>NSA domestic phone spying program illegal by appeals court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-domestic-phone-spying-program-illegal-by-appeals-court" />
      <updated>2015-05-08T12:41:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A US federal appeals court ruled on Thursday that the NSA spying program that collects data about millions of Americans&#039; phone calls is illegal. The court&#039;s ruling is adding pressure on lawmakers to decide quickly whether to end or replace the program, which was intended to help fight terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/check-out-the-video-from-the-first-webinar-on-introduction-to-th</id>
      <title>First webinar on Introduction to the Global Internet Policy Observatory online platform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/check-out-the-video-from-the-first-webinar-on-introduction-to-th" />
      <updated>2015-05-05T12:24:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first webinar introducing Global Internet Policy Observatory, a tool built through crowdsourcing to help the global community interested in Internet-related policy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-kill-switches-are-a-violation-of-human-rights-law</id>
      <title>Internet kill switches are a violation of human rights law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-kill-switches-are-a-violation-of-human-rights-law" />
      <updated>2015-05-04T22:35:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Major UN and international rights experts have just declared that internet kill switches are absolutely impermissible under international human rights law, even in times of conflict. This historic statement holds that governments can no longer justify ordering telecommunications companies to shut off mobile or internet services in the face of social unrest or protest. It is a critical decision that impacts the rights of people who are protesting from Burundi to Baltimore.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-usa-freedom-act-a-step-in-the-right-direction-but-more-m-1</id>
      <title>EFF comments on the new USA Freedom Act</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-usa-freedom-act-a-step-in-the-right-direction-but-more-m-1" />
      <updated>2015-05-02T17:13:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Similar to last year&#039;s bill, the new USA Freedom Act attempts to end the bulk collection of calling records under Section 215 of the Patriot Act by limiting collection to instances where there is &quot;reasonable, articulable suspicion&quot; that a &quot;specific selection term&quot; used to request call detail records is associated with international terrorism. The government must use a specific selection term, which represents an &quot;individual, account, or personal device.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-gipo-tool-is-live</id>
      <title>European Commission&#039;s GIPO tool is live</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-gipo-tool-is-live" />
      <updated>2015-05-05T12:26:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://giponet.org/&quot;&gt;giponet.org, &lt;/a&gt;part of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/global-internet-policy-observatory-gipo&quot;&gt;Global Internet Policy Observatory (GIPO)&lt;/a&gt;, is designed to help better understand global developments on internet policy and governance. The European Commission is helping set-up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/6jMmvIDAjIA&quot;&gt;GIPO tool&lt;/a&gt; to help everyone find their way in the Internet policy labyrinth and understand what is being discussed at key international events on Internet Governance, who does what, what positions different stakeholders adopt.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/webinar-introduction-to-global-internet-policy-observatory-onlin</id>
      <title>Webinar: Introduction to Global Internet Policy Observatory online platform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/webinar-introduction-to-global-internet-policy-observatory-onlin" />
      <updated>2015-05-05T12:15:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 2015 GIPO, the Global Internet Policy Observatory initiative of the European Commission (DG CONNECT) will be&amp;nbsp;launched.&amp;nbsp;A webinar will be held on 30 April to introduce the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-development-of-an-advisory-group-for-gipo</id>
      <title>The development of an Advisory Group for GIPO</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-development-of-an-advisory-group-for-gipo" />
      <updated>2015-05-05T12:15:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A call for GIPO&#039;s Advisory Group has been launched. GIPO is a tool built through crowdsourcing to help the global community interested in Internet-related policy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-c-51-will-undermine-canadas-business-climate-an-open-letter</id>
      <title>Canada: Bill C-51 will undermine Canada’s business climate</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-c-51-will-undermine-canadas-business-climate-an-open-letter" />
      <updated>2015-04-22T15:21:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bill C-51 would provide too much leeway for the Canadian Security and Intelligence Service (CSIS) to take unjustified actions against our businesses, including the takedown of websites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-global-digital-magna-carta-maybe-but-first-identify-needs-pane</id>
      <title>A global digital Magna Carta? Maybe, but first identify needs, panel says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-global-digital-magna-carta-maybe-but-first-identify-needs-pane" />
      <updated>2015-04-15T13:58:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A recent panel of internet governance experts was divided on whether a primary global set of principles protecting the balance of power on the internet is needed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/president-obama-creates-new-cyber-sanctions-programme</id>
      <title>President Obama creates new cyber sanctions programme</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/president-obama-creates-new-cyber-sanctions-programme" />
      <updated>2015-04-02T16:36:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;US President Barack Obama has ordered the creation of a programme that would allow the government to sanction foreign hackers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The authorisation gives the US Treasury Secretary - in coordination with the Attorney General and Secretary of State - the ability to sanction &quot;individuals or entities&quot; that pose a cyber threat to the &quot;national security, foreign policy, or economic health or financial stability of the United States,&quot; Mr Obama said in a statement issued by the White House.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-tracking-said-to-breach-eu-law</id>
      <title>Facebook tracking said to breach EU law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-tracking-said-to-breach-eu-law" />
      <updated>2015-04-01T12:36:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; tracks the web browsing of everyone who visits a page on its site even if the user does not have an account or has explicitly opted out of tracking in the EU, extensive research commissioned by the Belgian data protection agency has revealed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-on-the-agenda-at-the-swiss-internet-governance-forum</id>
      <title>.swiss on the agenda at the Swiss Internet Governance Forum</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-on-the-agenda-at-the-swiss-internet-governance-forum" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:44:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Berne will host the first Swiss Internet Governance Forum (Swiss-IGF) on 19 May. Among the themes selected by the organisers is an introduction to the new .swiss internet domain. This will give participants the opportunity to familiarise themselves with the conditions and processes for allocating domain names before the launch of .swiss in the autumn.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/international-coalition-launches-manila-principles-to-protect-fr</id>
      <title>International Coalition Launches &#039;Manila Principles&#039; to Protect Freedom of Expression Worldwide</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/international-coalition-launches-manila-principles-to-protect-fr" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T13:17:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An international coalition launched the “Manila Principles on Internet Liability” today—a roadmap for the global community to protect online freedom of expression and innovation around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our goal is to protect everyone’s freedom of expression with a framework of safeguards and best practices for responding to requests for content removal.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/turkey-has-passed-a-new-law-for-website-blocking</id>
      <title>Turkey has passed a new law for website blocking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/turkey-has-passed-a-new-law-for-website-blocking" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T13:26:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Turkey has passed a new law that allows the government to close a website. The Internet Service Providers have to comply in just 4 hours. The judiciary is authorized to intervene only ex post.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/indias-supreme-court-strikes-down-law-against-offensive-online-c</id>
      <title>India&#039;s Supreme Court strikes down law against offensive online content</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/indias-supreme-court-strikes-down-law-against-offensive-online-c" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T10:08:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;India’s Supreme Court has struck down as unconstitutional an Internet law that provided for the arrest of people sending online messages considered offensive or menacing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court struck down on Tuesday section 66A of the Information Technology Act, describing it as vague, and said it did not fall under reasonable restrictions on free speech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision by the Supreme Court follows a bunch of lawsuits that alleged that this section of India’s cyberlaw was a threat to free speech in the country, and had led to arbitrary arrests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinese-anti-censorship-group-greatfireorg-suffers-massive-hack-1</id>
      <title>Chinese anti-censorship group Greatfire.org suffers massive hack</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinese-anti-censorship-group-greatfireorg-suffers-massive-hack-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-23T17:02:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An advocacy group that helps internet users inside &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; bypass blocks on censored content says it is suffering a denial-of-service attack disrupting its operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US-subsidised Greatfire.org says the attack started two days ago and traffic is 2,500 times above normal. It has affected “mirror”, or duplicate, websites that it has set up via encrypted web services offered by companies such as Amazon.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223515168982/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/449afd5e/sc/21/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wrueytkxbtabandnytap&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223515168982/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/449afd5e/sc/21/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/an-autocratic-country-in-global-multistakeholder-internet-govern</id>
      <title>An autocratic country in global multistakeholder Internet governance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/an-autocratic-country-in-global-multistakeholder-internet-govern" />
      <updated>2015-03-23T16:33:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A&lt;a href=&quot;http://globalnetpolicy.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Chaos-and-Control.pdf&quot;&gt; recently published&lt;/a&gt; report supported by the Internet Policy Observatory &amp;nbsp;about Iran’s approach to Internet governance provides insight into how an autocratic government plays a role in Internet policy and operations. And as the report shows, the situation is not all dark and gloomy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-urged-by-copyright-industry-associations-to-take-action-ag</id>
      <title>ICANN urged by copyright industry associations to take action against IPR infringement</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-urged-by-copyright-industry-associations-to-take-action-ag" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:02:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, the Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA) issued a carefully-worded statement urging ICANN – the overseer of much of the Internet’s fundamental naming and numbering infrastructure – to take more vigorous action against &lt;span style=&quot;color: #565656;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;the “use of domain names for illegal and abusive activities, including those related to IP infringement” (&lt;em&gt;i.e.,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;motion picture piracy). &amp;nbsp;[See &quot;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://torrentfreak.com/domain-registrars-deny-police-requests-suspend-pirate-sites-140808/&quot;&gt;MPAA Pushes for ICANN Policy Changes to Target &#039;Pirate&#039; Domains&lt;/a&gt;&quot;]. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #565656;&quot;&gt;And just a few days ago, the recording industry joined in; a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.icann.org/en/system/files/correspondence/riaa-to-icann-05mar15-en.pdf&quot;&gt;letter from the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA) &amp;nbsp;to ICANN&lt;/a&gt;, while expressing the industry’s “disappointment with . . . ICANN’s treatment of copyright abuse complaints filed to date,” similarly urged ICANN to move more vigorously to ensure that&amp;nbsp;domain name registries and registrars “investigate copyright abuse complaints and respond appropriately.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-joins-civil-society-call-for-rejection-of-flawed-us-cybersec</id>
      <title>EFF joins civil society call for rejection of flawed US cybersecurity legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-joins-civil-society-call-for-rejection-of-flawed-us-cybersec" />
      <updated>2015-03-05T12:41:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;EFF has joined 26 civil society organizations and 22 computer security experts in &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/insight/letter-to-senate-select-cmte-on-cisa/&quot;&gt;a letter&lt;/a&gt; that calls on the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence to reject the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (CISA).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CISA, currently only available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/cyber-information-sharing-act-fo-2015-senate-intelligence-committee-114-congress&quot;&gt;draft form&lt;/a&gt;, is yet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/06/zombie-bill-comes-back-look-senates-cybersecurity-information-sharing-act-2014&quot;&gt;another iteration&lt;/a&gt; of the infamous Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cybersecurity-bill-faq&quot;&gt;CISPA&lt;/a&gt;), first introduced in 2011. These pieces of legislation have all been introduced under the auspices of increased computer and network security. But instead of providing increased funding for security research, providing funding for security training for federal government employees, or any of the other ways computer and network security could be made better, they have focused on information sharing, without addressing the privacy and civil liberties implications that entails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-says-new-cybersurveillance-proposal-follows-us-security-pr</id>
      <title>China says new cybersurveillance proposal follows US security practices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-says-new-cybersurveillance-proposal-follows-us-security-pr" />
      <updated>2015-03-05T12:42:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, China’s parliamentary spokeswoman tried to play down the impact the proposed legislation might have on foreign tech businesses, in the face of U.S. fears it would require companies to hand over sensitive data to the country’s government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The anti-terror law is still under review, but if passed, it would require tech companies to give encryption keys to the authorities, and create “back doors” into their systems for government surveillance access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-internet-rules-set-up-industrys-next-battle</id>
      <title>New Internet rules set up industry&#039;s next battle</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-internet-rules-set-up-industrys-next-battle" />
      <updated>2015-03-02T22:05:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;New rules that aim to protect the openness of the Internet will allow telecom and cable groups to prioritize and earn potentially vast income from some types of data, setting up likely clashes with regulators in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;Telecom companies such as AT&amp;amp;T and Vodafone have convinced U.S. and European regulators, finalizing so-called &quot;net neutrality&quot; rules, to allow them to dedicate network capacity to services such as providing connectivity to driverless cars and facilitating the exchange of medical data between patients and health professionals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/summary-of-what-we-know-about-the-fcc-net-neutrality-rules</id>
      <title>Summary of what we know about the FCC net neutrality rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/summary-of-what-we-know-about-the-fcc-net-neutrality-rules" />
      <updated>2015-03-02T22:19:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Federal Communications Commission voted Thursday to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.networkworld.com/article/2889164/lan-wan/fcc-passes-net-neutrality-rules-reclassifies-broadband-as-utility.html&quot;&gt;pass new net neutrality rules&lt;/a&gt; and reclassify broadband as a regulated telecommunications service, but the text of the full order may not be released for several weeks. This article is about what we know so far&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-censorship-sweep-deletes-more-than-60000-internet-accounts</id>
      <title>China censorship sweep deletes more than 60,000 Internet accounts</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-censorship-sweep-deletes-more-than-60000-internet-accounts" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:46:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some of China&#039;s largest Internet companies deleted more than 60,000 online accounts because their names did not conform to regulations due to take effect on Sunday, the top Internet regulator said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;body-slot-mod&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;yom-remote&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;mediacontentrelatedstory_container&quot;&gt;Alibaba Group Holding Ltd, Tencent Holdings Ltd, Baidu Inc, Sina Corp affiliate Weibo Corp and other companies deleted the accounts in a cull aimed at &quot;rectifying&quot; online names, the Cyberspace Administration of China (CAC) said.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;yui_3_16_0_1_1425048257189_988&quot;&gt;The reasons for their removal included accusations of being misleading, rumor mongering, links to terrorism, or involving violence, pornography and other violations, the CAC said in a statement on its website late on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-passes-strict-net-neutrality-regulations-on-3-2-vote</id>
      <title>FCC passes strict net neutrality regulations on 3-2 vote</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-passes-strict-net-neutrality-regulations-on-3-2-vote" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T17:00:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As expected, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) passed&amp;nbsp;new net neutrality regulations today on a vote of 3-2, with the Commission’s two Democratic appointees joining&amp;nbsp;Chairman Tom Wheeler in voting yes. The Commission’s two Republican-appointed members both voted no.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notably, the FCC’s plan is now known to have&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2015/02/fcc-chairman-tom-wheeler-net-neutrality-plan-google-115502.html?ml=tl_21&quot;&gt;undergone a last-minute revision&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to remove a potential weakness in its formation, pointed out by Google, that might have allowed for some paid prioritization. If you were curious about Google’s take on net neutrality, that fact should settle the question.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-internet-pirates-wont-be-pursued-using-proposed-metada</id>
      <title>Australia: Internet pirates won&#039;t be pursued using proposed metadata scheme</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-internet-pirates-wont-be-pursued-using-proposed-metada" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T12:49:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Australian&#039;s government proposed data retention scheme won’t be used to go after internet pirates, says Tim Morris the federal police assistant commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morris told a technology conference on Sunday that the $400m scheme, under which Australians’ metadata would be retained by internet service providers for up to two years, was essential to fight cybercrime and terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phone numbers, the time and duration of calls, email addresses and, potentially, URLs would all be stored, but Morris reiterated that the AFP was “not interested in someone sitting down in their lounge room torrenting Game of Thrones”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-bill-would-overturn-fcc-municipal-broadband-decision</id>
      <title>Republican bill would overturn FCC broadband decision</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-bill-would-overturn-fcc-municipal-broadband-decision" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T13:36:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long for congressional Republicans to attack the Federal Communications Commission’s vote to strike down two state laws that prevent municipal broadband networks from expanding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seven Republican lawmakers &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tillis.senate.gov/content/tillis-blackburn-introduce-bill-stop-fcc-nullifying-state-municipal-broadband-laws&quot;&gt;introduced a bill&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, just hours &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.com/article/2889632/fcc-votes-to-overturn-state-laws-limiting-municipal-broadband.html&quot;&gt;after the FCC vote&lt;/a&gt;, that would prohibit the agency from preempting state laws that limit municipal broadband networks. The main sponsors of the bill are Representative Marsha Blackburn, of Tennessee, and Senator Thom Tillis, of North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/congress-is-poised-to-introduce-a-bill-to-fast-track-tpp-so-its</id>
      <title>Fast track bill for TPP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/congress-is-poised-to-introduce-a-bill-to-fast-track-tpp-so-its" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T15:03:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Fast Track bill is likely going to be introduced as early as next week. Congress needs to hear from their constituents that we expect them to hold the White House accountable for the TPP&#039;s restrictive digital policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-fcc-thanks-for-listening-to-team-internet</id>
      <title>FCC vote in favor of broadband reclassification</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-fcc-thanks-for-listening-to-team-internet" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T13:51:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-adopts-strong-sustainable-rules-protect-open-internet&quot;&gt;the FCC voted three to two to reclassify broadband Internet access&lt;/a&gt; as a common carrier service under Title II of the Communications Act, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/07/forbearance-what-it-why-its-essential-net-neutrality-0&quot;&gt;forbear from the parts of the Act that aren’t necessary&lt;/a&gt; for net neutrality rules. This reclassification gives the FCC the authority to enact (and enforce) narrow, clear rules which will help keep the Internet the open platform it is today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As expected, the FCC’s new rules forbid ISPs from charging Internet users for special treatment on their networks. It will also reach interconnection between ISPs and transit providers or edge services, allowing the FCC to ensure that ISPs don’t abuse their gatekeeper authority to favor some services over others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-supports-early-push-in-congress-to-update-online-privacy-law</id>
      <title>EFF supports early push in Congress to update online privacy law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-supports-early-push-in-congress-to-update-online-privacy-law" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T13:55:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the first month of Congress we&#039;ve seen over four bills to update the archaic &lt;a href=&quot;https://ilt.eff.org/index.php/Category:ECPA&quot;&gt;Electronic Communications Privacy Act&lt;/a&gt;, which is the law that&#039;s been used by the Department of Justice to obtain emails and the location of your mobile device without a probable cause warrant. This is in clear violation of legal cases interpreting the Fourth Amendment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-fcc-votes-on-the-future-of-the-internet-live-1</id>
      <title>Net neutrality: FCC votes on the future of the internet – live</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-fcc-votes-on-the-future-of-the-internet-live-1" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:00:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Live coverage of the Federal Communications Commission&#039;s vote on new rules which are expected to ban internet providers from charging more for ‘fast lane’ access.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-rolls-out-new-suicide-prevention-and-support-tools-1</id>
      <title>Facebook rolls out new suicide prevention and support tools</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-rolls-out-new-suicide-prevention-and-support-tools-1" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:03:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Social network adds a report button that flags suicidal content for review by a dedicated team to try and help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook has rolled out new tools in the US that aim to help prevent suicides, allowing users to report content for review and encourage the vulnerable to get help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tools build on a reporting feature &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2011/mar/07/facebook-suicide-alert-samaritans&quot;&gt;implemented in 2011&lt;/a&gt;, which passed details to the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline in the US, and the Samaritans in the UK. The new initiative involves a trained team, more resources and features to help those at risk of suicide or self-harm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-last-100-days-to-pass-surveillance-reform-1</id>
      <title>The last 100 days to pass surveillance reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-last-100-days-to-pass-surveillance-reform-1" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:21:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of this past Saturday, there are less than 100 days remaining until certain provisions of the USA PATRIOT Act will expire unless Congress takes action. Now is the time for Congress to pass surveillance reform, and if they cannot, to allow the USA PATRIOT Act articles to sunset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the expiring provisions, the well-known and well-worn Section 215, has been used to collect phone records of nearly all Americans. Section 215 and the privacy-invasive programs it enables &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pclob.gov/library/215-Report_on_the_Telephone_Records_Program.pdf&quot;&gt;have been rejected&lt;/a&gt; by the government’s own privacy experts. Even intelligence community leaders have &lt;a href=&quot;https://d1ovv0c9tw0h0c.cloudfront.net/files/2014/09/2014-9-2-FISA-letter-from-AG-and-Clapper-to-Leahy-on-S.-2685-USA-Freedom....pdf&quot;&gt;supported real reform&lt;/a&gt;. Minimally acceptable legislation must end bulk collection under the USA PATRIOT Act and increase the transparency of surveillance programs without facilitating any new surveillance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/marco-civil-da-internet-the-devil-in-the-detail</id>
      <title>Brazil: Marco Civil Da Internet or Internet Constitution</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/marco-civil-da-internet-the-devil-in-the-detail" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:26:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;On April 24, 2014, Brazil’s President, Dilma Rousseff, signed &lt;a href=&quot;http://participacao.mj.gov.br/marcocivil/lei-no-12-965-de-23-abril-de-2014/&quot;&gt;Marco Civil Da Internet&lt;/a&gt;, a civil-rights based framework for the Internet which Brazilian activists have long fought. Dubbed the “Internet Constitution,” the law seeks to reinforce the protection of fundamental freedoms in the digital age. One of the most damaging concessions, fiercely opposed by digital rights activists, was a data retention mandate that compels the collection and storage of connections logs of any innocent individual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Brazil is now in the midst of rolling out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://participacao.mj.gov.br/marcocivil/&quot;&gt;Marco Civil’s secondary legislation&lt;/a&gt;, together with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://participacao.mj.gov.br/dadospessoais/&quot;&gt;comprehensive data protection law&lt;/a&gt; that will heavily influence how online companies and governments can treat personal data in the country. The Ministry of Justice &lt;a href=&quot;http://participacao.mj.gov.br/&quot;&gt;has announced&lt;/a&gt; a public online consultation over these two pieces of legislation in the style of the Marco Civil’s process, where all the stakeholders &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internetlab.org.br/en/internetlab-reports/internetlab-reports-public-consultation-no-02/&quot;&gt;can contribute&lt;/a&gt; to the development of the bills. These results of these consultations will determine how Marco Civil is enforced in practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-software-vendors-please-stop-trying-to-intercept-your-custo</id>
      <title>Software vendors need to stop trying to intercept customers’ encrypted traffic</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-software-vendors-please-stop-trying-to-intercept-your-custo" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:57:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past week many more details have emerged about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/02/further-evidence-lenovo-breaking-https-security-its-laptops&quot;&gt;HTTPS-breaking Superfish software that Lenovo pre-installed on its laptops for several months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the security implications have gone from bad to worse the more we’ve learned. For instance, researchers have determined that the software library Superfish uses to intercept traffic—developed by a company known as Komodia—&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.facebook.com/notes/protect-the-graph/windows-ssl-interception-gone-wild/1570074729899339&quot;&gt;is present in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Wack0/17c56b77a90073be81d3&quot;&gt;more than a dozen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://marcrogers.org/2015/02/19/will-the-madness-never-end-komodia-ssl-certificates-are-everywhere/&quot;&gt;other software products&lt;/a&gt;, including parental control software and (supposed) privacy-enhancing/ad-blocking software. All of these products have the same vulnerability that Superfish does: anyone with a little technical know-how could intercept and modify your otherwise secure HTTPS traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-freedom-also-means-banning-positive-discriminatio</id>
      <title>Net neutrality: Freedom also means banning positive discrimination</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-freedom-also-means-banning-positive-discriminatio" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:19:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zero rating, also known as “sponsored data”, is the policy of mobile network providers and mobile virtual network providers to not charge their clients for using specific services, such as Facebook or YouTube. Zero rating is a bad idea for several reasons: You give specific services an advantage over their competitors, and push users towards using a certain service and disadvantage all others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is particularly dangerous in third world countries, because the markets there are still in development. It’s now come to light that in certain African and Asian countries the number of Facebook users is larger than the number of (open) internet users. Which is bad news. It increases Facebook’s ever-growing data monopoly. It’s also detrimental for these countries because it puts the mobile market under pressure: The larger mobile operators that can offer these kinds of bundles are able to easily push the competitors aside.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-internet-pirates-wont-be-pursued-under-data-retention</id>
      <title>Australia: Internet pirates won&#039;t be pursued under data retention scheme</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-internet-pirates-wont-be-pursued-under-data-retention" />
      <updated>2015-02-25T00:30:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Assistant commissioner Tim Morris says ombudsman would prevent pirates being targeted, but ombudsman says his office would have no formal oversight role in proposed scheme&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Authorities are not interested in using the Abbott government’s proposed data retention scheme to go after internet pirates and would be prevented from doing so by the commonwealth ombudsman, the assistant commissioner of the Australian federal police, Tim Morris, has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morris also said any changes to the way metadata is collected and used would have to be approved by the ombudsman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/questions-the-us-congress-should-ask-in-its-iana-transition-hear</id>
      <title>Questions the US Congress should ask in its IANA transition hearing</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/questions-the-us-congress-should-ask-in-its-iana-transition-hear" />
      <updated>2015-02-25T00:33:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 25 the Senate Commerce committee will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.commerce.senate.gov/public/index.cfm?p=Hearings&amp;amp;ContentRecord_id=683924ae-83d7-4bf4-922a-cdecb9556ba9&amp;amp;ContentType_id=14f995b9-dfa5-407a-9d35-56cc7152a7ed&amp;amp;Group_id=b06c39af-e033-4cba-9221-de668ca1978a&quot;&gt;be holding hearings related to ICANN&lt;/a&gt;. For Congress, the hearings will be a progress report on the IANA transition and the ICANN accountability process. Testimony will come from the Assistant Secretary of Commerce Larry Strickling, ICANN CEO Fadi Chehade, and business lobbyist and former State Department ambassador David Gross.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-director-defends-plan-to-maintain-backdoors-into-technology</id>
      <title>NSA director defends plan to maintain &#039;backdoors&#039; into technology companies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-director-defends-plan-to-maintain-backdoors-into-technology" />
      <updated>2015-02-25T00:12:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The National Security Agency director, Mike Rogers, said that “backdoors” would not be harmful to privacy, would not fatally compromise encryption and would not ruin international markets for US technology products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rogers mounted an elaborate defense of Barack Obama’s evolving cybersecurity strategy in an appearance before an audience of cryptographers, tech company security officers and national security reporters at the New America Foundation in Washington. In an hour-long question-and-answer session, Rogers said a cyber-attack against Sony pictures by North Korea last year showed the urgency and difficulty of defending against potential cyber threats.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166440451/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/43b667c2/sc/21/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;kydfgiwgpkfwpdxzwhxw&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166440451/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/43b667c2/sc/21/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166440451/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/43b667c2/sc/21/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;kydfgiwgpkfwpdxzwhxw&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166440451/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/43b667c2/sc/21/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/222166440451/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/43b667c2/sc/21/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-warns-about-the-threats-of-the-trans-pacific-partnership-agr</id>
      <title>EFF warns about the threats of the Trans-Pacific Partnership agreement (TPP)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-warns-about-the-threats-of-the-trans-pacific-partnership-agr" />
      <updated>2015-02-20T13:02:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Trans-Pacific Partnership agreement (TPP) will force other TPP signatories to accept the United States&#039; excessive copyright terms of a minimum of life of the author plus 70 years, while locking the US to the same lengths so it will be harder to shorten them in the future. It contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;DRM &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;anti-circumvention provisions&lt;/a&gt; that will make it a crime to tinker with, hack, re-sell, preserve, and otherwise control any number of digital files and devices that you own. The TPP will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;encourage ISPs to monitor and police &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;their&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt; users&lt;/a&gt;, likely leading to more censorship measures such as the blockage and filtering of content online in the name of copyright enforcement. And in the most recent leak of the TPP&#039;s Intellectual Property chapter, we found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; even more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; alarming provision on trade secrets&lt;/a&gt; that could be used to crackdown on journalists and whistleblowers who report on corporate wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-push-on-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>Last-minute push on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-push-on-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-02-19T11:40:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advocates of strong net neutrality rules have generated more than 1 million messages to the FCC or Congress since the beginning of 2015 via the Battleforthenet.com website. “You can’t buy public opinion,” Evan Greer, campaign director of digital rights group Fight for the Future, said during a press briefing Wednesday. “We very clearly have won in the sphere of public opinion.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FCC is scheduled to vote on new rules that would reclassify broadband as a regulated utility on Feb. 26, and with agency rules mandating a week-long quiet period on lobbying before then, groups on both sides of the long-running debate were making last-minute pitches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-http2-protocol-to-speed-up-web-and-improve-encryption</id>
      <title>New HTTP/2 protocol to speed up web and improve encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-http2-protocol-to-speed-up-web-and-improve-encryption" />
      <updated>2015-02-19T11:47:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new web protocol that promises to speed up internet browsing has been approved. The changeover to HTTP/2, when it happens, will be the first major update to the standard in 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Internet Engineering Steering Group (IESG) has accepted the protocol, one of its senior members wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mnot.net/blog/2015/02/18/http2&quot;&gt;blogpost on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt;. The standard will now go on to be edited before being applied, Mark Nottingham added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its developers believe the new standard will represent a big step forward because it will make pages load quicker and improve encryption.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microsoft-adopts-first-international-cloud-privacy-standard-micr</id>
      <title>Microsoft adopts first international cloud privacy standard</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microsoft-adopts-first-international-cloud-privacy-standard-micr" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:53:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The standard in question may seem technical, but it has important practical benefits for enterprise customers around the world. It’s known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iso.org/iso/home/store/catalogue_tc/catalogue_detail.htm?csnumber=61498&quot;&gt;ISO/IEC 27018&lt;/a&gt;, and it was developed by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iso.org/iso/home.htm&quot;&gt;International Organization for Standardization&lt;/a&gt; (ISO) to establish a uniform, international approach to protecting privacy for personal data stored in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russian-researchers-expose-us-spying-program</id>
      <title>Russian researchers expose U.S. spying program</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/russian-researchers-expose-us-spying-program" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T19:01:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. National Security Agency has figured out how to hide spying software deep within hard drives made by Western Digital, Seagate, Toshiba and other top manufacturers, giving the agency the means to eavesdrop on the majority of the world&#039;s computers, according to cyber researchers and former operatives.&lt;br /&gt;That long-sought and closely guarded ability was part of a cluster of spying programs discovered by Kaspersky Lab, the Moscow-based security software maker that has exposed a series of Western cyberespionage operations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-executive-order-for-information-sharing</id>
      <title>US executive order for information sharing</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-executive-order-for-information-sharing" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:04:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama will set out new cybersecurity rules at a &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/silicon-valley&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; summit on Friday as the White House reacts to the Sony hacking scandal and attempts to mend increasingly ruptured relations with the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The White House announced an executive order to encourage information-sharing between the private sector and the government ahead of Obama’s&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/issues/foreign-policy/cybersecurity/summit&quot;&gt; cybersecurity summit at Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-holds-cybersecurity-summit</id>
      <title>Obama holds cybersecurity summit</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-holds-cybersecurity-summit" />
      <updated>2015-02-13T23:25:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot; id=&quot;story_continues_1&quot;&gt;US President Barack Obama has asked tech firms to share more information with security services and each other to tackle cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The White House confirmed ahead of a cybersecurity summit bringing together leading industry and law enforcement figures that the president would sign an executive order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will also develop a common set of voluntary standards for the organisations to follow, including the protection of civil liberties, the White House said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Obama has also launched an intelligence unit to co-ordinate cyber-threat analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cybersecurity-legislation-introduced-in-us-but-still-doesnt-1</id>
      <title>New cybersecurity legislation introduced in U.S., but still doesn’t protect users</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cybersecurity-legislation-introduced-in-us-but-still-doesnt-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:28:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, U.S. Senator Tom Carper introduced the Cyber Threat Sharing Act of 2015, a new bill to authorize the public/private dissemination of cybersecurity-related information. The legislation’s limitations on the type of information that can be shared are not enough to protect user privacy. Access is calling on the U.S. Congress not to consider information-sharing legislation--which could ostensibly create new surveillance authorities under the guise of cybersecurity--until existing surveillance authorities are adequately reformed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/senators-to-push-privacy-security-legislation-for-iot</id>
      <title>Senators to push privacy, security legislation for IoT</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/senators-to-push-privacy-security-legislation-for-iot" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:27:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some Democratic senators want new laws that mandate security and privacy measures on the Internet of Things, as concern grows over personal data collected by connected devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several democratic members of the Senate Commerce, Science and Transportation Committee said Wednesday they are exploring legislation that would enforce privacy and security standards for connected devices. Senator Edward Markey, a Massachusetts Democrat, plans to introduce a bill that will focus on security standards and the data collected by connected automobiles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-builds-platform-for-companies-to-share-cybersecurity-th</id>
      <title>Facebook builds platform for companies to share cybersecurity threat data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-builds-platform-for-companies-to-share-cybersecurity-th" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T18:37:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook has built a platform where organizations can share information about the security threats they face in order to better fend off cyberattacks. Facebook unveiled the new platform, &lt;a href=&quot;http://threatexchange.fb.com&quot;&gt;ThreatExchange&lt;/a&gt;, on Tuesday. The idea behind it was born over a year ago when several Internet companies, including Facebook, were trying to stop a botnet that was abusing their services to send spam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security vendors have long had private channels for sharing such data among themselves, but this form of collaboration has limits, because, after all, many of them are competitors and have business models built around providing security intelligence to customers as a service. Some companies also share information about attacks through dedicated industry groups, but this leaves them blind to attacks on companies in other industries that could later affect them too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-rights-groups-urge-the-fcc-to-protect-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>Digital rights groups urge the FCC to protect net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-rights-groups-urge-the-fcc-to-protect-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:04:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week 31 digital rights groups from some 21 countries on five continents urged the U.S. Federal Communications Commission to pass strong Net Neutrality rules that that would reclassify broadband providers under Title II of the Communications Act. FCC Chairman Tom Wheeler gave encouraging signs that he intends to propose rules that would harness the full extent of the FCC’s authority on February 26, yet members of the U.S. Congress and some ISPs are already on the attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-to-establish-new-cybersecurity-agency</id>
      <title>US to establish new cybersecurity agency</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-to-establish-new-cybersecurity-agency" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:08:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;The U.S. government is creating a new agency to monitor cybersecurity threats, pooling and analyzing information on a spectrum of risks, a senior Obama administration official said on Tuesday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;The Cyber Threat Intelligence Integration Center (CTIIC) will be an &quot;intelligence center that will &#039;connect the dots&#039; between various cyber threats to the nation so that relevant departments and agencies are aware of these threats in as close to real time as possible,&quot; the official said on condition of anonymity. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;Obama has moved cybersecurity to the top of his 2015 agenda after recent hacking attacks against Sony Pictures (&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_6758.T_0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=6758.T&quot;&gt;6758.T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;)(&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_SNE.N_1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=SNE.N&quot;&gt;SNE.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), Home Depot Inc (&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_HD.N_2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=HD.N&quot;&gt;HD.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;), Anthem Inc (&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_ANTM.N_3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=ANTM.N&quot;&gt;ANTM.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and Target Corp (&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_TGT.N_4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=TGT.N&quot;&gt;TGT.N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and the federal government itself. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/update-on-the-iana-transition</id>
      <title>Update on the IANA transition</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/update-on-the-iana-transition" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:11:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Friday and Saturday, the IANA Stewardship Coordination Group (ICG) met and succeeded in assessing proposals submitted by the IETF for &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-ianaplan-icg-response-09&quot;&gt;protocol parameters&lt;/a&gt; and the Regional Internet Registries (RIRs) for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nro.net/wp-content/uploads/ICG-RFP-Number-Resource-Proposal.pdf&quot;&gt;numbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the time being, both the IETF/protocol parameter proposal and the RIRs’ proposal for numbers would retain ICANN as the IANA functions provider. But both proposals established (or, in the case of IETF, retained) a severable contractual relationship with ICANN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Congress is now circling about the process intently, declaring this week &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/114th-congress/senate-resolution/71/text&quot;&gt;“Internet Governance awareness week&lt;/a&gt;” to encourage public awareness of the transition and education about the importance of it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/silk-roads-owner-convicted-of-running-online-drug-marketplace</id>
      <title>Silk Road&#039;s owner convicted of running online drug marketplace</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/silk-roads-owner-convicted-of-running-online-drug-marketplace" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:11:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The suspected mastermind of the online drug emporium &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/silk-road&quot;&gt;Silk Road&lt;/a&gt; is facing the prospect of spending the rest of his life in prison after a jury returned a guilty verdict at the end of a four-week trial that revealed a plethora of detail about US investigations into the use of the bitcoin digital currency for drug trafficking and other crimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ross Ulbricht, 30, was convicted on all seven charges which he had faced at Manhattan district court, including drug trafficking, criminal enterprise, aiding and abetting the distribution of drugs over the internet, computer hacking and money laundering.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-cheers-fcc-move-toward-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>Access cheers FCC move toward Net Neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-cheers-fcc-move-toward-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:02:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today U.S. Federal Communications Commission Chairman Tom Wheeler confirmed that the agency will move to pass strong Net Neutrality protections later this month. Any action by Congress to roll back FCC authority or threaten common carrier status for broadband providers will meet thunderous opposition, by U.S. users as well as international communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.15;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;Chairman Wheeler’s statement signals that the FCC could soon put its full enforcement power to work to protect the open internet for close to 300 million users—and countering the threats that blocking, “fast lanes,” and throttling of content and services pose to human rights like free expression and privacy online. In Chairman Wheeler’s &lt;a style=&quot;text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/02/fcc-chairman-wheeler-net-neutrality/&quot;&gt;own words&lt;/a&gt;, “These enforceable, bright-line rules will ban paid prioritization, and the blocking and throttling of lawful content and services.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;line-height:1.15;margin-top:0pt;margin-bottom:0pt;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-chairman-says-broadband-should-be-treated-as-utility-for-net</id>
      <title>FCC chairman says broadband should be treated as utility for net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-chairman-says-broadband-should-be-treated-as-utility-for-net" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:51:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chairman of the U.S. Federal Communications Commission has proposed net neutrality rules based on reclassifying broadband as a regulated public utility and will ask fellow commissioners to approve that approach later this month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FCC Chairman Tom Wheeler, as expected, will offer net neutrality rules that reverse a long-standing agency practice of treating broadband as a lightly regulated information service, instead reclassifying it as a regulated common carrier under Title II of the Telecommunications Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I am submitting to my colleagues the strongest open Internet protections ever proposed by the FCC,” Wheeler wrote in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/02/fcc-chairman-wheeler-net-neutrality&quot;&gt;Wired.com opinion piece&lt;/a&gt; published Wednesday. “These enforceable, bright-line rules will ban paid prioritization, and the blocking and throttling of lawful content and services.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/broadband-reclassification-is-essential-bur-the-devil-is-always</id>
      <title>Broadband reclassification is essential, bur the devil is always in the details, EFF says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/broadband-reclassification-is-essential-bur-the-devil-is-always" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:51:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;According to an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2015/02/fcc-chairman-wheeler-net-neutrality/&quot;&gt;op-ed &lt;/a&gt;published today in Wired, in a few weeks the FCC will vote on new rules that start with one crucial step: reversing the FCC’s 2002 decision to treat broadband as an “information service” rather than a “telecommunications service.” This is what’s known as Title II reclassification. According to the highest court to review the question, the rules that we need to preserve the open internet — such as forbidding discrimination against certain applications — require the FCC to treat access providers like “common carriers, ” treatment that can only be applied to telecommunications services. Having chosen to define broadband as an “information service,” the FCC can impose regulations that “promote competition” (good) but it cannot stop providers from giving their friends special access to Internet users (bad). INt&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-to-force-authors-to-provide-real-names-when-publishing-onl</id>
      <title>China to force authors to provide real names when publishing online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-to-force-authors-to-provide-real-names-when-publishing-onl" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:37:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;story-body-text&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;The Chinese government called for a system that would require all authors to register their real names with publishing platforms on the Internet. Under the guidelines, creators of online content will still be allowed to publish under pen names. But unlike before, when some writers registered accounts under fake names, websites will know exactly who is publishing what.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-raises-threshold-for-high-speed-internet</id>
      <title>FCC raises threshold for high-speed internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-raises-threshold-for-high-speed-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:34:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Federal Communications Commission on Thursday changed the definition of broadband to increase the threshold speed. In a 3-2 vote, the commission approved a measure that increases the minimum standard for broadband speed, giving the agency more power to force internet service providers to improve their service. The definition of broadband is set to be raised from 4 megabits per second (Mbps) to 25Mbps for downloads and 1Mbps to 3Mbps for uploads.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cyberthreat-sharing-must-include-strong-privacy-protections-advo</id>
      <title>Cyberthreat sharing must include strong privacy protections, advocates say</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cyberthreat-sharing-must-include-strong-privacy-protections-advo" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:38:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. lawmakers should put strict privacy controls into planned legislation to encourage companies to share cyberthreat information with government agencies and each other, some advocates said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee said Wednesday they plan to work on a cyberthreat information-sharing bill in the coming months. But representatives from Microsoft and the Center for Democracy and Technology told lawmakers they can avoid the controversies of other recent bills by requiring companies and government agencies to strip out personally identifiable information before sending cyberthreat information to other organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cybersecurity-rules-in-china</id>
      <title>New cybersecurity rules in China</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-cybersecurity-rules-in-china" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:39:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government has adopted new regulations requiring companies that sell computer equipment to Chinese banks to turn over secret source code, submit to invasive audits and build so-called back doors into hardware and software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a letter sent Wednesday to a top-level Communist Party committee on cybersecurity, led by President Xi Jinping, foreign business groups objected to the new policies and complained that they amounted to protectionism.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-security-agency-violates-defense-department-privacy-rul</id>
      <title>National Security Agency violates defense department privacy rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-security-agency-violates-defense-department-privacy-rul" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:37:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Defense Department has issued a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/FR-2015-01-27/pdf/2015-01262.pdf&quot;&gt;regulation&lt;/a&gt; for all Privacy Programs within the agency, including the National Security Agency&#039;s. EPIC &lt;a target=&quot;_self&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/nsa/Coal-DoD-Priv-Program-Cmts.pdf&quot;&gt;urged&lt;/a&gt; the Department to require the NSA to comply with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/1974act/&quot;&gt;Privacy Act&lt;/a&gt;, which permits individuals to know about government databases and to inspect their records held by federal agencies. The DoD responded that the NSA complies with the Privacy Act. However, the NSA &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://dpcld.defense.gov/Privacy/DODComponentArticleList/tabid/6799/Category/283/national-security-agencycentral-security-service.aspx&quot;&gt;fails&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://dpcld.defense.gov/Privacy/SORNsIndex/DODComponentArticleView/tabid/7489/Article/6618/gnsa-18.aspx&quot;&gt;describe&lt;/a&gt; the databases it maintains, which contain telephone numbers, email addresses, and social media information of U.S. citizens, in violation of the Privacy Act.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-blocks-vpn-access-to-the-internet</id>
      <title>China blocks VPN access to the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-blocks-vpn-access-to-the-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:40:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Global Times&lt;/i&gt; newspaper in Beijing reported that China announced it is &quot;upgrading&quot; its Internet censorship to disrupt VPN services inside the nation of 1.3 billion people. The Great Firewall of China has long blocked those within the country from reaching popular international sites such as Google, Twitter, Facebook and YouTube. To get around it, people must purchase access to a virtual private network, or VPN. These services allow a user to create a private pipeline to the Internet, bypassing China&#039;s online censors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Under Chinese law, companies and individuals that use VPN services are required to &lt;/span&gt;register with the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, though few do. Astrill, one of the more popular VPN providers in China tweeted that &quot;due to increased censorship in China,&quot; VPN usage on Apple devices was being blocked &quot;in almost real-time.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-can-happen-from-a-domain-name-system-error</id>
      <title>What can happen from a domain name system error</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-can-happen-from-a-domain-name-system-error" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:44:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A domain name system error directed all the internet traffic from China - 13,000 requests per second - to one small firm in North Carolina. What happens if a significant proportion of all the web traffic in &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/a&gt; gets directed to one server? Perhaps unsurprisingly, the answer is “that server dies a rapid death”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Craig Hockenberry, the senior software engineer for developers Iconfactory, reports that in the end, he was forced to block all traffic coming from China in order to keep the site up and running. “I’m a big believer in the power of an open and freely accessible internet: I don’t take blocking traffic from innocent people lightly. But in this case, it’s the only thing that worked.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-transformation-to-a-digital-government</id>
      <title>Australia&#039;s transformation to a digital government</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-transformation-to-a-digital-government" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:42:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Australians may soon be able to pay bills to every level of government and get information about all government services through a single website with one login, as easily as they can do internet banking or order a taxi through an app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communications minister Malcolm Turnbull said his first priority was “how to make the service work from the point of view of the customer” because “we already know it is going to save money”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-needs-agency-for-data-protection-european-commissioner-tells</id>
      <title>UN needs agency for data protection, European commissioner tells Davos</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-needs-agency-for-data-protection-european-commissioner-tells" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:46:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new UN agency for data protection and data security is needed to protect the confidential and personal information of citizens around the world, the European commissioner for digital economy told delegates at the World Economic Forum on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Günther Oettinger said the recent Sony hack, which exposed swaths of confidential and personal information, had shown Europe the need to radically reshape the way data is used.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-net-neutrality-proposal-falls-short-critics-say</id>
      <title>Criticism to the Republican net neutrality proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-net-neutrality-proposal-falls-short-critics-say" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:45:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Republican net neutrality proposal in the U.S. Congress would not fully protect broadband customers because it would prohibit the Federal Communications Commission from enacting new rules against selectively blocking or throttling traffic, critics said Wednesday. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.com/article/2871972/republican-net-neutrality-bill-allows-reasonable-network-management.html&quot;&gt;Republican draft legislation&lt;/a&gt; would kill the FCC’s ability to act on schemes that prioritize some traffic over others, witnesses told a congressional committee. The proposal “would strip the county’s expert communications agency of authority to protect consumers on the communications platform of the 21st century,” said Jessica Gonzalez, executive vice president of the National Hispanic Media Coalition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-snowden-show-nsa-preparations-for-cyber-battle</id>
      <title>New Snowden show NSA preparations for cyber battle</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-snowden-show-nsa-preparations-for-cyber-battle" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:47:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to top secret documents from the archive of NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden seen exclusively by SPIEGEL, they are planning for wars of the future in which the Internet will play a critical role, with the aim of being able to use the net to paralyze computer networks and, by doing so, potentially all the infrastructure they control, including power and water supplies, factories, airports or the flow of money.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-urges-congress-to-reject-cispa</id>
      <title>Access urges Congress to reject CISPA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-urges-congress-to-reject-cispa" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:47:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Dutch Ruppersberger (D-MD) re-introduced the Cyber Information Sharing and Protection Act (“CISPA”), a bill that has passed the House of Representatives twice previously, both in 2011 and 2013, and subsequently also twice faced a veto threat from the Administration. We once again urge Congress to reject CISPA. Instead, Congress should pass the Secure Data Act. Unlike CIPSA, it would actually protect user privacy and increase data security.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-protect-priva</id>
      <title>Secret US cybersecurity report: encryption vital to protect private data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/secret-us-cybersecurity-report-encryption-vital-to-protect-priva" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:55:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A secret US cybersecurity report warned that government and private computers were being left vulnerable to online attacks from Russia, China and criminal gangs because encryption technologies were not being implemented fast enough. The advice, in a newly uncovered five-year forecast written in 2009, contrasts with the pledge made by David Cameron this week to crack down on encryption use by technology companies.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cia-releases-report-on-surveillance-of-congress</id>
      <title>CIA releases report on surveillance of Congress</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cia-releases-report-on-surveillance-of-congress" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:50:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months after EPIC filed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://epic.org/foia/&quot;&gt;Freedom of Information Act&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://epic.org/foia/cia/congressspying/&quot;&gt;lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against the Central Intelligence Agency, the agency has released the &lt;a href=&quot;https://epic.org/foia/cia/07-2014-CIA-OIG-Rpt.pdf&quot;&gt;Inspector General&#039;s report&lt;/a&gt; on the agency&#039;s surveillance of Congress. The Inspector General launched an investigation after the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.feinstein.senate.gov/public/index.cfm/2014/3/feinstein-statement-on-intelligence-committee-s-cia-detention-interrogation-report&quot;&gt;Senate accused&lt;/a&gt; the CIA of improperly accessing the computers of Senate staff who were investigating CIA torture practices. The Inspector General found that CIA personnel improperly accessed Senate computers multiple times. The Inspector General also found that the CIA&#039;s accusations that Senate staff had improperly removed CIA files were baseless.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-bill-to-ensure-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>Republican bill to ensure net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republican-bill-to-ensure-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:56:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Top Republicans in Congress plan to introduce legislation that they say will ensure net neutrality protections for Internet users and will spur U.S. economic growth. The proposal would create “unambiguous” rules prohibiting broadband providers from selectively blocking or throttling Web traffic, while avoiding a reclassification of broadband as a regulated public utility.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-debates-in-india</id>
      <title>Net neutrality debates in India</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-debates-in-india" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:00:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Net neutrality is a global issue, but only recently has it made headlines in India. Last November, the Telecommunications Regulatory Authority of India (TRAI) announced it would investigate data plans offered by Airtel,&amp;nbsp;the country’s biggest mobile provider, that offer lower rates on specific apps (such as WhatsApp and Facebook) to determine whether this practice impacts net neutrality. But the very next month, following Airtel’s proposed hike in data charges for VoIP, TRAI’s chairperson said in an interview that this plan, while being against the principle of net neutrality, was not illegal because there are no laws or policies endorsing net neutrality in India. This has created confusion about TRAI’s views on net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/effs-call-to-stop-tpp-and-ttip-from-fast-track-ratification</id>
      <title>EFF&#039;s call to stop TPP and TTIP from fast track ratification</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/effs-call-to-stop-tpp-and-ttip-from-fast-track-ratification" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Senators are now working around the clock to re-introduce a bill that would put trade agreements on the fast track to passage in the US after those deals are finalized. Deals like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;Trans-Pacific Partnership&lt;/a&gt; (TPP) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/01/europe-releases-its-ttip-proposals-intellectual-property&quot;&gt;Trans-Atlantic Trade and Investment Partnership&lt;/a&gt; (TTIP) have been negotiated in almost complete secrecy, except for private industry advocates serving on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/02/us-trade-rep-charm-offensive-slight-tweaks-secret-tpp-process-far-enough&quot;&gt;trade advisory committees&lt;/a&gt; who can read and comment on these texts. That has enabled these agreements to include extreme copyright and other digital policy provisions that would bind all signatory nations to draconian rules that would hinder free speech, privacy, and access to knowledge. Under fast track, also referred to as Trade Promotion Authority, lawmakers would only have a small window of time to conduct hearings over binding trade provisions and give an up-or-down vote on ratification of the agreement without any ability to amend it before they bind the United States to its terms.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-statement-on-obamas-cybersecurity-law</id>
      <title>EFF statement on Obama&#039;s cybersecurity law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-statement-on-obamas-cybersecurity-law" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:58:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EFF published a statement saying that introducing information sharing proposals with broad liability protections, increasing penalties under the already draconian Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, and potentially decreasing the protections granted to consumers under state data breach law are both unnecessary and unwelcome.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/knight-foundation-net-neutrality-report</id>
      <title>Knight Foundation: Net Neutrality Report</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/knight-foundation-net-neutrality-report" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:00:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Knight Foundation released a report on net neutrality, analyzing recent development and debates.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/should-consumer-drones-be-better-regulated</id>
      <title>Should consumer drones be better regulated?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/should-consumer-drones-be-better-regulated" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:57:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/dec/07/drone-near-miss-passenger-plane-heathrow&quot;&gt;near miss&lt;/a&gt; between a passenger jet and a drone near Heathrow airport, five experts give their views.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-policy-on-increasing-access-to-the-whole-internet-not-jus</id>
      <title>Public policy on increasing access to the WHOLE internet - not just Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-policy-on-increasing-access-to-the-whole-internet-not-jus" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:52:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The social media firm’s latest big idea is to allow users in developing nations free net access if they use its app. The goal of public policy everywhere should be to increase access to the internet – the whole internet, not some corporate-controlled alcove – for as many people as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-will-unveil-new-cybersecurity-initiatives-this-week</id>
      <title>Obama will unveil new cybersecurity initiatives this week</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-will-unveil-new-cybersecurity-initiatives-this-week" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:02:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama is set to unveil a series of initiatives to bolster U.S. cybersecurity that he will detail in speeches this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. president will lay out a series of legislative proposals and executive actions that will be in his State of the Union that will tackle identity theft and privacy issues, cybersecurity, and access to the Internet, reported the New York Times, quoting a White House official.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-approves-privacy-resolution</id>
      <title>UN approves privacy resolution</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-approves-privacy-resolution" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:51:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UN General Assembly &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.un.org/press/en/2014/ga11604.doc.htm&quot;&gt;formally approved&lt;/a&gt; a major resolution on the right to privacy yesterday, by consensus. The resolution spotlights the privacy violations that are enabled by advances in technology, overbearing government surveillance, and corporate complicity. As communications have gone global, so too must privacy protections. Privacy rights limited by national borders are increasingly meaningless. This resolution contains strong language that definitively places mass surveillance under international human rights law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-leaked-document-on-the-trade-in-services-agreement-tisa-expo</id>
      <title>New leaked document on the Trade in Services Agreement (TiSA) exposes threats to privacy, data protection, and net neutrality.</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-leaked-document-on-the-trade-in-services-agreement-tisa-expo" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:51:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;TiSA, or the Trade in Services Agreement, is a trade accord currently being negotiated by &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/trade/policy/in-focus/tisa/&quot;&gt;23 member countries&lt;/a&gt; of the World Trade Organisation (WTO), including the EU, the U.S., Japan, Costa Rica, and Israel. TiSA aims to further open these markets up for trade in services, such as e-commerce, cross-border data flows, and technology transfer. The negotiations of this agreement were launched in 2013 and are taking place behind closed doors. They are not subject to public to the same pressure for transparency, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2014/07/23/ttip-negotiations-transparently-opaque&quot;&gt;other infamous trade agreements&lt;/a&gt; have been in the past, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/ACTA/booklet/ACTAbookletEN.pdf&quot;&gt;ACTA&lt;/a&gt;, the current &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;TPP&lt;/a&gt;, and the TTIP. However, this trade deal could have a similar, if not bigger,&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statewatch.org/analyses/no-257-ttip-ralf-bendrath.pdf&quot;&gt; impact on digital rights&lt;/a&gt; and particularly the rights to privacy, data protection and freedom of expression.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cispa-will-be-re-introduced-after-sony-hack</id>
      <title>CISPA will be re-introduced after Sony hack</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cispa-will-be-re-introduced-after-sony-hack" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:49:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After privacy concerns derailed this controversial legislation in the U.S. Senate, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thehill.com/policy/cybersecurity/228945-top-house-dem-to-reintroduce-major-cyber-bill&quot;&gt;CISPA will be re-introduced Friday&lt;/a&gt; by a senior Democrat on the House Intelligence Committee, reports The Hill. Maryland Representative Dutch Ruppersberger said he’s bringing the Cyber Intelligence Sharing and Protection Act back to the floor in response to the Sony hack, blamed on North Korea.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/reintroduced-bill-on-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>Reintroduced bill on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/reintroduced-bill-on-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:05:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday the Democrats introduced a bill in both the House of Representatives and the Senate that would require the U.S. Federal Communications Commission to ban paid prioritization agreements. The FCC is preparing to vote on new net neutrality rules in late February, after an appeals court threw out a large portion of the agency’s old rules a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reintroduced &lt;a href=&quot;http://matsui.house.gov/uploads/Online%20Competition%20and%20Consumer%20Choice%20Act%20for%20114th%20Congress.pdf&quot;&gt;Online Competition and Consumer Choice Act&lt;/a&gt;, which failed to pass after Democrats introduced it last year, is designed to prevent broadband providers from creating Internet fast lanes and slow lanes, based on the ability of Web content providers and services to pay for faster speeds, sponsors said.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/critics-to-the-netmundial-initiative</id>
      <title>Critics to the NetMundial Initiative</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/critics-to-the-netmundial-initiative" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:08:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The year 2014 was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2014/08/27/why-im-going-to-geneva-for-the-netmundial-initiative&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;historic year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in internet governance: From the announcement of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntia.doc.gov/press-release/2014/ntia-announces-intent-transition-key-internet-domain-name-functions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IANA transition process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.internetgovernance.org/2014/04/27/netmundial-moves-net-governance-beyond-wsis/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetMundial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; meeting and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://linguasynaptica.com/pp14-itu-not-taking-over-net/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ITU Plenipotentiary Conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the procedures and policies regarding the coordination of the internet seem to be more than ever a central topic of global governance. But just before the end of the year, yet another process in internet governance added a bitter aftertaste to this development: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netmundial.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetMundial Initiative (NMI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Perceived by some as an attempt to create a “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/11/07/internet_un_security_council_net_mundial_initiative/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Council of the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”, this new initiative has stirred an intense debate among civil society groups about the limits of multistakeholder governance – a debate which could actually help to overcome the gridlocked controversy between multistakeholder and intergovernmental governance models for the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tisa-trade-agreement-threatens-net-neutrality-data-protection-an</id>
      <title>TISA trade agreement threatens net neutrality, data protection and consumer rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tisa-trade-agreement-threatens-net-neutrality-data-protection-an" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:53:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://data.awp.is/filtrala/2014/12/17/19.html&quot;&gt;newest leak on the &lt;strong&gt;TISA trade agreement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; once again confirms the danger that free trade agreements pose to our democracy. Like ACTA, CETA and TTIP before it, TISA demonstrates that these intransparently negotiated treaties are &lt;strong&gt;driven by the interests of multinational corporations&lt;/strong&gt; and risk undermining the efforts of the European Parliament to ensure consumer protection, data protection, net neutrality etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US proposal now made public would undermine European &lt;strong&gt;data protection&lt;/strong&gt; regulations. The EU would be rendered unable to enforce European standards on service providers from the signatory states thanks to clauses allowing the transfer of personal data and freeing companies from any requirements to establish local registered offices.r&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/samsung-pledges-to-make-an-open-internet-of-things</id>
      <title>Samsung pledges to make an open Internet of Things</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/samsung-pledges-to-make-an-open-internet-of-things" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:07:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/samsung&quot;&gt;Samsung&lt;/a&gt; sold 665m devices last year, many of which already have internet connectivity. But Yoon promised that by 2017 90% of those devices will plug into the IoT ecosystem, and 100% in five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’ve heard people say they want to create a single operating system for IoT, but these people only work with their own devices. We can deliver the benefits of IoT only if all sensors can talk to each other,” said Yoon in his opening keynote for &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/ces&quot;&gt;CES&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas where he laid out Samsung’s vision for the future of IoT. “I’m making a promise that our IoT devices and products will be open. We will ensure that others can easily connect to our devices.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-freedom-china-russia-and-us-policies</id>
      <title>Internet freedom &amp; China, Russia and US policies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-freedom-china-russia-and-us-policies" />
      <updated>2015-01-05T14:51:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recent reports that &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/dec/29/google-gmail-blocked-china-great-firewall&quot;&gt;China has imposed further restrictions on Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. This loophole has now been closed, which means determined Chinese users have had to turn to more advanced circumvention tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it’s not just the Chinese. A new law that came into effect last summer obliges all &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/jun/19/russia-digital-soveriegnty-nsa-surveillance&quot;&gt;internet companies to store Russian citizens’ data on servers inside the country&lt;/a&gt;. This has already prompted &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/dec/12/google-closes-engineering-office-russia&quot;&gt;Google to close down its engineering operations&lt;/a&gt; in Moscow. The Kremlin’s recent success in getting &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/dec/30/-sp-verdict-alexei-navalny-kremlin-critic-galvanises-russia-opposition&quot;&gt;Facebook to block a page calling for protests in solidarity with the charged activist Alexey Navalny&lt;/a&gt; indicates that the government is rapidly re-establishing control over its citizens’ digital activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/sep/20/brazil-dilma-rousseff-internet-us-control&quot;&gt;Brazil toyed with the idea of forcing American companies to store user data locally &lt;/a&gt;– an idea it eventually abandoned. However, Russia, China and Brazil are simply responding to the extremely aggressive tactics adopted by none other than the US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-to-vote-on-net-neutrality-rules-in-february</id>
      <title>FCC to vote on net neutrality rules in February</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fcc-to-vote-on-net-neutrality-rules-in-february" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:55:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Federal Communications Commission plans to vote on new net neutrality rules during its February meeting. FCC Chairman Tom Wheeler will bring a proposal to a vote during the commission’s Feb. 26 meeting, FCC spokeswoman Kim Hart said Friday, following &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2015/01/02/get-ready-the-fcc-says-itll-vote-on-net-neutrality-in-february/&quot;&gt;a report in the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/white-house-approves-sanctions-against-north-korea-for-sony-hack</id>
      <title>White House approves sanctions against North Korea for Sony hack</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/white-house-approves-sanctions-against-north-korea-for-sony-hack" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:55:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. President Barack Obama has authorized new economic sanctions against North Korea, in part for the country’s alleged hack of Sony Pictures Entertainment in November, the White House said. Obama’s executive order is “a response to the government of North Korea’s ongoing provocative, destabilizing, and repressive actions and policies, particularly its destructive and coercive cyber attack on Sony Pictures Entertainment,” the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2015/01/02/statement-press-secretary-executive-order-entitled-imposing-additional-s&quot;&gt;White House said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-censorship-in-2015</id>
      <title>Internet censorship in 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-censorship-in-2015" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:56:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Russia’s president, Vladimir V. Putin, signed the latest version of a personal data law that will require companies to store data about Russian users on computers inside the country, where it will be easier for the government to get access to it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/happy-new-year-happy-new-iana</id>
      <title>Happy New Year, Happy New IANA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/happy-new-year-happy-new-iana" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:09:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the new year dawns a new IANA is emerging, but the outlines are still blurry. IGP has reviewed all the public comments submitted in response to the CWG’s draft proposal. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1eC0qwH1-MrwJ8oj3NL2sMB5e3zNBwfNYHUdXNQ8uFQQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;The results can be seen directly here&lt;/a&gt;. Two-thirds (67%) of the comments directly addressing the issue supported the core ideas behind the draft: that the IANA functions operator should be separable from ICANN, and that there should be an external oversight entity with the authority to award the IANA functions contract on a periodic basis, just as the NTIA did before.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/intelligence-layer-for-the-internet-of-things</id>
      <title>Intelligence layer for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/intelligence-layer-for-the-internet-of-things" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:08:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;IFTTT has far bigger ambitions, explains founder and CEO Linden Tibbets. Its future, he believes, is in connecting the &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/internet-of-things&quot;&gt;internet of things&lt;/a&gt; - everyday devices and objects increasingly being given internet capability to be monitored, controlled and connected online. As part of the ambition to make IFTTT “a foundational layer” for the internet of things, a next step is to make recipes a fixed part of third party apps. So where Instagram users are offered the choice of posting to Facebook and Twitter, they might be offered an IFTTT recipe too.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/snowden-revelations-make-ietf-rethink-security</id>
      <title>Snowden revelations make IETF rethink security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/snowden-revelations-make-ietf-rethink-security" />
      <updated>2015-01-02T11:18:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the Snowden revelations, the IETF said it was going to do something about mass surveillance. In May 2014, the IETF published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7258&quot;&gt;“best practice” document&lt;/a&gt; stating baldly that “pervasive monitoring is an attack.” Snowden’s revelations prompted a fundamental rethink within the IETF about what kind of security the internet should be aiming for overall. Specifically, the IETF is in the process of &lt;a href=&quot;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-dukhovni-opportunistic-security/&quot;&gt;formalizing&lt;/a&gt; a concept called “opportunistic security” whereby — even if full end-to-end security isn’t practical for whatever reason — some security is now officially recognized as being better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-users-care-more-about-online-privacy-and-security</id>
      <title>Internet users care more about online privacy and security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-users-care-more-about-online-privacy-and-security" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:12:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Journalist &lt;span class=&quot;fn&quot;&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;author&quot; itemprop=&quot;url&quot; href=&quot;http://www.itworld.com/author/Lucas-Mearian/&quot;&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt;Lucas Mearian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span itemprop=&quot;name&quot;&gt; reports that &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;an international &lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cigionline.org/internet-survey&quot;&gt;survey of Internet users&lt;/a&gt; has found that more than 39% have taken steps to protect their online privacy and security as a result of spying revelations by one-time NSA employee Edward Snowden. The survey, conducted by the Centre for International Governance Innovation (CIGI), found that 43% of Internet users now avoid certain websites and applications and 39% change their passwords regularly. The survey reached 23,376 Internet users in 24 countries and was conducted between Oct. 7 and Nov. 12.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-says-new-gtlds-did-not-cause-data-breaches</id>
      <title>ICANN says new gTLDs did not cause data breaches</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/icann-says-new-gtlds-did-not-cause-data-breaches" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:12:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CSO reports that an ICANN spokesman dismissed accusations that the recent growth in the number of generic top-level domains has caused data breaches. There are now more than 700 top-level domains such as .meme, .guru and .blog. The number of TLDs has exploded only recently -- between 1985 and 2012, the number of TLDs grew slowly, from five to 22. According to critics, the recent growth has been a &lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;http://www.csoonline.com/article/2687132/social-engineering/recently-introduced-tlds-create-new-opportunities-for-criminals.html&quot;&gt;windfall for cyber criminals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sony-pictures-was-hacked</id>
      <title>Sony Pictures was hacked</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sony-pictures-was-hacked" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:14:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;Journalist Martyn Williams writes that more of Sony Picture&#039;s corporate secrets appears to have been put on the Internet over the weekend. Sony Pictures was hacked in late November and has had to endure two weeks of embarrassing leaks of corporate information onto the Internet.&lt;p&gt;The major Hollywood movie studio first saw several unreleased movies uploaded then salary information about its employees. Leaks have also included medical information about employees, financial data, contracts for TV shows and, last week, the Outlook email boxes of two senior executives. Those email leaks revealed embarassing message exchanges with executives at Sony and other Hollywood studios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microsofts-fight-for-privacy</id>
      <title>Microsoft&#039;s fight for privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microsofts-fight-for-privacy" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:14:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/29/us-court-microsoft-personal-data-emails-irish-server&quot;&gt;US government demands&lt;/a&gt; Microsoft access to a customer&#039;s emails which are currently sitting on a server in Dublin, Ireland, as part of a narcotics investigation. Earlier this year, a US court ruled that Microsoft should hand the data over. Microsoft declined to comply, voluntarily entering into contempt. Last week Microsoft filed its appeal. If Microsoft loses, Microsoft&#039;s general counsel, Brad Smith, argues it could put all of our private digital information at risk as well as further damaging the standing and reputation of US tech firms still reeling from &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/edward-snowden&quot;&gt;the NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden’s&lt;/a&gt; leaks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sir-tim-berners-lee-recognise-the-internet-as-a-human-right</id>
      <title>Sir Tim Berners-Lee: Recognise the Internet as a human right</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sir-tim-berners-lee-recognise-the-internet-as-a-human-right" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:21:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sir Tim Berners-Lee called for the Internet to be recognised as a basic human right. Sir Tim noted that in our increasingly unequal world, the Web has the potential to be a great equalizer, but only &lt;i&gt;“if we hardwire the rights to privacy, freedom of expression, affordable access and net neutrality into the rules of the game.” &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2014-15 edition of the Web Foundation’s annual Web Index examines key Web issues — including privacy, censorship, gender-based violence, equality and, for the first time ever, net neutrality — across 86 countries. The findings from this year’s Index point to a Web that is becoming less free and more unequal.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-supports-the-efforts-of-congress-to-pass-cybersecurity-le</id>
      <title>Access supports the efforts of Congress to pass cybersecurity legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-supports-the-efforts-of-congress-to-pass-cybersecurity-le" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:50:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 13th U.S. Congress pushed through four positive last-minute cybersecurity bills over the past two days. President Obama is soon expected to sign these bills into law. The new cyber measures increase government transparency and Congressional oversight of federal cybersecurity efforts, while expanding coordination between civilian agencies. Access supports the efforts of Congress to pass cybersecurity legislation and hopes the momentum will lead to more significant legislation for the 114th Congress.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fbi-the-top-3-ways-congress-could-help-fight-tenacious-cyber-thr</id>
      <title>FBI proposes Congress 3 ways to fight cyber threats</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fbi-the-top-3-ways-congress-could-help-fight-tenacious-cyber-thr" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:18:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;FBI’s assistant director Joseph Demarest suggested three ways Congress could combat cyber threat: to&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;update the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, to require businesses to provide prompt notice to consumers in the wake of cyber attacks, and for government and the private sector to share insights into cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/twitter-should-reconsider-the-reports-of-abuse</id>
      <title>Twitter should reconsider the reports of abuse</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/twitter-should-reconsider-the-reports-of-abuse" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T15:29:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;California-based journalist Darwin BondGraham tweeted a document he had obtained under the state’s public records act. It showed an email exchange between an employee and a customer of the law enforcement contractor, &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://predpol.com/&quot;&gt;PredPol&lt;/a&gt;. Shortly afterwards, the employee responded on Twitter by asking BondGraham not to publish personal information publicly. The request apparently referred to the fact that the office phone number was visible in the emails. After BondGraham refused to remove the Tweet, he received a notification from Twitter that his account had been suspended.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-congress-possible-attempt-to-compromise-the-iana-transition</id>
      <title>US Congress possible attempt to compromise the IANA transition</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-congress-possible-attempt-to-compromise-the-iana-transition" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:52:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet Governance project reports that the House of Representatives passed a consolidated appropriations bill to fund the majority of government through fiscal year 2015. Contradicting their ‘Internet freedom’ rhetoric, Republicans attached a rider to the gigantic ($1.014 trillion) federal funding bill that defunded any attempt by the NTIA to set the domain name system free of government control until October 2015. The action does not stop ongoing community efforts to develop a plan for the IANA transition. But it does prevent the NTIA from spending any time on completing the process. Paul Rosenzweig &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lawfareblog.com/2014/12/congress-tries-to-stop-the-iana-transition-but-does-it/&quot;&gt;wrote on the Lawfare blog&lt;/a&gt; that this does not totally prevent the transition from happening, because “the act of &lt;em&gt;not signing&lt;/em&gt; a contract (which is what NTIA proposes to do) costs nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this relatively optimistic view overlooks the fact that completing the transition requires a bit more than just not renewing ICANN’s contract. It also requires NTIA to amend its Cooperative Agreement with Verisign. It requires an orderly transition of authority over the DNS root to whatever new institution the proposal developers come up with. And, if NTIA is to ensure that the transition meets its own criteria – such as not allowing intergovernmental control, having widespread support, upholding the ‘multistakeholder model’ and maintaining the openness, stability and security of the Internet, NTIA needs to review and approve the plan submitted to it by the IANA Stewardship Transition Coordination Group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-is-considered-to-be-one-of-the-key-organisational-s</id>
      <title>Social media is considered to be one of the key organisational strengths of Isis</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/social-media-is-considered-to-be-one-of-the-key-organisational-s" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T15:53:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Guardian mentions Charles Lister&#039;s recent report, a visiting fellow at the Brookings Institute thinktank, which found social media to be one of the key organisational strengths of Isis. It used outlets such as Twitter “to spread and legitimise Islamic State’s ideology, activities, and objectives, and to recruit and acquire international support”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter closed dozens of accounts linked to Isis jihadists earlier this year. They had been used to boast of victories in Syria and Iraq and threaten US forces and post grisly images of executed hostages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-supporters-disrupt-fcc-meeting</id>
      <title>Net neutrality supporters disrupt FCC meeting</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-supporters-disrupt-fcc-meeting" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T15:57:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IT World report that approximately a dozen protestors calling on the U.S. Federal Communications Commission to pass net neutrality rules disrupted the commission’s meeting for a short time Thursday. Protestors shouting and carrying signs interrupted the beginning of the FCC’s meeting as commissioners were hearing from staff members, teachers and administrators about proposed changes to the agency’s E-Rate program, which subsidizes broadband service for schools and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/first-smartphone-drivers-license</id>
      <title>First smartphone driver’s license</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/first-smartphone-drivers-license" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:20:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iowa could be the first state to offer a smartphone driver’s license, with plans to launch a free app in 2015. According to &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/politics/2014/12/08/iowa-digital-smartphone-drivers-license/20114979/&quot;&gt;The Des Moines Register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the license will be a free option alongside a traditional license. Iowa law enforcement offers will recognize the digital license during traffic stops, and airport personnel will accept it during screenings. For security, accessing the license will require a PIN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-groups-call-for-trans-pacific-partnership-secret-t</id>
      <title>Civil society groups call for Trans-Pacific Partnership secret text to be revealed</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-groups-call-for-trans-pacific-partnership-secret-t" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:19:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) has joined dozens of civil society groups from around the world in calling for the release of the secret text of the Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP)—a massive proposed trade agreement that could quash digital rights for Internet users everywhere in the name of intellectual property protection. &quot;The TPP has been under negotiation for five years, but the only real information we have about it has been through leaks,&quot; said EFF Global Policy Analyst Maira Sutton. &quot;Those leaks show extremely troubling provisions, including expanding laws that hurt fair use and free speech along with a number of privacy-threatening enforcement proposals.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/app-for-selling-anything-to-anyone-in-complete-privacy</id>
      <title>App for selling anything to anyone in complete privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/app-for-selling-anything-to-anyone-in-complete-privacy" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:17:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Guardian describes a new app allowing users to sell anything to anyone in complete privacy has been launched, opening a new front in the fast-developing war between coders and the law. Bitmarkets, an opensource app available for download at &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://voluntary.net&quot;&gt;voluntary.net&lt;/a&gt;, is the latest in a series of technical innovations by digital activists who want to prevent surveillance over commerce and communications.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/itu-plenipotentiary-2014-access-nows-impressions-and-analysis-of</id>
      <title>ITU Plenipotentiary 2014 - Access Now&#039;s impressions and analysis of outcomes</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/itu-plenipotentiary-2014-access-nows-impressions-and-analysis-of" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:01:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;c2 c4&quot;&gt;In summary, this was a successful Plenipot conference. The participating countries reached consensus and everyone left having achieved at least some of their goals. Neither the ITU constitution nor the charter were changed, a good thing because changes may very well have expanded the ITU’s mandate into issues of Internet policy that are best dealt with by other existing institutions. In addition, the ITU gained a better understanding of the need to work with the many stakeholders within the Internet ecosystem, as well as the ways through which it can have a positive impact on some issues that fall within its mandate. Significant gains were also achieved in terms of opening up some ITU processes and access to documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;c2 c4&quot;&gt;To download the full brief detailing the outcomes of major points of discussion at the Plenipot click &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c6&quot; href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.accessnow.org%2Fpage%2F-%2Fdocs%2FPlenipot2014_Brief.pdf&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEornp6odor6YBD86rP6N12ZSYO2Q&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-is-developing-artificial-intelligence</id>
      <title>Facebook is developing artificial intelligence</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-is-developing-artificial-intelligence" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:16:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Guardian describes a new Facebook feature to protect private information. &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is developing artificial intelligence that will ask if users really want to post pictures of themselves and friends under the influence. The aim for Facebook’s “digital assistant” is that it will analyse every action by a user with the social network, beyond photos to videos and interactions, and give them more control such as notifications when other users post unauthorised photos.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-department-of-justice-thinks-companies-need-to-trust-govt-on</id>
      <title>US Department of Justice thinks companies need to trust gov&#039;t on cybersecurity</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-department-of-justice-thinks-companies-need-to-trust-govt-on" />
      <updated>2014-12-10T12:00:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US&amp;nbsp;Department of Justice (DOJ) said that the fight against cybercrime would be more effective if private companies put more trust in the country&#039;s law enforcement agencies and if they engage more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But DOJ calls for legislation to require mobile phone operating systems to include back doors in newly announced encryption tools may be a major stumbling block to additional cooperation. FBI Director James Comey raised concerns about law enforcement access to criminal evidence on smartphones after Apple and Google both announced encryption tools for their mobile operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dean Garfield, CEO of tech trade group the Information Technology Industry Council, said the tech industry will oppose efforts to pass a law requiring a back door in encryption tools. Such regulations would be &quot;incredibly disruptive in a negative way,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/darkweb-site-taken-down</id>
      <title>Darkweb site taken down</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/darkweb-site-taken-down" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:24:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FBI and Europol, took down Doxbin,&amp;nbsp;one of the darkweb’s most notorious sites where users and admins posted the names, addresses, social security numbers, healthcare histories and other personal details in a spirit of digital vigilantism – or plain malice. Although the police were able to seize the domain, it is technically trivial to re-establish control of a “seized” site. And the Doxbin’s new overlord has simply set up a new domain that agents cannot touch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Offline, one common use of data from Doxbin is to employ it in “SWATing” a target, where a victim’s phone number is spoofed and used to call in armed police. The caller claims they need urgent assistance to the related address, officers arrive with guns drawn and surprise the victim.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-demands-seizure-from-irish-server</id>
      <title>US demands seizure from Irish server</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-demands-seizure-from-irish-server" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;U.S. demands to seize emails stored on a Microsoft server in Ireland. According to the district court, the location of the data is not relevant and seeking cooperation with Irish authorities is not necessary for a warrant’s powers to reach abroad. However, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/1376674-microsoft-brief-to-appeals-court.html&quot;&gt;there is “no way” the U.S. government would accept the reasoning the district court is using&lt;/a&gt; if other countries wanted to access data stored on U.S. soil, Microsoft said in a brief filed with the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit on Monday. If the warrant is carried out it would open the door to such seizures in the U.S., endangering the privacy of U.S. citizens, Microsoft said. The Irish government asked the European Commission for legal aid in the case.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-bill-prohibits-government-mandating-backdoors-in-technolgy</id>
      <title>US bill prohibits government mandating backdoors in technolgy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-bill-prohibits-government-mandating-backdoors-in-technolgy" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:50:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, U.S. Senator Ron Wyden &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wyden.senate.gov/news/press-releases/wyden-introduces-bill-to-ban-government-mandated-backdoors-into-americans-cellphones-and-computers&quot;&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wyden.senate.gov/download/?id=B8F74B59-0A6E-45C2-A259-109978D275EA&amp;amp;download=1&quot;&gt;bill&lt;/a&gt; to prohibit the government from mandating backdoors in hardware and software technologies. The legislation prohibits any federal agency from intentionally weakening consumer encryption standards.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/qualcomm-hopes-to-cure-wi-fi-rage-with-enterprise-platform</id>
      <title>Qualcomm hopes to cure Wi-Fi rage with enterprise platform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/qualcomm-hopes-to-cure-wi-fi-rage-with-enterprise-platform" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T20:59:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Wi-Fi networks in crowded environments can be a soul-destroying experience, but next-generation access points powered by Qualcomm chipsets will use a new antenna technology to ease the pain. Wi-Fi has become a victim of its own success, leaving busy networks simply unable to handle all the laptops, smartphones and tablets we use today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem is that access points or wireless routers use short time slots to communicate with only one user at a time, and as more users get connected networks get overloaded. New antenna technology MU-MIMO (multi user-multiple-input multiple-output) will help change that by letting 802.11ac networks transmit data to many users simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-internet-of-things-economic-boom</id>
      <title>The Internet of Things may bring a new economic boom</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-internet-of-things-economic-boom" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T18:36:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IT World thinks the Internet of Things (IoT) may be more significant in reshaping the competitive landscape than the arrival of the Internet. Its productivity potential is so powerful it will deliver a new era of prosperity. That&#039;s the argument put forth by Michael Porter, an economist at the Harvard Business School and James Heppelmann, president and CEO of PTC, in a recent &lt;a target=&quot;new&quot; href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2014/11/how-smart-connected-products-are-transforming-competition&quot;&gt;Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt; essay. PTC is a product design software firm that recently acquired machine-to-machine (M2M) firm Axeda Corp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past 50 years, IT has delivered two major transformations or &quot;waves,&quot; as the authors describe it. The first came in the 1960s and 1970s, with IT-enabled process automation, computer-aided design and manufacturing resource planning. The second was the Internet and everything it delivered. The third is IoT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/switzerland-telecommunications-authority-publishes-annual-report</id>
      <title>Switzerland Telecommunications Authority publishes annual report</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/switzerland-telecommunications-authority-publishes-annual-report" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:47:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The OFCOM report sheds light on international roaming, previous and new phenomena in relation to consumer and youth protection, net neutrality, as well as the challenges in relation to fast broadband coverage which is as comprehensive as possible. The Telecommunications Report 2014 concludes that the current Telecommunications Act does not provide adequate responses to many questions and should be revised, and proposes a two-stage procedure for this. Regarding the Confederation’s majority holding in Swisscom, the report calls for this to be maintained for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/server-farm-in-sub-arctic</id>
      <title>Server farm in sub-Arctic</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/server-farm-in-sub-arctic" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T16:01:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;cnn_storypgraphtxt cnn_storypgraph11&quot;&gt;The attraction of the extreme north for many tech companies is both practical and environmental. In the tiny sub-Arctic town of Lulea, Facebook has operated &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/lule%C3%A5-data-center/lule%C3%A5-goes-live/474321655969861&quot;&gt;a 30,000 square meter server farm since 201&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/lule%C3%A5-data-center/lule%C3%A5-goes-live/474321655969861&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; -- its first such facility outside the U.S.. TeliaSonera is currently laying down &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.teliasonera.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2014/5/teliasonera-boosts-capacity-for-european-network-traffic-hub/&quot;&gt;Skanova Backbone North&lt;/a&gt;, a 1,250-kilometer (776-mile) fiber cable that will serve mobile and communications networks as well as provide the digital infrastructure that data centers in northern Sweden require. Lulea will soon host another large data facility for UK-based data-storage specialist firm, Hydro66, while the nearby town of Boden welcomed Bitcoin mining group KnCMiner earlier this year. Across the border in Finland, Google runs a similar operation in the town of Hamina.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-gives-fcc-political-cover-to-regulate-broadband</id>
      <title>Obama gives FCC political cover to regulate broadband</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/obama-gives-fcc-political-cover-to-regulate-broadband" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T15:38:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;U.S. President Barack Obama, in a strong net neutrality policy statement, has given the Federal Communications Commission the political cover it needs to move ahead with new rules by reclassifying broadband as a regulated utility.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-app-poses-a-dilemma-for-publishers</id>
      <title>Facebook app poses a dilemma for publishers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-app-poses-a-dilemma-for-publishers" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T12:17:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The social network seems to have decided to host content itself rather than send users to&amp;nbsp;other websites. What are the chances you came to this article after picking up your phone and opening the Facebook app? The probability is pretty high and its rising fast. That&#039;s bad news for most traditional publishers. Facebook can, almost single-handedly, make or break media companies: if it sends you traffic you&#039;re golden; if it takes it away, you&#039;re toast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media/2014/nov/09/facebook-app-dilemma-for-publishers-content-social-networking&quot;&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-gtld-influx-what-does-it-mean-for-the-industry</id>
      <title>The New gTLD Influx: What Does It Mean for the Industry?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-gtld-influx-what-does-it-mean-for-the-industry" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T12:26:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As new gTLD adoption steadily increases, the Internet landscape is undergoing tectonic changes. We’re now entering a phase in which new gTLD adoption by consumers is starting to disrupt established business models.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/web-statistics-ignore-users-in-developing-countries-study-shows-1</id>
      <title>Web statistics ignore users in developing countries, study shows</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/web-statistics-ignore-users-in-developing-countries-study-shows-1" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T12:51:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Up to a billion people using the internet in developing countries are ignored by web statistics, which focus on US-based servers and ignore mobile-only users and shared devices, says a new study. The result is a form of digital imperialism, says a new study by Global Web Index (GWI), a digital measurement company which provides information to a wide range of some of the webs largest advertisers and brands such as Twitter. Because those users either don&#039;t show up, or are believed to be in mature economies, they aren&#039;t targeted for advertising - or the brand-building that is important to establish companies.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-will-internet-governance-change-after-the-itu-conference-1</id>
      <title>How will internet governance change after the ITU conference?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-will-internet-governance-change-after-the-itu-conference-1" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T13:02:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is the United Nations trying to take over the internet? Read anything in much of the western media about the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) and you might think so, especially in the lead-up to the International Telecommunication Union&#039;s (ITU) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itu.int/en/plenipotentiary/2014/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;Plenipotentiary Conference 2014&lt;/a&gt; just wrapping up in Busan, Korea.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-will-the-internet-governance-change-after-the-itu-conference</id>
      <title>How will the Internet Governance change after the ITU conference?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-will-the-internet-governance-change-after-the-itu-conference" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T15:19:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the role of&amp;nbsp;International Telecommunication Union (ITU) in Internet Governance and summarizes the discussions during the ITU&#039;s Plenipotentiary Conference 2014 in Busan, Korea.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/demand-the-fcc-enact-real-net-neutrality-join-one-of-the-emergen</id>
      <title>Demand the FCC Enact Real Net Neutrality, Join One of the Emergency Protests Happening Today Across the Country</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/demand-the-fcc-enact-real-net-neutrality-join-one-of-the-emergen" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T13:19:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, across the United States, Internet users are gathering for an emergency vigil calling on the FCC to protect the open Internet. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/01/technology/fcc-considering-hybrid-regulatory-approach-to-net-neutrality.html&quot;&gt;news reports&lt;/a&gt;, the FCC is leaning towards a proposal that would protect the relationship between ISPs and big web companies, but not the relationship between ISPs and users. This “hybrid” approachwould leave the door open for all kinds of discriminatory practices against end-users and is less &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2014/11/01/the-reported-fcc-hybrid-plan-for-net-neutrality-is-not-winning-many-fans/&quot;&gt;likely to hold up in court&lt;/a&gt; than the clean proposal we’ve been supporting. Even rules that sound good aren’t going to help anyone if they wind up being struck down. And it doesn’t even make sense to differentiate between users who are “subscribers” and users who run websites; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2014/10/31/does-the-fcc-really-not-get-it-about-the-internet/&quot;&gt;all users send and receive information&lt;/a&gt; online and any “subscriber” could start a website tomorrow. At best, such a distinction is factually incoherent, and at worst it could become a self-fulfilling prophecy, legally assigning “subscriber” and “provider” roles to people and companies on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-top-level-domain-swiss-available-in-2015</id>
      <title>The top-level domain .swiss available in 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-top-level-domain-swiss-available-in-2015" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:45:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OFCOM will assume the function of registrar for .swiss. This top-level domain will be used to promote and serve the interests of the Swiss community.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mesh-networks-and-firechat-make-switching-off-the-internet-that</id>
      <title>Mesh networks and Firechat make ‘switching off the internet’ that much harder</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mesh-networks-and-firechat-make-switching-off-the-internet-that" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T15:25:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The events in Hong Kong have seen technology play a huge role in organising political protest, as much as in the days of the Arab Spring of 2011. But governments have become wise to the potential influence of Twitter, Facebook and Instagram, and blocking websites is easy (if you’re the government). This article explains peer-to-peer networking and describes how Firechat works.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/in-the-webs-hidden-darknet-criminal-enterprise-is-thriving</id>
      <title>In the web&#039;s hidden darknet, criminal enterprise is thriving</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/in-the-webs-hidden-darknet-criminal-enterprise-is-thriving" />
      <updated>2014-10-08T12:05:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Europol’s recent Internet Organised Crime Threat Assessment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europol.europa.eu/content/internet-organised-crime-threat-assesment-iocta&quot;&gt;iOCTA&lt;/a&gt;) report reveals how entire criminal enterprises have developed around using the internet to hawk criminal services to anyone with the cash.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/does-icann-violate-human-rights-the-council-of-europe-report</id>
      <title>Does ICANN violate Human Rights? The Council of Europe report</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/does-icann-violate-human-rights-the-council-of-europe-report" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T16:50:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe has released an important report on how human rights apply to ICANN. The findings? Not only do ICANN policies intersect in important ways with free expression and privacy rights, but many ICANN policies and procedures are obviously inconsistent with those rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-governance-forum-and-internet-ungovernance-forum</id>
      <title>Internet Governance Forum and Internet Ungovernance Forum</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-governance-forum-and-internet-ungovernance-forum" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T15:59:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The ninth Internet Governance Forum (IGF) was held in Istanbul, Turkey, on 2-5 September. Alternative Informatics Association (AIA) submitted&amp;nbsp;four proposals to&amp;nbsp;the IGF, but all of them were rejected. As a result, AIA decided to organise a parallel event, the Internet Ungovernance Forum (IUF). The IUF attracted considerable interest among Internet researchers and activists who wished to address urgent issues, such as censorship and surveillance, in a more inclusive manner.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
