<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/CZ/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in CZ</title>
  <updated>2017-04-21T22:05:46+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-is-closer-to-blocking-of-gambling-websites</id>
      <title>Czech Republic is closer to blocking of gambling websites</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-is-closer-to-blocking-of-gambling-websites" />
      <updated>2017-04-21T22:05:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new bill that allows blocking gambling websites without a licence in the Czech Republic has been passed through the Czech Chamber of Deputies. The bill is in now the Senate who can suggest changes but these can be overridden by the Chamber of Deputies. Besides traditional reasoning of regulation’s opponents, the bill is controversial because the black list of websites will be created and maintained by decision of the Ministry of finance and not by the order of court.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czechs-reluctant-to-implement-idn</id>
      <title>Czechs reluctant to implement IDN</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czechs-reluctant-to-implement-idn" />
      <updated>2015-06-03T00:09:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Czech .CZ domain administrator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nic.cz/&quot;&gt;CZ.NIC Association&lt;/a&gt; undertakes biannual surveys at the domain holders (individuals as well as companies) in which the respondents are asked whether they wish to implement IDN (Internationalized domain name) within the .CZ domain. CZ.NIC is ready from a technical point of view for the implementation of IDN; however, it has not implemented IDN in .CZ domains yet since the Internet user community in the Czech Republic (individuals as well as organizations) did not show much interest in the implementation of IDN.&amp;nbsp; If the IDN was deployed, the web addresses within the .CZ domain could contain Czech letters with diacritic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The regular biannual survey started in 2004. The support of IDN implementation has been continually dropping from 45 % to 32 % (in 2014) in case of individuals while the support from companies has been slightly growing. However, it is still significantly poor - with less than 20 % (in 2014) in favour of IDN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See whole article with survey results and possible impact issues &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.háčkyčárky.cz&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (the only Czech IDN domain in use).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-agenda-should-be-dealt-by-one-agency-advises-the-nationa</id>
      <title>Digital agenda should be dealt by one agency, advises the National Convent to the Czech Government</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-agenda-should-be-dealt-by-one-agency-advises-the-nationa" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T18:53:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 28 May, the Czech National Convent on the European Union made several recommendations for the area of the European Digital Agenda. Among others, the National Convent recommended to dedicate Digital Agenda policy to only one agency, to remove obstacles to cross-border online trade as quickly as possible, to adhere to the principle of digital by default, and to have open-source software requirement as a standard component of tenders. The recommendations and background paper are available in English at the end of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.narodnikonvent.eu/1077/doporuceni-5/&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-ttip-agreement-negotiations</id>
      <title>Czech Republic: TTIP agreement negotiations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-ttip-agreement-negotiations" />
      <updated>2015-03-25T14:22:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although there have been more than seven rounds of negotiations between EU, USA and Canada, the position of the Czech Government is somewhat uncertain. Based on several announcements and notes from government officials, the position seems to be rather positive. However, an official platform for discussion or information campaign has yet to be established. So far the Czech Ministry of Industry and Trade, which is responsible for this agenda, issued only a few news announcements informing about achieved results. The ministry only passively seeks for invitation to any debates regarding both agreements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this perspective a Czech NGO Iuridicum Remedium joined the European STOP TTIP initiative. Iuridicum Remedium addresses issues of blanket infringements on individual rights in the fields of Social Exclusion; Human Rights and Technologies; and Human Rights and Public Administration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Czech Stop TTIP initiative can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vttip.cz/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Basic information about TTIP agreements can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinfo.cz/cs/clanky/transatlanticka-dohoda-o-obchodu-a-investicich-mezi-eu-a-usa-ttip-41079.html#!&amp;amp;chapter=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-czech-government-adopted-the-national-strategy-for-cyber-sec</id>
      <title>The Czech government adopted the National Strategy for Cyber Security for the next five years</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-czech-government-adopted-the-national-strategy-for-cyber-sec" />
      <updated>2015-02-24T23:56:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This strategy closely follows a promulgation of the Cybersecurity Act (181/2014) and builds upon the original strategy for cybersecurity, which was intended for the period 2012 to 2015. The new strategy for 2015-2020 aims at active international cooperation, protection of national critical information infrastructure and important information systems, cooperation with private sector, support of research and education, active participation on creation and implementation of European and international regulation. Specific details will be elaborated in an action plan to be introduced by the Czech National Cyber Security Centre in the second quarter of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-a-new-law-on-cyber-security-came-into-force</id>
      <title>Czech Republic: A new law on cybersecurity came into force</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-a-new-law-on-cyber-security-came-into-force" />
      <updated>2015-03-25T14:08:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Act 181/2014 on cybersecurity came into force on the 1st of January 2015. The law&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;aims at making the country more resilient against cyber threats and attacks on important ICT infrastructures. The system for ensuring cyber security consists of: security measures, reporting of cyber security incidents, preparation of countermeasures, reporting of contact details and monitoring activities of supervising authorities. Both the law and related regulation define critical information infrastructures and important information systems. Operators of such infrastructures and systems, who can be either government as well as private organisations, must now comply with sets of rules and obligations. The law also introduces the term of “state of cyber emergency”.&amp;nbsp; The main control function will be performed by the Czech National Security Authority via Government CERT, which was established in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
