<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/IT/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in IT</title>
  <updated>2016-10-31T15:33:16+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-the-end-of-the-monopoly-of-siae</id>
      <title>Towards the end of the monopoly of SIAE?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-the-end-of-the-monopoly-of-siae" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:43:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Between May and June 2016 two important Italian singers – Fedez and Gigi D’Alessio - expressed their will to abandon the SIAE – Società Italiana Autori ed Editori (Italian Society of Authors and Publishers) and to protect their IPR rights by Soundreef. One of the main reasons for their choice is the lack of transparency in the mechanisms of attribution to each author of his/her rights, while in the field of audio and video, the new technologies could allow each author to monitor the use and the reproduction of their own music, songs and products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The debate following the publication of the decision of these two singers stressed the need to reduce the monopoly of brokerage that SIAE holds in the field of IPR and to strengthen free market and competition. In the debate the need for Italy to adopt the EU Directive 2014/26/UE on the collective management of IPR was also stressed. In this regard, one expert, Prof. Scorza, proposed to have a public body able to guarantee the protection of IPR rights and to establish an online registry of IPR, with information for each author of the brokering agency chosen, the contract signed, etc. For the Italian Antitrust Authority, the adoption of the Directive might represent an occasion to open the IPR Italian market of brokering agencies, and to allow the freedom of choice for the authors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agendadigitale.eu/smart-cities-communities/che-cosa-insegna-gigi-d-alessio-sul-futuro-del-copyright-per-l-agenda-paese_2276.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/operation-against-ipr-violation-promoted-by-fieg</id>
      <title>Operation against IPR violation promoted by FIEG</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/operation-against-ipr-violation-promoted-by-fieg" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T15:33:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On March 30, 2016, the FIEG Federazione Italiana Editori Giornali (Italian Federation of Newspaper Publishers), in accordance with the AGCOM rule, obtained the removal of 30.000 daily publications and newspapers illegally available at http://www.emerotecaonline.it. The owner of the website agreed and removed the illegal content.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-guardia-di-finanza-blocked-87-pirate-websites</id>
      <title>The Guardia di Finanza blocked 87 pirate websites</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-guardia-di-finanza-blocked-87-pirate-websites" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T15:25:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On May 26, the Guardia di Finance (Italian finance police) seized 87 web sites unlawfully transmitting and disseminating proprietary content owned by the pay-TVs of Sky and Mediaset. It is one of the biggest operations of such kind. Charges have been pressed against 145 individuals and 7 societies as buyers of the contents protected by IPR (article 171ter – comma 2 Italian IPR Law).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/an-ongoing-debate-on-digital-ipr-protection</id>
      <title>An ongoing debate on Digital IPR protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/an-ongoing-debate-on-digital-ipr-protection" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T15:28:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is an ongoing debate on how the Law is dealing with the issue of IPR protection in the digital world. One emerging issue concerns the need to involve the internet provider in the activities against piracy and in the fight against IPR violation. An example is the judgement of January 13, 2016 passed by the Sezione Specializzata Impresa del Tribunale di Milano (Specialised Enterprise Section of the Court of Milan), by which the Court orders to the internet provider to block the access to Rojadirecta web site. Other judgements calling for an involvement of internet providers, have been passed by the relevant Sections of the Court of Milan, as well as by the Court of Turin.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sentence-of-the-court-of-rome-about-ipr-of-a-photo-on-facebook</id>
      <title>Sentence of the Court of Rome about IPR of a photo on Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sentence-of-the-court-of-rome-about-ipr-of-a-photo-on-facebook" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:48:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The IX Session of the Court of Rome made a decision condemning a newspaper, which had published a photo taken from Facebook, without recognizing the property rights of the photo author. The Court established that a person, who publishes photos on his/her Facebook page retains his/her property right on such photos.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/one-year-of-ipr-regulation-in-italy-report</id>
      <title>One year of IPR regulation in Italy report</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/one-year-of-ipr-regulation-in-italy-report" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:46:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On March 31, 2015, the Italian Authority AGCOM published the results of one year implementation of the IPR regulation: 209 requests received, of which 207 concerning web sites and 2 concerning the audiovisual media. The AGCM processed 134 dossiers: 57% in ordinary procedures and 43% in urgent procedure (requiring a decision within 12 working days). 42% of the requests concerned audiovisual products; 23% photographs;14% audio products; and 12% editorial works. Very few requests concerned literary works, software and videogames. About 55% of the dossiers ended with the spontaneous removal of the contested content, while 35% of the procedures regarding strong violation of the regulation ended with the DNS block. The actions against piracy carried out by Italian authorities and in particular by the Guardia di Finanza allowed to block the activities of 15 illegal platforms in the sector of music industry. On April 29, 19 online kiosks have been closed by the Guardia di Finanza, in the framework of the operation “Black Press Review”.&amp;nbsp; According to the AGCOM these data show the efficacy of the IPR regulation. A contrary view is expressed by some lawyers, who argue that IPR regulation is lacking efficacy, since the blocked websites are likely to be soon replaced by new ones, and voices believe that the AGCOM regulation is de-facto encouraging piracy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/landmark-copyright-case-starts-in-italy-before-constitutional-co</id>
      <title>Landmark copyright case starts in Italy before Constitutional Court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/landmark-copyright-case-starts-in-italy-before-constitutional-co" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T16:23:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 11 of February 2015, Italian Constitutional Court starting to review the landmark case regarding the constitutionality of the Italian Communication Authority’s (‘AGCOM’) Regulation on Online Copyright Enforcement. AGCOM granted itself copyright enforcement power without any previous Parliamentary debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consumer’s and small business associations (Altroconsumo, Movimento di difesa del Cittadino, Assoprovider&amp;nbsp;and Assintel) filed action against this Regulation for violation of civil&amp;nbsp;and fundamental rights (freedom of expression and to be informed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;and economic initiative), protected by the Italian Constitution, before the Regional Administrative Court of Lazio and then before Constitutional Court.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republic-of-san-marino-requires-national-taxes-on-iprs</id>
      <title>Republic of San Marino requires national taxes on IPRs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/republic-of-san-marino-requires-national-taxes-on-iprs" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:10:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The owners of European patents and international trademarks that want to protect their inventions or trademarks in the Republic of San Marino are required to pay national taxes in San Marino and can not longer avail themselves of the reciprocity of recognition on trademarks, patents and designs sanctioned by art. 43 of the Convention San Marino-Italy of 1939.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All applicants originating from countries other than Italy, that require industrial property rights through the international systems (WIPO and EPO), are required to make a deposit in each of the two countries, by paying the taxes both in San Marino and in Italy, in consistency with what is happening in all the member states of the relevant international conventions and in compliance with the principle of territoriality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
