<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/DE/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in DE</title>
  <updated>2018-02-28T13:04:27+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-fighting-the-anti-whistleblower-provision</id>
      <title>Germany: Fighting the anti-whistleblower provision</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-fighting-the-anti-whistleblower-provision" />
      <updated>2017-01-25T20:33:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gesellschaft für Freiheitsrechte’s most recent Constitutional Court case in Germany concerns an anti-whistleblowing provision threatening the freedom of the press. Part-time journalists and bloggers, as well as the legal or IT experts on which journalists rely, now risk a prison sentence of up to three years for handling “leaked” data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-network-agency-prohibits-parts-of-telekoms-streamon-serv</id>
      <title>Federal Network Agency prohibits parts of Telekom’s “StreamOn” service</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-network-agency-prohibits-parts-of-telekoms-streamon-serv" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T13:04:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The German Federal Network Agency forbid certain aspects of the optional service “StreamOn” for their mobile phone contracts in order to enforce that consumers could make use of the “roam-like-at-home” principle. Currently, the data volume used by StreamOn in EU countries was divided from the overall volume included in the phone contract. According to the Federal Network Agency, this was violating the EU rules on roaming and net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-draft-hate-crime-legislation</id>
      <title>Germany: draft hate crime legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-draft-hate-crime-legislation" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:49:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just before the upcoming elections in September, the German government seems eager to push through legislation to rein in internet hate speech, fake news, and also legalise state hacks and police searches of computers and mobile phones against suspects of all kinds.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-companies-cant-be-judges-of-free-speech</id>
      <title>Internet companies can’t be judges of free speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-companies-cant-be-judges-of-free-speech" />
      <updated>2018-01-06T11:16:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For US Internet corporate giants, Germany has become ground zero in the global regulatory battle on how to deal with hate speech on social media platforms. Facebook’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2017-04-05/merkel-cabinet-backs-facebook-fines-to-stem-fake-news-in-germany&quot;&gt;concern&lt;/a&gt; that the draft of a new law currently currently making its way through the German legislative process “would force private companies instead of courts to decide which content is illegal in Germany” is spot on.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-network-agency-investigates-possible-violation-of-net-ne</id>
      <title>Federal Network Agency investigates possible violation of net neutrality by Vodafone</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-network-agency-investigates-possible-violation-of-net-ne" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T17:43:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vodafone announced to throttle the bandwidth for certain websites (e.g. one-click-hoster such as uploaded.net or mega.nz) if an overload of the network is happening. According to Vodafone, browsing the web or using social media platforms would take the priority in this case. Whether this might be a violation to the net neutrality rules is subject to an investigation through the Federal Network Agency.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-regulation-enhancing-transparency-for-information-about-inte</id>
      <title>New regulation enhancing transparency for information about internet connections</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-regulation-enhancing-transparency-for-information-about-inte" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T17:45:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new regulation passed by the “Bundestag” enforces internet access providers to provide customers with information about the expected bandwidth of an internet connection before a contract is signed. This information shall include the minimum and maximum bandwidth, as well as the expected average. Internet Access Providers are also obliged to inform customers about the actual bandwidth available once the connection is available.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/revenge-porn-to-be-criminalised-in-western-australia-domestic-vi</id>
      <title>Revenge porn to be criminalised in Western Australia domestic violence law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/revenge-porn-to-be-criminalised-in-western-australia-domestic-vi" />
      <updated>2016-09-11T14:10:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Western Australian government aims to criminalise cyber-stalking and revenge porn with new family violence legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the proposed laws, anyone who cyber-stalks or posts revenge porn online to blackmail or humiliate their current or former partner could face a two-year jail term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-for-adjusting-the-telecommunications-act-telekommunika</id>
      <title>Draft law for adjusting the Telecommunications Act (Telekommunikationsgesetz)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-for-adjusting-the-telecommunications-act-telekommunika" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T16:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 12 August 2016, the federal government proposed legislation for a law adjusting the Telecommunications Act in the “Bundesrat”. The draft law seeks to implement regulation (EU) 2015/2120 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 25 November 2015 laying down measures concerning open internet access and amending Directive 2002/22/EC on universal service and users’ rights relating to electronic communications networks and services and Regulation (EU) No 531/2012 on roaming on public mobile communications networks within the Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-police-launch-mass-raids-over-online-hate-speech</id>
      <title>German police launch mass raids over online hate speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-police-launch-mass-raids-over-online-hate-speech" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:07:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;German police on Wednesday launched nationwide raids targeting social media users who posted racial hatred on Facebook and other online networks. No arrests were made but computer equipment, cameras and smartphones were seized in the first-ever such mass raids targeting online hate crime.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-on-digital-trespassing-proposed-in-bundesrat</id>
      <title>Draft law on digital trespassing proposed in “Bundesrat”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-on-digital-trespassing-proposed-in-bundesrat" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T15:50:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 17 June 2016, the federated state Hessen proposed legislation for digital trespassing in the “Bundesrat”. The new provision shall be included in the criminal code and define the unlawful usage of IT-systems as an offence.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-and-us-intelligence-agencies-resume-collaboration</id>
      <title>German and US intelligence agencies resume collaboration</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-and-us-intelligence-agencies-resume-collaboration" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T19:50:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Germany&#039;s BND intelligence agency has resumed joint internet surveillance with the U.S. National Security Agency (NSA) after halting collaboration with Washington last year following a row over spying practices, German media reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;German newspapers on Friday said that collaborations at the Bad Aibling station have been resumed and the NSA is again being supplied with intelligence by the BND. The station is considered central to surveillant crisis countries in the Middle East, such as Afghanistan, Syria, Iraq and Libya, the papers said.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-spying-on-german-intelligence</id>
      <title>NSA spying on German intelligence</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nsa-spying-on-german-intelligence" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T13:44:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fresh insight shows that the NSA intercepted internal German communications about the kidnapping incident in Yemen. In a list of reports from wiretapped telephone conversations and emails, NSA analysts marked a section of text with the keywords &quot;Germany-Yemen/hostages.&quot; The text read: &quot;German BKA reports Western hostages in Yemen are alive, Yemeni officials delay releasing information, 12 July 2009.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-supports-new-bill-removing-liability-for-wifi-providers</id>
      <title>Germany supports new bill removing liability for WiFi providers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-supports-new-bill-removing-liability-for-wifi-providers" />
      <updated>2015-09-18T16:05:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A government&#039;s &lt;a itemscope=&quot;itemscope&quot; itemprop=&quot;StoryLink&quot; title=&quot;Link to Website&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.bundesregierung.de/Content/DE/Artikel/2015/09/2015-09-16-telemediengesetz.html&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; announced on Wednesday that Merkel’s cabinet supports a new bill that would remove the liability for WiFi providers. Under the bill, providers won’t be held liable as long as they secure the network&amp;nbsp;properly and get users to agree not to act illegally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-intelligence-agency-halts-internet-monitoring-for-nsa-new</id>
      <title>German intelligence agency halts Internet monitoring for NSA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-intelligence-agency-halts-internet-monitoring-for-nsa-new" />
      <updated>2015-05-08T12:44:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to press reports, the German intelligence service BND ended Internet monitoring for the US National Security Agency at the start of the week. Only information from faxes and phone calls is still being sent on.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-intelligence-agency-bnd-is-tapping-internet-exchange-poin</id>
      <title>German intelligence agency is tapping Internet Exchange Point</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-intelligence-agency-bnd-is-tapping-internet-exchange-poin" />
      <updated>2015-04-01T11:09:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since 2009 the German intelligence agency BND accesses traffic from the internet node DE-CIX in Frankfurt am Main – as a follow-up to „Operation Eikonal“ at the German company „Deutsche Telekom“. This was stated by the operator of DE-CIX at the NSA investigation comittee of the German Bundestag. The German Chancellery intervened several times and prevented the G-10 commission and the Federal Network Agency (Bundesnetzagentur) to investigate this interception operation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/merkel-and-hollande-talk-about-avoiding-us-servers</id>
      <title>Merkel and Hollande talk about avoiding US servers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/merkel-and-hollande-talk-about-avoiding-us-servers" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T15:31:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We will talk with France about how we can maintain a high level of data protection. Above all, we will discuss which European providers we have who offer security to citizens. So that you don&#039;t have to cross the Atlantic with emails and other things, but also can build up communication networks within Europe, said Merkel.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
