<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/IT/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in IT</title>
  <updated>2018-01-13T17:38:57+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-extends-data-retention-to-six-years-1</id>
      <title>Italy extends data retention to six years</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-extends-data-retention-to-six-years-1" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T17:38:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 8 November 2017, the Italian Parliament approved a Regulation on data retention that allows telecommunication operators to save telephone and internet data for up to six years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-plans-to-extend-telecoms-data-retention-and-increase-censo</id>
      <title>Italy plans to extend telecoms data retention and increase censorship powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-plans-to-extend-telecoms-data-retention-and-increase-censo" />
      <updated>2017-10-13T14:11:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 19th July, the Chamber of Deputies of the Italian Parliament approved two amendments to existing laws. One of the amendments aims at extending telecommunications data retention to 6 years, while the other gives Agcom, the communications regulator, powers to order takedown powers and blocking of online content without judicial oversight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-meets-italys-demands-on-data-use-practices</id>
      <title>Google meets Italy&#039;s demands on data use practices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-meets-italys-demands-on-data-use-practices" />
      <updated>2016-08-08T13:37:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Italy&#039;s data privacy regulator said on Friday Alphabet Inc&#039;s Google had met its requests to change the way it treats and stores user data to bring practices into line with Italian rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, the watchdog told Google its disclosure to users on how their data was being treated was inadequate, giving it 18 months to comply fully and indicating a series of measures that needed to be carried out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move was one of several privacy challenges against the U.S. Internet giant in the European Union, highlighting the bloc&#039;s desire to ensure its citizens&#039; data is treated according to EU law, even when held in foreign jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/opinion-of-the-data-protection-authority-of-the-right-to-be-forg</id>
      <title>Opinion of the Data Protection Authority of the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/opinion-of-the-data-protection-authority-of-the-right-to-be-forg" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:30:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A person involved in serious political crimes between the end of seventies and the eighties, having served his jail detention time, asked Google to remove from the web his name linked with those facts. Google refused to do so. The person asked the intervention of the Data Protection Authority. On June 20 2016 the Authority rejected this request stressing the fact that from a public interest point of view the right to know the history is much more relevant than the right to be forgotten of the single person. During the last months the Italian Corte di Cassazione (high Court of Appeal) has clarified conditions and limits for applying the norms about to right to be forgotten, trying to find a balance between the right to identity protection and the right to information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agendadigitale.eu/competenze-digitali/diritto-all-oblio-le-condizioni-di-tutela-secondo-la-giurisprudenza_1890.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/pre-filled-tax-returns-forms-available-for-30-millions-of-people</id>
      <title>Pre-filled tax returns forms available for 30 millions of people</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/pre-filled-tax-returns-forms-available-for-30-millions-of-people" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:26:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Starting from April 15 2016, around 30 million of Italian citizens can present their tax returns using the pre-filled form set up by the National Revenue Agency. The prefilled form includes data about revenues, tax, expenditures, including health. The pre-filled form can be changed and corrected by the citizens before submitting it online before July 7. Special procedures have been taken in order to protect sensitive health data. It is the second year for the prefilled tax declaration. 700 millions of new data and information have been added in the 2016 version.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-identity-work-in-progress</id>
      <title>Digital identity: work in progress</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-identity-work-in-progress" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:20:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year 2016 the test phase of the implementation of the Public System of the Digital Identity (SPID) started. By this System all Italian citizens, enterprises and organizations will have a digital identity, allowing them to dialogue with a unique identity with the Public Administration. A campaign on the national TV is accompanying the test phase. The agreements with the three national identity providers - Poste Italiane (Italian Postal Service); Infocert and TIM – have been signed. The regulations have been corrected taking into account the requests of the Data Protection National Authority.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Municipality of Venice and that of Florence are among the municipalities involved. The test phase – started on March 15 2016 - involve also: six Italian Regional Governments – Emilia Romagna, Friuli Venezia Giulia, Liguria, Marche, Piemonte, Toscana; three important Public Administration bodies – INAIL, Agenzia delle Entrate (Agency for Taxation), INPS. All in all 401 services will be available digitally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SPID Road Map foresees that by the end of 2017 all Italian citizens will have a digital identity. One of the important issue of the spread of SPID concern the development of the digital skills and competences of citizens. Public administration bodies will have 24 months for joining the SPID system. The start of SPID was accompanied by a debate among involved stakeholders and opinion leaders on various issues. The first one is the privacy of citizens, also taking into account the fact that identity provider also provide services for thousands of users: SPID is in line with eIDAS and with the Italian Code of Privacy, but there is the concern on the absence of explicit mention of the respect of principle of aim to which the personal data are collected and stored (risks of profiling). The second one is the fact that are allowed to act as identity provider only big enterprise; the third one is about the security of data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/electronic-identity-card</id>
      <title>Electronic Identity Card</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/electronic-identity-card" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:23:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January 2016 the Italian Ministry of Interior published the guidelines tied with the legislative decree no. 78/2015 of December 23 2015, addressed to the Italian Municipalities about the issuing of the Electronic Identity Card - CIE. The information stored in the CIE for each citizen includes: finger prints, face image, tax code, consent to organ donation, address, signature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March 2016 the CIE system started in the first 130 municipalities, including Milan, Rome, Naples, Bologna, Florence. The adoption of CIE will facilitate spread and use of SPID – Public System of the Digital Identity. In this first period only the Municipalities already issuing electronic identity cards are involved. Various stakeholders expressed their concerns about relationship between CIE and SPID; the usefulness of CIE; the protection of privacy and security of SPID and in general about the issue of how to transfer the personal identification from paper or other physical supports to a digital/virtual one.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cookies-rules-come-into-force-in-italy</id>
      <title>Cookies rules come into force in Italy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cookies-rules-come-into-force-in-italy" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:28:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 2, 2015 entered into force the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/3118884&quot;&gt;general resolution of the Italian Data Protection Authority (DPA) No. 229/2014&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;Simplified arrangements to provide information and obtain consent regarding cookies&quot;, of May 2014. Due to interpretative uncertainty, on June 5, the Italian DPA, issued a &lt;a href=&quot;http://194.242.234.211/documents/10160/0/Infografica+cookie+e+privacy+-+cosa+devi+fare&quot;&gt;set of clarifications&lt;/a&gt; concerning the correct interpretation and the relevant implementation of the provisions provided. Although the DPA has tried to follow a transparent and open approach in adopting cookies rules, according to some there are significant difficulties in understanding the technical language used in the resolution and in the clarifications. As consequence, the requirements about the consent mechanism appear hard to be implemented in practice, especially by SMEs and bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available in Italian &lt;a href=&quot;https://lamiaprivacy.wordpress.com/2015/06/11/cookielaw-esame-senza-sconti-degli-ultimi-chiarimenti-del-garante/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corrierecomunicazioni.it/tlc/34079_privacy-soro-piu-controlli-sui-cookie-con-nuova-normativa.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-launches-myaccountgooglecom</id>
      <title>Google launches myaccount.google.com</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-launches-myaccountgooglecom" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:36:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;On May 2015, following a specific a request from the Italian Data Protection Authority, Google Inc. launched myaccount.google.com, a page that contains all the useful information for the users of Google services on how to protect their privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-of-things-industry-questioned-by-privacy-regulator</id>
      <title>Internet of Things industry questioned by privacy regulator</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-of-things-industry-questioned-by-privacy-regulator" />
      <updated>2015-05-12T12:02:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) is becoming exponentially reviewed by regulators. &amp;nbsp;After the report from the Italian telecom regulator (AgCom), the Italian privacy authority just launched a consultation seeking inputs from the industry on how to regulate the IoT.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/guidelines-of-the-italian-data-protection-authority-on-the-onlin</id>
      <title>Guidelines of the Italian Data Protection Authority on the online profiling and open consultation on Internet of Things</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/guidelines-of-the-italian-data-protection-authority-on-the-onlin" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:32:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;On May 6, 2015 the Italian DPA published the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/3881513&quot;&gt;Guidelines on online profiling activities&lt;/a&gt;, drafted on March 19, 2015. The Guidelines contain a definition of profiling activities and provide some indications about the management of data. On April 28, 2015 the DPA launched a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garanteprivacy.it/web/guest/home/docweb/-/docweb-display/docweb/3889962&quot;&gt;public consultation on the Internet of Things&lt;/a&gt;. The consultation will remain open for 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available in Italian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dirittiweb.it/2015/05/profilazione-online-le-linee-guida-del-garante/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diritto24.ilsole24ore.com/art/avvocatoAffari/mercatiImpresa/2015-05-07/le-linee-guida-garante-privacy-6-maggio-2015-profilazione-on-line-111611.php&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/law-against-defamation</id>
      <title>Law against defamation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/law-against-defamation" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:53:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Commission on Justice of the Chamber of Deputies is working on the Law against defamation and about telephone interception. One proposal is to introduce the obligation for blogs to publish a correction within two days in case of incorrect data. It is also under discussion the issues regarding the right to be forgotten: in case of defamation all the information published on the web have to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposal-for-new-legislation-against-terrorism-and-privacy-prote</id>
      <title>Proposal for new legislation against terrorism and privacy protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposal-for-new-legislation-against-terrorism-and-privacy-prote" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T16:20:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new piece of legislation (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gazzettaufficiale.it/eli/id/2015/02/19/15G00019/sg&quot;&gt;Decreto Legge 18 February 2015 no.7&lt;/a&gt;) concerning urgent measures against terrorism and for International missions of peace-keeping and participation building was approved by both Italian Chambers of representatives. The new text changes the previous legislation against terrorism. The new norms consider equal those who perform activities leading to a terrorist act with those who conduct the act. The text contains also norms against the use of the web for supporting terrorism and foreign fighters. It allows to carry out preventive interceptions to counteract terrorism, using special software and technologies and availing of the possibilities to obtain data and documents from foreign bodies. It foresees also the possibility to close websites disseminating pro-terrorism information and request the Police to constantly update the websites black lists. The new norms also extended the duration of retention of data on telephonic and communication traffic (in contrast with the new EU sentence on data retention). The itinerary of the approval of the new norms has been followed by comments and remarks by politicians, lawyers and scholars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available in Italian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.repubblica.it/politica/2015/03/25/news/quintarelli_antiterrorismo_privacy-110447154/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.repubblica.it/politica/2015/04/15/news/terrorismo_il_senato_vota_la_fiducia_il_decreto_e_legge-112007789/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italian-privacy-watchdog-says-to-conduct-inspections-at-google-u</id>
      <title>Italian privacy watchdog says to conduct inspections at Google U.S. offices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italian-privacy-watchdog-says-to-conduct-inspections-at-google-u" />
      <updated>2015-02-23T22:18:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;Italy&#039;s data privacy watchdog said Google Inc had agreed to it conducting inspections at its Californian headquarters, the first time a European Union regulator will make checks on the company inside U.S. territory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;Friday&#039;s announcement represents the latest privacy challenge for the company in the EU and underscores the willingness of the 28-member bloc to ensure its citizens&#039; data are treated according to EU law, even when held in foreign jurisdictions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;Google has been under investigation by several EU data protection authorities (DPAs) since it consolidated some 70 existing privacy policies into one in March 2012, combining data collected on individual users across its services, including YouTube, Gmail and social network Google+.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
