<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory</title>
  <updated>2018-07-14T21:09:49+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-fined-for-data-breaches-in-cambridge-analytica-scandal</id>
      <title>Facebook fined for data breaches in Cambridge Analytica scandal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-fined-for-data-breaches-in-cambridge-analytica-scandal" />
      <updated>2018-07-14T21:09:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Facebook is to be fined £500,000, the maximum amount possible, for its part in the Cambridge Analytica scandal, the information commissioner has announced. The fine is for two breaches of the Data Protection Act. The Information Commissioner’s Office concluded that Facebook failed to safeguard its users’ information and that it failed to be transparent about how that data was harvested by others.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/labour-bought-data-on-1m-mothers-and-their-children</id>
      <title>Labour bought data on 1m mothers and their children</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/labour-bought-data-on-1m-mothers-and-their-children" />
      <updated>2018-07-14T21:07:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The British Labour party bought data on more than 1 million new and expectant mothers and their children from a leading baby club ahead of the 2017 general election. The Information Commissioner’s Office has issued a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ico.org.uk/media/2259363/emmas-diary-noi-redacted.pdf&quot;&gt;notice of intent&lt;/a&gt; to fine Emma’s Diary £140,000 for the infraction.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-loses-right-to-be-forgotten-case-bbc-news</id>
      <title>Google loses &#039;right to be forgotten&#039; case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-loses-right-to-be-forgotten-case-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:05:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A businessman fighting for the &quot;right to be forgotten&quot; has won a UK High Court action against Google. The man, who has not been named due to reporting restrictions surrounding the case, wanted search results about a past crime he had committed removed from the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-fines-whatsapp-and-facebook-for-s</id>
      <title>Spanish Data Protection Agency fines Whatsapp and Facebook for sharing and processing personal data without consent</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-fines-whatsapp-and-facebook-for-s" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:06:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Data Protection Agency (AEPD) just published a resolution imposing fines of €300k to WhatsApp and Facebook each for exchanging, sharing and crossing personal data data without appropriate user consent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-to-require-platforms-to-filter-uploaded-content-includi</id>
      <title>EU wants to require platforms to filter uploaded content (including code)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-to-require-platforms-to-filter-uploaded-content-includi" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:08:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU is considering a copyright proposal that would require code-sharing platforms to monitor all content that users upload for potential copyright infringement (see the EU Commission’s proposed Article 13 of the Copyright Directive). The proposal is aimed at music and videos on streaming platforms, based on a theory of a “value gap” between the profits those platforms make from uploaded works and what copyright holders of some uploaded works receive. However, the way it’s written captures many other types of content, including code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/insights-about-the-first-three-years-of-the-right-to-be-forgotte</id>
      <title>Insights about the first three years of the Right To Be Forgotten requests at Google</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/insights-about-the-first-three-years-of-the-right-to-be-forgotte" />
      <updated>2018-02-27T13:36:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Blog post from Google that summarizes the key findings after two full years of application of the Right to Be Forgotten using categorised data, including practices and statistics on how Google is implementing the European Court’s decision.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/crazy-swedish-bill-makes-sharing-tv-as-bad-a-crime-as-manslaught</id>
      <title>Crazy Swedish bill makes sharing TV as bad a &quot;crime&quot; as manslaughter</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/crazy-swedish-bill-makes-sharing-tv-as-bad-a-crime-as-manslaught" />
      <updated>2018-02-23T16:25:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new bill has been tabled in Sweden that triples the maximum prison sentence for infringement of the copyright monopoly, such as using ordinary BitTorrent, to a maximum of six years in prison.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-guardia-civil-blocks-access-to-23-webs-that-provided-mov</id>
      <title>Spanish Guardia Civil blocks access to 23 webs that provided movie downloads</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-guardia-civil-blocks-access-to-23-webs-that-provided-mov" />
      <updated>2018-02-20T15:04:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spanish Guardia Civil has announced an operation to block access to up to 23 websites that provided links to contents protected by copyright, including games, music, movies and TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/test-at-amsterdam-airport-schiphol-quick-and-easy-boarding-using</id>
      <title>Test at Amsterdam Airport Schiphol: quick and easy boarding using facial recognition</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/test-at-amsterdam-airport-schiphol-quick-and-easy-boarding-using" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T14:38:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Together with the airline KLM, Amsterdam Airport Schiphol has started a trial with voluntary ‘biometric boarding’, involving boarding without having to show your boarding pass and passport. Passengers can board quickly and easily via a separate gate that identifies passengers using facial recognition. Schiphol and KLM are assessing facial recognition technology with this trial, testing the speed, reliability and user-friendliness of the system. The boarding process and passenger experience will also be evaluated. The ultimate goal is to make the boarding process as easy and quick as possible for passengers. The trial period will last at least three months.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/corporations-use-facial-recognition-for-marketing-and-profiling</id>
      <title>Corporations use facial recognition for marketing and profiling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/corporations-use-facial-recognition-for-marketing-and-profiling" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T14:35:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the Netherlands the use of facial recognition technologies for marketing and profiling purposes of customers seems to be increasing. According to the source, this is legally allowed in cases where costumers provide consent. The article highlights the mainstreaming of biometrical technologies. It is questionable if the general public agrees to the widespread use of such technologies and what the impact on societal interaction will be once the technologies have become ubiquitous.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-police-increasingly-using-facial-recognition-technology</id>
      <title>Dutch police increasingly using facial recognition technology</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-police-increasingly-using-facial-recognition-technology" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T14:30:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch police has a facial recognition database containing &quot;well over a million&quot; faces of people taken into temporary detention (and consequently in the &quot;strafrechtdatabase&quot;). According to the news source, police ran approximately one thousand suspects through it, which led to 93 hits. There are at least three humans involved in the process as safeguarding measure: one before a photograph is fed through the algorithm to look at consider aspects such as the quality of the picture. Two humans are checking the results of the automated process. Furthermore, a hit is seen as in &quot;indication&quot; of someone&#039;s identity, not as definite proof.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-apple-is-paving-the-way-to-a-cloud-dictatorship-in-china-hon</id>
      <title>How Apple is paving the way to a ‘cloud dictatorship’ in China</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-apple-is-paving-the-way-to-a-cloud-dictatorship-in-china-hon" />
      <updated>2018-02-20T11:59:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US-based global tech giant Apple Inc. is set to hand over the operation of its iCloud data center in mainland China to a local corporation called Guizhou-Cloud Big Data (GCBD) by February 28, 2018.&amp;nbsp;Once the agreement is signed, GCBD — a company solely owned by the state — would get a key that can access all iCloud user data in China, legally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-process-of-drafting-a-cybersecurity-act-commenced</id>
      <title>The process of drafting a Cybersecurity Act commenced</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-process-of-drafting-a-cybersecurity-act-commenced" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T12:07:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A consultation procedure was initiated on 15 February 2018 to discuss and gather ideas and recommendations for the future Cybersecurity Act, which will aim to transpose the NIS Directive concerning measures for a high common level of security of network and information systems across the Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epic-joins-call-for-increased-oversight-of-intelligence-agencies</id>
      <title>EPIC joins call for increased oversight of intelligence agencies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epic-joins-call-for-increased-oversight-of-intelligence-agencies" />
      <updated>2018-02-12T11:15:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EPIC and other leading open government organizations &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.openthegovernment.org/sites/default/files/Reforms%20in%20light%20of%20Nunes%20Memo%20final.pdf&quot;&gt;urged&lt;/a&gt; Congress to promote transparency and accountability of the Intelligence agencies. The groups called for the release of annual public reports, all significant opinions by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court, and an accounting on the number of Americans subject to foreign intelligence surveillance. EPIC previously &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/surveillance/fisa/Section702Backdoor-CoalitionLetter.pdf&quot;&gt;called on&lt;/a&gt; lawmakers to require federal agencies to obtain a warrant before searching information about Americans in foreign intelligence databases. Through a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/foia/nsd/702-query-report/&quot;&gt;Freedom of Information Act lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, EPIC obtained a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/foia/epic-v-NSD/EPIC-17-05-15-NSD-FOIA-20180108-Production.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; detailing the FBI&#039;s failure to follow procedures regarding the use of foreign intelligence data for a domestic criminal investigation. EPIC has also &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/testimony/EPIC-FISA-Amd-Act-Testimony-HJC.pdf&quot;&gt;testified in Congress&lt;/a&gt; on reforms to the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/surveillance/fisa/&quot;&gt;Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coalition-agreement-of-cducsu-and-spd-asks-to-consider-modern-wa</id>
      <title>Coalition agreement of CDU/CSU and SPD asks to consider modern ways of IPR utilization and ancillary copyright for press publishers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coalition-agreement-of-cducsu-and-spd-asks-to-consider-modern-wa" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T13:13:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The coalition agreement of CDU/CSU and SPD, who could form the next German government, includes some considerations on how the IPR legislation should be developed in the EU. In particular, the agreement suggests an ancillary copyright for press publishers, as well as regulations to cover modern ways of IPR utilization. However, it remains unclear which forms exactly shall be tackled. In addition, a national strategy to strengthen Open Access shall be developed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-opposition-calls-for-abolition-of-online-hate-speech-law-1</id>
      <title>German opposition calls for abolition of online hate speech law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-opposition-calls-for-abolition-of-online-hate-speech-law-1" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:13:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Germany’s opposition parties on Sunday called for the abolition of a new law that aims to rid social media of hate speech, saying it was wrong for private companies to be making decisions about whether posts are unlawful. The legislation, which came into force on Jan. 1, can impose fines of up to 50 million euros ($60.1 million) on sites that fail to remove hate speech promptly, raising fears that Twitter, Facebook and other social media platforms could block more content than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-us-cloud-act-is-a-threat-to-global-privacy</id>
      <title>New U.S. CLOUD Act is a threat to global privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-us-cloud-act-is-a-threat-to-global-privacy" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:10:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;This bill, however, would give law enforcement around the globe — though particularly in the U.S. — more access to users’ private data without sufficient privacy protections.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-constitutional-complaint-against-intelligence-agency-bnd</id>
      <title>Germany: Constitutional complaint against intelligence agency BND</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-constitutional-complaint-against-intelligence-agency-bnd" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T19:53:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EDRi observer Gesellschaft für Freiheitsrechte (GFF) has filed a constitutional complaint against surveillance by Germany’s foreign intelligence agency, the Bundesnachrichtendienst (BND). A new law that the German Parliament passed in October 2016 allows the BND to spy on foreign journalists.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-fighting-terrorism-with-closed-door-secrecy</id>
      <title>European Parliament – fighting terrorism with closed-door secrecy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-fighting-terrorism-with-closed-door-secrecy" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T19:55:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament’s Special Committee on Terrorism (TERR) was established on 6 July 2017, for a renewable twelve-month mandate. The Committee was created with the ambitious aim of addressing ostensible practical and legislative deficiencies in the fight against terrorism across the European Union and with international actors.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-bulgarian-eu-council-presidency-the-latest-assault-on-epriva</id>
      <title>The Bulgarian EU Council presidency and the latest assault on ePrivacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-bulgarian-eu-council-presidency-the-latest-assault-on-epriva" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:26:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, the Bulgarian Presidency of the Council of the European Union picked up where the Estonian Presidency left off on the ePrivacy Regulation. It issued two examinations of the last Estonian “compromise” proposal and asked national delegations for guidance on some issues. Together, the documents cover most of the key points of the text. While the Bulgarian Presidency brings clarity on some points, its questions pave the way to undermine the text – and therefore threatens the protection of citizens’ privacy, confidentiality of communications of both citizens and businesses, as well as the positions of innovative EU companies and trust in the online economy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
