<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/Global/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in Global</title>
  <updated>2018-01-11T23:17:16+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-department-of-education-open-licensing-rule-now-in-effect</id>
      <title>U.S. Department of Education Open Licensing Rule Now in Effect</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-department-of-education-open-licensing-rule-now-in-effect" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:21:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2017/01/19/2017-00910/open-licensing-requirement-for-competitive-grant-programs&quot;&gt;new open licensing rule&lt;/a&gt; has gone into effect. Starting in 2018, education resources created with Department of Education discretionary competitive grants must be openly licensed and shared with the public.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eyes-above-the-waves-the-fight-for-patent-unencumbered-media-cod</id>
      <title>The fight for patent-unencumbered media codecs is nearly won</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eyes-above-the-waves-the-fight-for-patent-unencumbered-media-cod" />
      <updated>2018-01-11T23:17:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After Apple joining the Alliance for Open Media, now all the most powerful tech companies — Google, Microsoft, Apple, Mozilla, Facebook, Amazon, Intel, AMD, ARM, Nvidia — plus some content providers like Netflix and Hulu, are on now in the Alliance to keep media codec suite AV1 patent-free.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-grants-isps-and-search-engine-blockade-of-sci-hub</id>
      <title>US court grants ISPs and search engine blockade of Sci-Hub</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-grants-isps-and-search-engine-blockade-of-sci-hub" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T20:09:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sci-Hub, often referred to as the &quot;Pirate Bay of Science&quot;, has suffered another blow in a US federal court. The American Chemical Society has won a default judgment of $4.8 million for alleged copyright infringement against the site. In addition, the publisher was granted an unprecedented injunction which requires search engines and ISPs to block the platform.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/should-robot-artists-be-given-copyright-protection</id>
      <title>Should robot artists be given copyright protection?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/should-robot-artists-be-given-copyright-protection" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:07:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short novel written by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaltrends.com/cool-tech/japanese-ai-writes-novel-passes-first-round-nationanl-literary-prize/&quot;&gt;Japanese computer program&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 reached the second round of a national literary prize. The Google-owned artificial intelligence (AI) firm, Deep Mind, has created software that can &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/09/googles-wavenet-uses-neural-nets-to-generate-eerily-convincing-speech-and-music/&quot;&gt;generate music&lt;/a&gt; by listening to recordings. Other projects have seen computers &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/article/google-artificial-intelligence-poetry&quot;&gt;write poems&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://deepdreamgenerator.com/gallery&quot;&gt;edit photographs&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2015/dec/01/beyond-the-fence-computer-generated-musical-greenham-common&quot;&gt;compose a musical&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But who owns creative works generated by artificial intelligence? This isn’t just an academic question. AI is already being used to generate works &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/790523/daddys-car-the-first-song-ever-written-by-artificial-intelligence-is-actually-pretty-good/&quot;&gt;in music&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/media/2016/apr/03/artificla-intelligence-robot-reporter-pulitzer-prize&quot;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/2014/1/12/5295980/how-ai-game-developer-angelina-could-change-the-industry&quot;&gt;and gaming&lt;/a&gt;, and these works could in theory be deemed free of copyright because they are not created by a human author.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-grants-elsevier-copyright-infringement-damages-from-sci</id>
      <title>US court grants Elsevier copyright infringement damages from Sci-Hub</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-grants-elsevier-copyright-infringement-damages-from-sci" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:11:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dutch publisher Elsevier, won a default legal judgement on 21 June, 2017 against websites that provide illicit access to tens of millions of research papers and books. A New York district court awarded Elsevier US$15 million in damages for copyright infringement by Sci-Hub, the Library of Genesis (LibGen) project and related sites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-of-justice-rules-pirate-bay-is-infringing-copyrig</id>
      <title>European court of justice rules Pirate Bay is infringing copyright</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-of-justice-rules-pirate-bay-is-infringing-copyrig" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:09:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Justice has ruled that BitTorrent site The Pirate Bay is directly infringing copyright, in a move that could lead to ISPs and governments blocking access to other torrent sites across Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/while-eu-copyright-protests-mount-the-proposals-get-even-worse</id>
      <title>While EU copyright protests mount, the proposals get even worse</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/while-eu-copyright-protests-mount-the-proposals-get-even-worse" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:09:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, EFF joined Creative Commons, Wikimedia, Mozilla, EDRi, Open Rights Group, and sixty other organizations in signing an &lt;a href=&quot;http://copybuzz.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/29May_OpenLetter_Council.pdf&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; addressed to Members of the European Parliament expressing our concerns about two key proposals for a new European &quot;Digital Single Market&quot; Directive on copyright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/10/upload-filtering-mandate-would-shred-european-copyright-safe-harbor&quot;&gt;&quot;value gap&quot; proposal&lt;/a&gt; to require Internet platforms to put in place automatic filters to prevent copyright-infringing content from being uploaded by users (Article 13) and the equally misguided &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/08/european-copyright-leak-exposes-plans-force-internet-subsidize-publishers&quot;&gt;&quot;link tax&quot; proposal&lt;/a&gt; that would give news publishers a right to compensation when snippets of the text of news articles are used to link to the original source (Article 11).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-top-court-tightens-patent-suit-rules-in-blow-to-patent-trolls-1</id>
      <title>U.S. top court tightens patent suit rules to counteract &#039;patent trolls&#039;</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-top-court-tightens-patent-suit-rules-in-blow-to-patent-trolls-1" />
      <updated>2017-05-25T13:16:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court on May 22nd, 2017 tightened rules for where patent lawsuits can be filed in a decision that may make it harder for so-called patent &quot;trolls&quot; to launch sometimes dodgy patent cases in friendly courts.&amp;nbsp;The justices ruled 8-0 that patent suits can be filed only in courts located in the jurisdiction where the targeted company is incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-web-is-at-a-crossroads-new-standard-enables-copyright-enforc</id>
      <title>New standard enables copyright enforcement violating users’ rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-web-is-at-a-crossroads-new-standard-enables-copyright-enforc" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T05:18:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Wide Web today stands at a crossroads, as its standards body, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), considers the demand of big content providers to provide them with the facility to be able to control user devices for ensuring that their content is not copied. This facility is called the Encrypted Media Extension (EME), which enables these companies to put digital rights management (DRM) into the user&#039;s browser, whether the user wants it or not, and whether such restrictions are as per the user&#039;s local national laws or not.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-court-rules-against-publicresourceorg-says-public-safety</id>
      <title>Federal court rules against Public.Resource.Org saying that private organizations can use copyright to control access to federal laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/federal-court-rules-against-publicresourceorg-says-public-safety" />
      <updated>2017-02-07T14:44:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A US federal district court has ruled against Public.Resource.Org, forbiding their practice of providing public and open access to documents that have become law through “incorporation by reference”, meaning that they are initially created through private standards organizations and later incorporated into federal law. In the views of the EFF, the district court’s decision suggests that laws can be copyrighted and put behind paywalls as long as they were first written down by someone outside of government.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/freedom-to-utilize-genetic-resources-the-nagoya-protocol-two-yea</id>
      <title>Freedom to utilize genetic resources? The Nagoya Protocol two years later</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/freedom-to-utilize-genetic-resources-the-nagoya-protocol-two-yea" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:28:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At its second anniversary, the Nagoya Protocol is ushering in an international access and benefit-sharing (ABS) system that may impact the freedom to operate with genetic resources.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/big-week-for-wipo-marrakesh-treaty-on-access-for-visually-impair</id>
      <title>WIPO Marrakesh Treaty on access for visually impaired</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/big-week-for-wipo-marrakesh-treaty-on-access-for-visually-impair" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:26:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Intellectual Property Organization treaty on copyright exceptions for print-disabled readers entered into effect on 30 September, and trading in accessible format works began immediately. This week, the treaty will be a highlight of the annual WIPO General Assemblies, and is expected to come up at the parallel UN Social Forum taking place next door.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-anti-counterfeiting-chargeback-project-paying-back-decei</id>
      <title>Canada’s anti-counterfeiting chargeback project: paying back deceived consumers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/canadas-anti-counterfeiting-chargeback-project-paying-back-decei" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:42:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2012, Project Chargeback was created as an anti-counterfeiting, anti-piracy initiative. It is having significant success in disrupting the sale of counterfeit and pirated goods over the internet and preventing their entry into the channels of commerce in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project, which is administered by the Canadian Anti-Fraud Center (CAFC), was launched in response to complaints from Canadians receiving counterfeit or questionable goods from e-commerce websites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-dismisses-movie-piracy-case-linking-ip-address-to-a-downlo</id>
      <title>Judge dismisses movie piracy case - linking IP address to a download is not enough</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-dismisses-movie-piracy-case-linking-ip-address-to-a-downlo" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:47:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In what&#039;s believed to be a first of its kind ruling, a federal court in Oregon has dismissed a direct infringement complaint against an alleged movie pirate from the outset. According to the judge, linking an IP-address to a pirated download is not enough to prove direct copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-on-tpp-and-how-it-affects-digital-rights</id>
      <title>EFF on TPP and how it affects digital rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-on-tpp-and-how-it-affects-digital-rights" />
      <updated>2016-02-05T14:33:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EFF lists the communities who were excluded from the Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP) deliberation process - such as security researchers, artists, libraries, and user rights groups -, and describes the main ways that the TPP&#039;s copyright and digital policy provisions will negatively impact them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-officials-sign-the-tpp-but-its-still-up-to-lawmakers-to-re</id>
      <title>Trade officials sign the TPP but it&#039;s still up to lawmakers to reject it</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-officials-sign-the-tpp-but-its-still-up-to-lawmakers-to-re" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:39:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top officials of countries involved in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;Trans-Pacific Partnership&lt;/a&gt; (TPP) are convening in New Zealand today to sign the final agreement. But for the TPP to actually go into force, countries need to ratify it. Each of the twelve TPP countries have differing procedures for doing this, however due to both political reasons and the terms of stipulated by the TPP, the agreement cannot go into force without the United States&#039; ratification. That&#039;s why it&#039;s so critical that people in the U.S. demand congressional accountability over this deal and &lt;a href=&quot;https://act.eff.org/action/tell-congress-to-vote-no-on-the-tpp&quot;&gt;urge their lawmakers to vote no when the TPP comes before them for approval&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/addressing-the-chilling-effect-of-patent-damages-open-policy-adv</id>
      <title>Addressing the chilling effect of patent damages</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/addressing-the-chilling-effect-of-patent-damages-open-policy-adv" />
      <updated>2016-02-02T21:46:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has joined several other tech and software companies in filing an amicus brief with the Supreme Court of the United States in the Halo and Stryker cases to urge the Court to limit the availability of treble damages.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-law-requires-asking-permission-for-fixing-a-tractor</id>
      <title>Copyright law requires asking permission for fixing a tractor</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-law-requires-asking-permission-for-fixing-a-tractor" />
      <updated>2016-02-02T21:51:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How many people does it take to fix a tractor?&amp;nbsp;When the repair involves a tractor&#039;s computer, it actually takes an army of copyright lawyers, dozens of representatives from U.S. government agencies, an official hearing, hundreds of pages of legal briefs, and nearly a year of waiting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-ruling-in-the-monkey-photo-copyright</id>
      <title>Judge ruling in the monkey photo copyright</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-ruling-in-the-monkey-photo-copyright" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:45:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A federal judge in San Francisco has ruled that a macaque monkey who took now-famous selfie photographs cannot be declared the copyright owner of the photos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US district judge William Orrick said in a tentative opinion Wednesday that while Congress and the president can extend the protection of law to animals as well as humans, there is no indication that they did so in the Copyright Act.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-china-australia-free-trade-agreement-chafta-and-what-does-it</id>
      <title>The China-Australia Free Trade Agreement (“ChAFTA”) and what does it mean for intellectual property</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-china-australia-free-trade-agreement-chafta-and-what-does-it" />
      <updated>2015-11-04T18:31:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following more than a decade of negotiations, the final text of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://The China-Australia Free Trade Agreement (“ChAFTA”) – the intellectual property chapter&quot;&gt;China-Australia Free Trade Agreement&lt;/a&gt; (the “ChAFTA”) has now been tabled in the Australian Federal Parliament and is thought to have a clear majority backing. The ChAFTA agreement is expected to be formally applicable from 1 January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, the IP-related provisions of the ChAFTA are examined and the Australian - Chinese business opportunities are being discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-invention-network-10-years-celebration</id>
      <title>Open Invention Network 10 years celebration</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-invention-network-10-years-celebration" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:29:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago this week, five public companies launched a novel, pioneering, and seldom heralded project that was one of the first patent defense alliances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The consortium, known as the Open Invention Network, is dedicated to protecting a mode of collaborative invention. Specifically, it tries to safeguard the Linux open-source software ecosystem—software that’s written collaboratively and distributed for free—from patent licensing demands and lawsuits from any aggressor.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/volkswagen-revelation-drm-open-software-and-the-internet-of-thin</id>
      <title>DRM, open software and the Internet of things - Volkswagen case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/volkswagen-revelation-drm-open-software-and-the-internet-of-thin" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:29:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We live in an increasingly software-defined world, a trend which has both good and bad aspects. The recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.epa.gov/otaq/cert/documents/vw-nov-caa-09-18-15.pdf&quot;&gt;revelation&lt;/a&gt; that Volkswagen has been selling cars that have been explicitly built to defeat emissions tests highlights one of the bad ones: software control makes the incorporation (and hiding) of antifeatures easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The article offers analyses into DRM, open software and the Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-open-letter-on-tpp-to-include-user-safeguards</id>
      <title>New open letter on TPP to include user safeguards</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-open-letter-on-tpp-to-include-user-safeguards" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T13:33:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This letter echoes a call from earlier this year when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/05/hundreds-tech-companies-congress-tpp-and-fast-track-harms-digital-innovation-and&quot;&gt;hundreds of tech companies called on the U.S. Congress to oppose the TPP and the Fast Track bill&lt;/a&gt; for doing nothing to promote fair use or other exceptions and limitations to copyright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the letter, EFF urges officials to be receptive to new changes that would mandate their countries to pass rules that bring more balance and flexibility to their copyright regimes. The letter makes clear that EFF remains very concerned about other provisions in the TPP, including its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpps-copyright-trap&quot;&gt;retroactive copyright term extension&lt;/a&gt;, its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;ban on DRM circumvention&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt;trade secret rules that could criminalize investigative journalism and whistleblowers&lt;/a&gt; who report on corporate wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This letter has been sent to trade negotiations today as they prepare to re-convene in Atlanta, Georgia to finalize the terms of the TPP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-asks-for-security-policies-from-american-companies</id>
      <title>China asks for security policies from American companies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/china-asks-for-security-policies-from-american-companies" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:52:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chinese government distributed a document to some American tech companies earlier this summer, in which it asked the companies to promise they would not harm China’s national security and would store Chinese user data within the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The letter also asks the American companies to ensure their products are “secure and controllable,” a catchphrase that industry groups said could be used to force companies to build so-called back doors — which allow third-party access to systems — provide encryption keys or even hand over source code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next week, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/09/science/china-flexes-tech-muscles-before-state-visit-with-meeting-of-industry-giants.html&quot;&gt;Beijing has also planned a tech forum&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle between China’s Internet czar, Lu Wei, and tech companies including Apple, Facebook, IBM, Google and Uber.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-copyright-owners-must-consider-fair-use-in-online-taked</id>
      <title>US court: copyright owners must consider fair use in online takedowns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-court-copyright-owners-must-consider-fair-use-in-online-taked" />
      <updated>2015-09-15T14:05:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A federal appeals court in San Francisco today affirmed that copyright holders must consider whether a use of material is fair before sending a takedown notice. The ruling came in &lt;em&gt;Lenz v. Universal&lt;/em&gt;, often called the “dancing baby” lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/agreement-between-5-main-ip-offices</id>
      <title>Agreement between 5 main IP offices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/agreement-between-5-main-ip-offices" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T17:59:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five main intellectual property offices (IP5, European Patent Office, Japanese Patent Office, Korean Intellectual Property Office, State Intellectual Property Office of P.R.C, and United States Patent and Trademark Office) held the 8th Meeting of the Heads of the Five Intellectual Property Offices on May 22, 2015 in Suzhou, China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further tasks concerning cooperation between the five offices was discussed by the heads of the five offices, and the mission of the five offices to provide better services to their customers and the public was reaffirmed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The agreement and the services provided by the cooperation of the five offices are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lexology.com/library/detail.aspx?g=cc933bc5-ef8e-4a5f-aa6d-e133bb84b0aa&amp;amp;utm_source=Lexology+Daily+Newsfeed&amp;amp;utm_medium=HTML+email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Lexology+subscriber+daily+feed&amp;amp;utm_content=Lexology+Daily+Newsfeed+2015-09-22&amp;amp;utm_term=&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-tpp-leaked-text-reveals-countries-weakening-resistance-to-co</id>
      <title>New TPP leaked text reveals Countries&#039; Weakening Resistance to Copyright Maximalist Proposals</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-tpp-leaked-text-reveals-countries-weakening-resistance-to-co" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:01:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://keionline.org/tpp/11may2015-ip-text&quot;&gt;publication of the leaked TPP document&lt;/a&gt; by Knowledge Ecology International there is more insight on the current state of play and why the most recent round of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/08/tpp-negotiators-leave-hawaii-while-conclusion-deal-still-looms&quot;&gt;negotiations in Maui fell apart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;Countries are resisting U.S. negotiators&#039; proposal to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt;distort trade secrets law&lt;/a&gt; into a weapon against hackers, journalists, and whistleblowers. There are two new proposals in this leaked text, one of which the U.S. itself supports, to allow countries to adopt a narrow safe harbor for whistleblowers in respect of information that exposes a violation of the law. But this is far from enough. The safe harbor isn&#039;t compulsory and it doesn&#039;t apply to leaks of information that are of vital public interest, but that don&#039;t expose illegality—such as the TPP text itself.&lt;p&gt;Another important area of dissent from the U.S. negotiators&#039; hard line appears in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://keionline.org/sites/default/files/Section-H-1-11-of-Enforcement-TPP-IPChapter-11May2015.pdf&quot;&gt;Enforcement section of the IP chapter&lt;/a&gt;, in which every single country is now lined up against the U.S. in favor of a remedy for victims of wrongful copyright abuse. As in previous drafts, most countries remain opposed to a worrying U.S. proposal to limit the Internet retransmission of television broadcasts without the authorization of the rights holder of the broadcast content—and, tellingly, that of the rights holder of the broadcast signal itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-issues-surrounding-iana-trademarks</id>
      <title>The issues surrounding IANA trademarks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-issues-surrounding-iana-trademarks" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:12:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest controversies surrounding the IANA stewardship transition revolves around the fate of the IANA trademark and domain name (IANA.ORG). Both of these assets are currently owned by ICANN. But the IANA stewardship transition has raised questions about who or what should be their proper home. This article explains why this matters and what would be the implications for the IANA transition.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-issues-to-be-discussed-by-wipo-committee-next-week</id>
      <title>Copyright issues to be discussed by WIPO committee next week</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-issues-to-be-discussed-by-wipo-committee-next-week" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:37:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Intellectual Property Organization committee on copyright is meeting next week with an agenda of discussions on a potential international instrument to protect broadcasting organisations’ copyrights, and at the same time exceptions and limitations to copyright for the benefit of libraries, archives, education, research, and persons with disabilities other than sight impairment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/meetings/en/details.jsp?meeting_id=35590&quot;&gt;30th session&lt;/a&gt; of the WIPO Standing Committee on Copyright and Related Rights is taking place from 29 June to 3 July 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wipo-seminar-on-shared-genetic-resources-and-traditional-knowled</id>
      <title>WIPO seminar on shared genetic resources and traditional knowledge</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wipo-seminar-on-shared-genetic-resources-and-traditional-knowled" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T20:42:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue of genetic resources or traditional knowledge that are shared among different countries was discussed at a World Intellectual Property Organization seminar this week. Panellists presented national and regional efforts to protect such resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/meetings/en/details.jsp?meeting_id=35602&quot;&gt;seminar&lt;/a&gt; took place from 23-25 June. Four panels were organised to discuss several topics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ip-watch.org/2015/06/25/wipo-seminar-looks-at-protection-of-tk-genetic-resources-across-borders/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;IPW&lt;/em&gt;, WIPO, 25 June 2015&lt;/a&gt;), one of them focusing on regional and international experiences on transboundary (shared) genetic resources (GRs), traditional knowledge (TK), and traditional cultural expressions (TCEs or folklore).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;rces.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trips-council-to-discuss-waiver-extension</id>
      <title>TRIPS Council to discuss waiver extension</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trips-council-to-discuss-waiver-extension" />
      <updated>2015-06-09T00:12:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Trade Organization committee on intellectual property and trade this week will discuss a range of issues including a request by least-developed countries to extend the time before they are required to enforce rules on IP and pharmaceuticals. Other issues include a discussion of IP and innovation, and a moratorium on complaints about government actions that do not violate WTO rules but may harm trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WTO Council for Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS) is scheduled to meet on 9-10 June.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-for-not-locking-down-public-wifi</id>
      <title>Open letter for NOT locking down public WiFi</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-for-not-locking-down-public-wifi" />
      <updated>2015-06-09T14:35:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;EFF together with a coalition of other organizations from both sides of the Atlantic have formulated an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2015/06/05/closedwifiasanobstacletolegitimatetrade-4.pdf&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; presenting their views on why a result that threatens open wireless would be a serious loss to innovators, small businesses, travellers, emergency services and users at large.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main question point in CJEU case &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?pro=&amp;amp;lgrec=en&amp;amp;nat=or&amp;amp;oqp=&amp;amp;dates=&amp;amp;lg=&amp;amp;language=en&amp;amp;jur=C%2CT%2CF&amp;amp;cit=none%252CC%252CCJ%252CR%252C2008E%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252Ctrue%252Cfalse%252Cfalse&amp;amp;num=C-484%252F14&amp;amp;td=%3BALL&amp;amp;pcs=Oor&amp;amp;avg=&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;mat=or&amp;amp;jge=&amp;amp;for=&amp;amp;cid=98207&quot;&gt;McFadden&lt;/a&gt; (C-484/14) is whether locking of open wireless networks would be a proportionate enforcement mechanism that advances the public interest. The case concerns a German shopkeeper whose free open wireless network was allegedly used to infringe copyright. In the preliminary reference to the Court of Justice of the European Union, the Europe&#039;s highest court is asked whether an enforcement practice requiring open wireless networks to be locked is an acceptable one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Germany&#039;s Federal Supreme Court in 2010 held that the private operator of a wireless network is obliged to use password protection in order to prevent abuse by third parties. If the CJEU affirms this finding, the effect could be to extend this bad precedent throughout Europe, grounding the open wireless movement across the continent. If on the other hand it rejects that finding, German law will allow thousands of hotspot operators to open up their networks again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-fiber-sends-automated-copyright-settlement-demands</id>
      <title>Google Fiber sends automated copyright settlement demands</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-fiber-sends-automated-copyright-settlement-demands" />
      <updated>2015-06-02T13:58:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google Fiber is forwarding copyright infringement notices to its subscribers including controversial and automated piracy fines. To protect customers against these practices many ISPs &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/comcast-kills-business-model-of-piracy-monitoring-and-settlement-firm-131206/&quot;&gt;including Comcast&lt;/a&gt;, Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T have chosen not to forward settlement demands.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-criticizes-newly-introduced-us-patents-act</id>
      <title>EFF criticizes newly introduced US Patents Act</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-criticizes-newly-introduced-us-patents-act" />
      <updated>2015-03-05T14:02:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The STRONG Patents Act, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coons.senate.gov/newsroom/releases/release/coons-durbin-hirono-introduce-patent-reform-bill-to-protect-innovation-confront-abuse&quot;&gt;introduced yesterday&lt;/a&gt; by Sens. Coons, Durbin, and Hirono, claims to be a &quot;reform&quot; bill—in reality, it would achieve the exact opposite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we note in our recent whitepaper, &lt;a href=&quot;https://defendinnovation.org/&quot;&gt;Defend Innovation&lt;/a&gt;, we should primarily tackle the root problem of most patent issues: the abundance of poor quality patents. Important tools exist already to challenge bad patents, and these should be strengthened and made less expensive. The STRONG Patents Act&#039;s major &quot;reform,&quot; however, cripples these means of limiting or scrapping patents that are poor quality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/congress-is-poised-to-introduce-a-bill-to-fast-track-tpp-so-its</id>
      <title>Fast track bill for TPP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/congress-is-poised-to-introduce-a-bill-to-fast-track-tpp-so-its" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T15:03:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Fast Track bill is likely going to be introduced as early as next week. Congress needs to hear from their constituents that we expect them to hold the White House accountable for the TPP&#039;s restrictive digital policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-software-vendors-please-stop-trying-to-intercept-your-custo</id>
      <title>Software vendors need to stop trying to intercept customers’ encrypted traffic</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dear-software-vendors-please-stop-trying-to-intercept-your-custo" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:57:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past week many more details have emerged about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/02/further-evidence-lenovo-breaking-https-security-its-laptops&quot;&gt;HTTPS-breaking Superfish software that Lenovo pre-installed on its laptops for several months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the security implications have gone from bad to worse the more we’ve learned. For instance, researchers have determined that the software library Superfish uses to intercept traffic—developed by a company known as Komodia—&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.facebook.com/notes/protect-the-graph/windows-ssl-interception-gone-wild/1570074729899339&quot;&gt;is present in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/Wack0/17c56b77a90073be81d3&quot;&gt;more than a dozen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://marcrogers.org/2015/02/19/will-the-madness-never-end-komodia-ssl-certificates-are-everywhere/&quot;&gt;other software products&lt;/a&gt;, including parental control software and (supposed) privacy-enhancing/ad-blocking software. All of these products have the same vulnerability that Superfish does: anyone with a little technical know-how could intercept and modify your otherwise secure HTTPS traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-highlightes-the-absurd-automated-notices-in-abuse-of-the-dmc</id>
      <title>EFF highlightes the absurd automated notices, in abuse of the DMCA takedown process</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-highlightes-the-absurd-automated-notices-in-abuse-of-the-dmc" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:34:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every month, &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/&quot;&gt;TorrentFreak&lt;/a&gt; reports on absolutely ridiculous takedown notices issued by copyright holders to Internet service providers related to allegedly infringing content, using the process created by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/dmca&quot;&gt;Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA)&lt;/a&gt;. This month, TorrentFreak &lt;a href=&quot;https://torrentfreak.com/the-worlds-most-idiotic-copyright-complaint-150222/&quot;&gt;tore apart&lt;/a&gt; a series of takedown notices sent to Google by the German-based Total Wipes Music Group targeting, among other things, an EFF webpage describing &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssd.eff.org/en/module/how-use-pgp-mac-os-x&quot;&gt;how to use PGP for Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;—a webpage within our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssd.eff.org/en&quot;&gt;Surveillance Self-Defense&lt;/a&gt; guide.&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chillingeffects.org/notices/10421509&quot;&gt;the notice that cites the EFF webpage&lt;/a&gt; as an “allegedly infringing URL” purports to protect an album called &lt;span&gt;“Cigarettes” on Spanish music label Mona Records. But &lt;i&gt;not one&lt;/i&gt; of the seven allegedly infringing URLs listed in the notice even refers to the album, let alone in an infringing way. Another &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chillingeffects.org/notices/10416081&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;notice issued by Total Wipes to Google two days earlier&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt; purports to target pirates of the album “In To The Wild – Vol.7″ on music label Aborigeno Music. Again, &lt;i&gt;not one&lt;/i&gt; of the 95 allegedly infringing URLs had anything to do with music, as TorrentFreak reported. The notice instead listed generic download pages for some of the world’s most popular online services, including Skype, Tor, Dropbox, LibreOffice, Python, and WhatsApp.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-proposed-copyright-code-of-practice-under-public-deba</id>
      <title>Australia&#039;s proposed copyright code of practice under public debate</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-proposed-copyright-code-of-practice-under-public-deba" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:38:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/12/2014-review-international-copyright-law&quot;&gt;last December&lt;/a&gt;, the Australian government has asked to develop a new code of practice on copyright that would could change the lay of the land for the Internet industry for decades to come. The code is designed to force ISPs to adopt new “reasonable measures” to deter copyright infringement—measures that the Australian High Court had earlier decided that they were under &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roadshow_Films_v_iiNet&quot;&gt;no obligation&lt;/a&gt; to adopt. The results of that process have just been released in the form of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.commsalliance.com.au/__data/assets/pdf_file/0005/47570/DR-C653-2015.pdf&quot;&gt;draft industry code&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.commsalliance.com.au/Documents/public-comment&quot;&gt;open for public comment&lt;/a&gt; until March 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-report-on-the-us-patent-system</id>
      <title>EFF report on the US patent system</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-report-on-the-us-patent-system" />
      <updated>2015-02-24T23:41:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &quot;Defend Innovation&quot; whitepaper is the culmination of two-and-a-half years worth of research, drawing from the stories, expertise, and ideas of more than 16,500 people who agree that the current patent system is broken. Split into two parts, the report covers both the challenges facing innovators under the current patent regime, as well as concrete measures that policymakers must take in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-warns-about-the-threats-of-the-trans-pacific-partnership-agr</id>
      <title>EFF warns about the threats of the Trans-Pacific Partnership agreement (TPP)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-warns-about-the-threats-of-the-trans-pacific-partnership-agr" />
      <updated>2015-02-20T13:02:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Trans-Pacific Partnership agreement (TPP) will force other TPP signatories to accept the United States&#039; excessive copyright terms of a minimum of life of the author plus 70 years, while locking the US to the same lengths so it will be harder to shorten them in the future. It contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;DRM &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;anti-circumvention provisions&lt;/a&gt; that will make it a crime to tinker with, hack, re-sell, preserve, and otherwise control any number of digital files and devices that you own. The TPP will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;encourage ISPs to monitor and police &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;their&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt; users&lt;/a&gt;, likely leading to more censorship measures such as the blockage and filtering of content online in the name of copyright enforcement. And in the most recent leak of the TPP&#039;s Intellectual Property chapter, we found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; even more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; alarming provision on trade secrets&lt;/a&gt; that could be used to crackdown on journalists and whistleblowers who report on corporate wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-supports-innovation-act-against-patent-trolls</id>
      <title>EFF supports Innovation Act against patent trolls</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-supports-innovation-act-against-patent-trolls" />
      <updated>2015-02-19T11:29:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although there was a small decline in litigation in 2014, patent trolling exploded over the past decade and remains at &lt;a href=&quot;http://unifiedpatents.com/unified-patents-2014-litigation-report/&quot;&gt;historically high levels&lt;/a&gt;. This litigation is overwhelmingly &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2014/07/the-evidence-is-in-patent-trolls-do-hurt-innovation&quot;&gt;a tax on innovation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2565292&quot;&gt;does nothing&lt;/a&gt; to promote the deployment of new technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Congress should not be misled into thinking that problems with the patent system have gone away. With trolls going strong, we still need legislative patent reform. Earlier this month, Rep. Bob Goodlatte, chairman of the House Judiciary Committee, reintroduced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/02/innovation-act-back-lets-finally-put-stop-patent-trolls&quot;&gt;Innovation Act&lt;/a&gt;. While it won’t solve all problems with the patent system, the bill includes a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cases/six-good-things-about-innovation-act&quot;&gt;number of provisions&lt;/a&gt; designed to make litigation abuse more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-comments-on-tpp</id>
      <title>EFF comments on TPP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-comments-on-tpp" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:03:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;Trans-Pacific Partnership agreement&lt;/a&gt; (TPP) poses massive threats to users in a dizzying number of ways. It will force other TPP signatories to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/02/negotiators-burn-their-last-opportunity-salvage-tpp-caving-copyright-term&quot;&gt;accept the &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2015/02/negotiators-burn-their-last-opportunity-salvage-tpp-caving-copyright-term&quot;&gt;United States&#039; excessive copyright terms&lt;/a&gt; of a minimum of life of the author plus 70 years, while locking the US to the same lengths so it will be harder to shorten them in the future. It contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;extreme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;DRM &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;anti-circumvention provisions&lt;/a&gt; that will make it a crime to tinker with, hack, re-sell, preserve, and otherwise control any number of digital files and devices that you own. The TPP will &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;encourage ISPs to monitor and police &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;their&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt; users&lt;/a&gt;, likely leading to more censorship measures such as the blockage and filtering of content online in the name of copyright enforcement. And in the most recent leak of the TPP&#039;s Intellectual Property chapter, we found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; even more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/10/cyber-espionage-and-trade-agreements-ill-fitting-and-dangerous-combination&quot;&gt; alarming provision on trade secrets&lt;/a&gt; that could be used to crackdown on journalists and whistleblowers who report on corporate wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-filed-petitions-for-the-rights-to-tinker-repair-and-remix</id>
      <title>EFF filed petitions for the rights to tinker, repair, and remix</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-filed-petitions-for-the-rights-to-tinker-repair-and-remix" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:08:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) filed petitions with the U.S. Copyright Office seeking to keep users who remix DVD content or jailbreak their devices from losing their legal safe harbors and to establish new rights for those who need to circumvent &quot;access control&quot; or &quot;digital rights management&quot; (DRM) technologies for activities such as conducting security research, repairing cars, and resuscitating old video games. The petitions were submitted as part of the complex, triennial rulemaking process that determines exemptions from Section 1201 of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA).&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-finds-fundamental-flaws-in-ustr-report-on-intellectual-prope</id>
      <title>EFF finds fundamental flaws in USTR report on intellectual property</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-finds-fundamental-flaws-in-ustr-report-on-intellectual-prope" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:07:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United States Trade Representative (USTR)—comes a lesser-known, but also insidious global &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/intellectual-property/the-term&quot;&gt;intellectual property&lt;/a&gt; gambit: the Special 301 Report. The Special 301 Report is a survey conducted under the auspices of the Trade Act and has been issued every year since 1989. The USTR assesses whether the other countries of the world have been naughty or nice in their treatment of U.S. intellectual property holders, and raps them over the knuckles if they don&#039;t come up to scruff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key points that we and our partners make in this submission is that the process for drawing up the Special 301 Report is fundamentally flawed. The Special 301 Report is unabashedly partial to the complainant—the USTR acts as its own judge, jury, and executioner.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tpp-negociations-to-extend-copyright-terms</id>
      <title>TPP negociations to extend copyright terms</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tpp-negociations-to-extend-copyright-terms" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:52:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.nhk.or.jp/nhkworld/english/news/20150203_05.html&quot;&gt;New reports indicate&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp&quot;&gt;Trans-Pacific Partnership&lt;/a&gt; (TPP) negotiators have agreed to language that would bind its 12 signatory nations to extend copyright terms to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/all-nations-lose-tpps-expansion-copyright-terms&quot;&gt;match the United States&#039; already excessive length of copyright&lt;/a&gt;. Nations including Japan, New Zealand, Malaysia, and Canada would all be required to extend their terms and grant Big Content companies lengthy exclusive rights to works for no empirical reason. This means that all of the TPP&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/05/transpacific-plague&quot;&gt;extreme&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/tpp-creates-liabilities-isps-and-put-your-rights-risk&quot;&gt;enforcement&lt;/a&gt; provisions would apply to creative works for upwards of 100 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are the terms of the proposal, revealed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/leaked-tpp-intellectual-property-chapter-aug-2013&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/leaked-tpp-intellectual-property-chapter-may-2014&quot;&gt;leaks&lt;/a&gt; of the TPP Intellectual Property chapter: If the copyright holder is an individual, the minimum copyright term would extend to the lifetime of the creator plus 70 years after her death&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt; This means restrictions could easily be in place for a century after a work is created. In the case of works with corporate authors, the term extends to 95 years from the first publication, or if not published within 25 years of its creation, 120 years from then. These terms go far beyond what is required by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/trips_e/intel2_e.htm%23copyright&quot;&gt;international&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/trips_e/intel2_e.htm%23copyright&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/trips_e/intel2_e.htm%23copyright&quot;&gt;standards&lt;/a&gt; set out in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/treaties/en/ip/berne/index.html&quot;&gt;Berne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/treaties/en/ip/berne/index.html&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/treaties/en/ip/berne/index.html&quot;&gt;Convention&lt;/a&gt; (WIPO) and the Agreement on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/trips&quot;&gt;Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights&lt;/a&gt; (TRIPS).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uber-and-boston-city-agreement-to-provide-data-for-better-planni</id>
      <title>Uber and Boston city agreement to provide data for better planning decisions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uber-and-boston-city-agreement-to-provide-data-for-better-planni" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:32:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Uber agreed to provide Boston city officials a wealth of ride data to help them make better planning decisions—but it will go to considerable lengths to ensure that data is not made public. The data, which includes anonymous pick-off and drop-off locations for each Uber ride, contains confidential commercial and financial information that prohibits the city from sharing it publicly, according to Uber’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/1513002-final-city-data-agreement-boston-uber-011215.html&quot;&gt;agreement&lt;/a&gt; with the city. While citizens are often entitled access to public records, Uber and the city agreed that the data it provided contains trade secrets, which making it exempt from public disclosure under a a section of Massachusetts Public Records Law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-comments-the-motion-picture-association-of-america-schemes-f</id>
      <title>EFF comments the Motion Picture Association of America schemes for Internet censorship</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-comments-the-motion-picture-association-of-america-schemes-f" />
      <updated>2015-03-11T21:22:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documents that were brought to light by the December 2014 Sony hack revealed the MPAA&#039;s plans to create SOPA-like Internet censorship mechanisms through agencies outside of the federal legislature in order to purposefully skirt the public oversight that comes with Congressional rule making. The first explosive revelation was that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/12/hollywood-funds-sopa-revival-through-state-officials-google-and-internet-respond&quot;&gt;MPAA had been colluding with, and even financing, state attorneys generals to go after Google&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But another set of documents revealed Hollywood&#039;s other crooked plan—to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2015/1/2/7481409/the-mpaa-has-a-new-plan-to-stop-copyright-violations-at-the-border&quot;&gt;persuade the International Trade Commission (ITC) into forcing Internet service providers to block sites&lt;/a&gt; that allegedly distribute copyright-infringing content. The ITC is a federal, quasi-judicial agency that regulates the importation of goods coming into the United States. It recently held in a patent case (which is under appeal) that its authority extends to data transmitted online. The MPAA wants to take advantage of the ITC&#039;s expansive new interpretation of its mandate to fight contraband online, and extend that to blacklist content in the name of fighting piracy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/services-for-skipping-ads-and-live-streaming-are-not-copyright-i</id>
      <title>Services for skipping ads and live streaming are not copyright infringements</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/services-for-skipping-ads-and-live-streaming-are-not-copyright-i" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:46:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A federal court in California has ruled that Dish Network did not infringe the copyright of Fox Broadcasting by offering users &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dish.com/technology/dish-anywhere/&quot;&gt;services for skipping ads and streaming live or recorded programming&lt;/a&gt; over the Internet to their computers and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinas-patent-policy</id>
      <title>China&#039;s patent policy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/chinas-patent-policy" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:04:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;China is about to engage in a form of import substitution to support local hi-tech champions, the ultimate goal being perhaps to replace foreign technology with home-grown development. An interesting report appeared on various news sites this week regarding the policy decision taken by the Chinese government to treble by the year 2020 the number of patents filed by local Chinese inventors (see for instance&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldipreview.com/news/china-seeks-to-treble-patent-filings-by-2020-7603&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;the report on WIPR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). The metric cited is that China hopes to encourage local inventors to increase the number of filed patents from four patents filed for each 10,000 persons to 14 inventions per 10,000 persons, this to be accomplished by the year 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several data points demonstrate the context of this goal. It is reported that, in 2013, more than 825,000 patents were filed at the China State Intellectual Property Office. For that same year, it is reported that 629,612 patents were published in China (according to a Thomson Reuters study of December 2014, this is 200,000 more than the patents published in the US for the same year). On a comparative basis, as reported in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/ipstats/en/wipi/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;World Intellectual Property Indicators for 2014&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 32% of the 2.57 million patents filed globally came from China.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/consumers-protection-for-e-books</id>
      <title>Consumers protection for e-books</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/consumers-protection-for-e-books" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:03:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Often DRM isn&#039;t just an infringement of your speech rights under copyright law, but more fundamentally an infringement of your rights as a consumer (you might be prevented not only from &lt;i&gt;lending&lt;/i&gt; a book, but even from &lt;i&gt;reading&lt;/i&gt; it). That&#039;s why a new wave of consumer protection laws around the world are also beginning to address the problems of DRM, by holding purveyors of digital products to the same standards as their physical counterparts. For example, since 2011, Europe has had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32011L0083&amp;amp;rid=1&quot;&gt;Consumer Rights Directive&lt;/a&gt; [PDF] that requires vendors of digital products to disclose up-front any DRM restrictions or interoperability issues, in clear and comprehensible language.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/you-cant-make-an-abstract-idea-patentable-by-simply-adding-do-it</id>
      <title>You can’t make an abstract idea patentable by simply adding “do it on a computer”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/you-cant-make-an-abstract-idea-patentable-by-simply-adding-do-it" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:05:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Late last month, Judge Otis Wright of the Central District of California invalidated five claims in one of MyMedicalRecords’ patents in a case involving Walgreens, Quest Diagnostics, WebMD, and more. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/files/2015/01/07/mmrf_466_judgement.pdf&quot;&gt;Wright’s decision [PDF]&lt;/a&gt; is one of many new cases that have implemented the Supreme Court’s recent ruling in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2014/06/bad-day-bad-patents-supreme-court-unanimously-strikes-down-abstract-software&quot;&gt;Alice v. CLS Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a groundbreaking decision that basically says: you can’t make an abstract idea patentable by simply adding “do it on a computer.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ford-claims-copyright-on-list-of-spare-parts</id>
      <title>Ford claims copyright on list of spare parts</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ford-claims-copyright-on-list-of-spare-parts" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:06:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ford Motor Company recently sued Autel, a manufacturer of third-party diagnostics for automobiles, for creating a diagnostic tool that includes a list of Ford car parts and their specifications. Ford claims that it owns a copyright on this list of parts, the &quot;FFData file,&quot; and thus can keep competitors from including it in their diagnostic tools. It also claims that Autel violated the anti-circumvention provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act by writing a program to defeat the &quot;encryption technology and obfuscation&quot; that Ford used to make the file difficult to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-copyright-reform</id>
      <title>Australia&#039;s copyright reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australias-copyright-reform" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:27:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Over the past several weeks, there have been several developments concerning Australia&#039;s recently-proposed online copyright&amp;nbsp;enforcement reforms. Particularly, the Australian government is in the process of adopting reforms that would allow&amp;nbsp;owners of copyright-protected works and other authorized parties (collectively, &quot;Rights Holders&quot;) to petition Australian Courts for an injunctive order to directly block foreign-hosted websites from accessing Australia. Although these proposed measures will arguably provide Rights Holders greater means to enforce rights in their works across borders, they pose a number of potentially problematic issues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-to-challenge-podcasting-patent-before-uspto</id>
      <title>EFF to Challenge Podcasting Patent Before USPTO</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-to-challenge-podcasting-patent-before-uspto" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:13:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;EFF will have a public hearing at the US Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) in an attempt to invalidate key claims of a patent used by Personal Audio to shake down podcasters. Personal Audio claims it owns a patent that covers podcasting, despite the fact that many examples of what we now call podcasting existed before the patent was issued. Personal Audio is known as a &quot;non-practicing entity&quot;—a company that doesn&#039;t do podcasting itself but instead bases its business model on demanding license fees from actual creators, from garage podcasters to major broadcasters.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sony-pictures-was-hacked</id>
      <title>Sony Pictures was hacked</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sony-pictures-was-hacked" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:14:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;Journalist Martyn Williams writes that more of Sony Picture&#039;s corporate secrets appears to have been put on the Internet over the weekend. Sony Pictures was hacked in late November and has had to endure two weeks of embarrassing leaks of corporate information onto the Internet.&lt;p&gt;The major Hollywood movie studio first saw several unreleased movies uploaded then salary information about its employees. Leaks have also included medical information about employees, financial data, contracts for TV shows and, last week, the Outlook email boxes of two senior executives. Those email leaks revealed embarassing message exchanges with executives at Sony and other Hollywood studios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-amicus-curiae-on-copyright-case-on-performances</id>
      <title>EFF amicus curiae on copyright case on performances</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eff-amicus-curiae-on-copyright-case-on-performances" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:21:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/cases/garcia-v-google-inc&quot;&gt;Garcia v. Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; is a copyright case arising from the &quot;Innocence of Muslims&quot; video that was associated with violent protests around the world. The appellant, Cindy Lee Garcia, argues that she holds a copyright in her five-second performance in the video, and that the video uses that performance without permission. EFF and many other public interest groups have filed friend-of-the-court briefs in the case, noting (among other concerns) that it is a matter of firmly established law that actors generally do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; have a copyright in their performances.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/telling-users-how-to-strip-the-drm-from-their-ebooks-is-not-copy</id>
      <title>US court: Telling users how to strip the DRM from their ebooks is not copyright infringement</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/telling-users-how-to-strip-the-drm-from-their-ebooks-is-not-copy" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:17:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EFF&#039;s article says that telling users how to strip the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/drm&quot;&gt;DRM&lt;/a&gt; from their legally purchased ebooks is not contributory copyright infringement, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/abbey-house-media-v-apple-inc&quot;&gt;a ruling last month&lt;/a&gt; by a federal judge in New York. Judge Denise Cote dismissed two publishers&#039; claims of contributory infringement and inducement in &lt;i&gt;Abbey House Media v. Apple Inc&lt;/i&gt;., one of the many cases to come out of the antitrust litigation against Apple and a handful of major publishers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-will-amend-copyright-laws-to-block-overseas-file-shari</id>
      <title>Australia will amend copyright laws to block overseas file sharing sites</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/australia-will-amend-copyright-laws-to-block-overseas-file-shari" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:23:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Australia will amend copyright laws to allow courts to order the blocking of overseas websites used for illegal downloads and streaming. The government has given internet service providers (ISPs) and copyright holders a four-month deadline to develop a new industry code which should canvass a “fair” sharing of the cost of notifying and educating customers about infringement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-report-most-companies-have-no-control-over-sensitive-data</id>
      <title>US Report: Most companies have no control over sensitive data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-report-most-companies-have-no-control-over-sensitive-data" />
      <updated>2014-12-10T12:06:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The majority of businesses don&#039;t have a solid system for tracking sensitive data, or a mature patch management process, according to new survey of IT professionals released by Trustwave. &quot;If you don&#039;t know where your data is -- your sensitive data, your critical data, data that you use to operate your business -- then how can you protect it?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-deleted-music-from-users-ipods-purchased-from-rivals</id>
      <title>Apple deleted music from users’ iPods purchased from rivals</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-deleted-music-from-users-ipods-purchased-from-rivals" />
      <updated>2014-12-13T19:59:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Users who tried to sync and update an iPod with music from the likes of Amazon or 7Digital were told there was an error with their iPod that could only be solved with a factory restore through iTunes, which completely wiped the &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/ipod&quot;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;qghusdrksveqlrkgntbx ctbqapppypxfxsagyeyc&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;qghusdrksveqlrkgntbx ctbqapppypxfxsagyeyc&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;qghusdrksveqlrkgntbx ctbqapppypxfxsagyeyc&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;qghusdrksveqlrkgntbx ctbqapppypxfxsagyeyc&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612434761/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411d3dfa/sc/15/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-law-as-a-tool-for-state-censorship-of-the-internet</id>
      <title>Copyright Law as a Tool for State Censorship of the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-law-as-a-tool-for-state-censorship-of-the-internet" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T21:08:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When state officials seek to censor online speech, they&#039;re going to use the quickest and easiest method available. For many, copyright takedown notices do the trick. After years of lobbying and increasing pressure from content industries on policymakers and tech companies, sending copyright notices to take media offline is easier than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The copyright law that state actors most often invoke is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/dmca&quot;&gt;Digital Mille&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/dmca&quot;&gt;n&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/dmca&quot;&gt;nium Copyright Act&lt;/a&gt; (DMCA). The DMCA was the first major digital copyright law passed in the United States, creating strict procedural rules for how and when a copyright holder can claim that uploaded content infringes on their copyright. US-based tech companies that receive these infringement notices must comply with these rules to receive their safe harbor—the protection they have from being liable for hosting unlawful user content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DMCA has become a global tool for censorship, precisely because it was designed to facilitate the removal of online media. The law carries provisions on intermediary liability, among many other strict copyright enforcement rules, which induce websites, Internet service providers, and other such &quot;intermediaries&quot; to remove content that is alleged to be a copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-bill-would-update-copyright-law-to-recognize-marriage-equali</id>
      <title>New Bill Would Update Copyright Law to Recognize Marriage Equality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-bill-would-update-copyright-law-to-recognize-marriage-equali" />
      <updated>2014-11-25T11:14:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Rep. Derek Kilmer&lt;/strong&gt; (D-&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;WA&lt;/span&gt;), along with &lt;strong&gt;Ilena Ros-Lehtinen&lt;/strong&gt; (R-&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FL&lt;/span&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;Jared Polis&lt;/strong&gt; (D-&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CO&lt;/span&gt;) and other co-sponsors introduced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/113/hr5617/text&quot;&gt;Copyright and Marriage Equality Act&lt;/a&gt;, a new bipartisan bill that would amend the Copyright Act to more fully include same-sex married couples under the Copyright Act’s protection regarding the transfer of the rights to original&amp;nbsp;work.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/computer-scientists-ask-supreme-court-to-rule-apis-cant-be-copyr</id>
      <title>Computer Scientists Ask Supreme Court to Rule APIs Can’t Be Copyrighted</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/computer-scientists-ask-supreme-court-to-rule-apis-cant-be-copyr" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T12:47:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;EFF Files Amicus Brief on Behalf of Tech Pioneers in Oracle v. Google Court Battle. Generally speaking, APIs are specifications that allow programs to communicate with each other. So when you type a letter in a word processor, and hit the print command, you are using an API that lets the word processor talk to the printer driver, even though they were written by different people. The brief explains that the freedom to re-implement and extend existing APIs has been the key to competition and progress in both hardware and software development. It made possible the emergence and success of many robust industries we now take for granted—for example, mainframes, PCs, and workstations/servers—by ensuring that competitors could challenge established players and advance the state of the art.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/when-trainees-meet-terminology-how-should-we-describe-copyright</id>
      <title>How should we describe copyright?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/when-trainees-meet-terminology-how-should-we-describe-copyright" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T13:08:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;During my last trainee presentation, as I was covering the copyright portion, at some point I described copyright as a unique type of “exclusive” right. “Not so”, intervened one of the trainees. “I had a course on the subject, and we were taught that copyright is a monopoly right.” While I deflected the issue (“let’s talk about it after the presentation”—which we did), the comment got me to thinking once again: how should we be describing copyright; indeed, should be seeking to describe it at all in such a fashion?&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/jailbreaking-is-not-a-crimeand-eff-is-fighting-to-keep-it-that-w</id>
      <title>Jailbreaking Is Not A Crime—And EFF Is Fighting To Keep It That Way</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/jailbreaking-is-not-a-crimeand-eff-is-fighting-to-keep-it-that-w" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T13:22:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you own a phone or a tablet, you should be able to run whatever software you want on it. It seems like a simple truth, but there are a surprising number of hurdles in the way. Most pressingly, if the manufacturer of that phone or tablet wants to, they can misuse the law to limit your control over the device long after your purchase. This week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/document/eff-jailbreaking-exemption-request&quot;&gt;EFF has filed a petition&lt;/a&gt; with the Librarian of Congress and the Copyright Office to extend and expand the exemption that allows you to &quot;jailbreak&quot; your phone from those restrictions, without running afoul of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/dmca&quot;&gt;Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&#039;s important because jailbreaking (or &quot;rooting,&quot; on Android devices) has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/02/letters-copyright-office-why-i-jailbreak&quot;&gt;real-world implications&lt;/a&gt; for users&#039; ability to use their phones and tablets effectively and securely. It may be a necessary step before installing security updates after a device has stopped being supported by the manufacturer. In other cases, it may help users install accessibility software that allows them to use a device despite disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-piracy-is-changing-the-music-industry-landscape</id>
      <title>How piracy is changing the music industry landscape</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-piracy-is-changing-the-music-industry-landscape" />
      <updated>2014-09-30T14:39:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While legal sales of recorded music continue to suffer from widespread music piracy, the popularity of live music appears to be enjoying an unprecedented boom, particularly in the UK where new stadiums such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://livemusicexchange.org/blog/from-the-apollo-to-the-hydro-from-atmosphere-to-convenience-kenny-forbes/&quot;&gt;£125m Hydro Arena in Glasgow&lt;/a&gt; have contributed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
