<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/FR/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in FR</title>
  <updated>2018-01-13T16:39:28+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-dpa-issues-formal-notice-to-microsoft-to-comply-with-data</id>
      <title>French DPA issues formal notice to Microsoft to comply with data protection rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-dpa-issues-formal-notice-to-microsoft-to-comply-with-data" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:10:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Chair of the National Data Protection Commission (CNIL) has ordered Microsoft to stop collecting excessive user data and to stop tracking the web browsing of Windows 10 users without their consent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-facebook-to-stop-tracking-non-users</id>
      <title>CNIL orders Facebook to stop tracking non-users</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-facebook-to-stop-tracking-non-users" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:06:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French data protection authority, the CNIL, has issued the company with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnil.fr/english/news-and-events/news/article/the-french-data-protection-authority-publicly-issues-formal-notice-to-facebook-to-comply-with-the-fr/&quot;&gt;formal notice&lt;/a&gt; to comply with European data protection law or face possible sanctions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook has been given three months to make the changes deemed necessary by the CNIL.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-approves-surveillance-bill-despite-un-concerns</id>
      <title>France approves surveillance bill despite UN concerns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-approves-surveillance-bill-despite-un-concerns" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:07:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The constitutional council approved the surveillance bill, a law that gives new spying powers to intelligence agencies.&amp;nbsp;The Socialist government justified the bill, which allows intelligence agencies to tap phones and emails, and hack computers without permission from a judge, in the wake of terrorist attacks in Paris in January.&amp;nbsp;The bill was &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/may/05/france-passes-new-surveillance-law-in-wake-of-charlie-hebdo-attack&quot;&gt;passed in June&lt;/a&gt; by an overwhelming number of French MPs, despite opposition from green and far-left parliamentarians and &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fidh.org/International-Federation-for-Human-Rights/europe/france/human-rights-organisations-alarmed-by-bill-that-will-give&quot;&gt;human rights activists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a report published on Friday, the 18-strong &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://tbinternet.ohchr.org/_layouts/treatybodyexternal/SessionDetails1.aspx?SessionID=899&amp;amp;Lang=en&quot;&gt;United Nations committee for human rights&lt;/a&gt; warned that the surveillance powers granted to French intelligence agencies were “excessively broad”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-constitutional-court-broadly-approves-surveillance-act</id>
      <title>French Constitutional Court broadly approves Surveillance Act</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-constitutional-court-broadly-approves-surveillance-act" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:07:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First proposed in March in the aftermath of the Charlie Hebdo shootings in Paris, the Surveillance Act allows French intelligence agencies to spy on citizens with almost complete impunity. Despite opposition from rights groups and a petition signed by over 100,000 people, MPs passed the bill into law in late June anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The act empowers intelligence agencies - under the authority of the prime minister’s office - to monitor anyone. A warrant or any other type of court approval is not needed. A dedicated special advisory group made up of magistrates, MPs, and senators will instead be consulted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French Constitutional Court press release is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conseil-constitutionnel.fr/conseil-constitutionnel/francais/les-decisions/acces-par-date/decisions-depuis-1959/2015/2015-713-dc/communique-de-presse.144139.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-privacy-watchdog-raps-whatsapp-over-facebook-data-sharing</id>
      <title>French privacy watchdog raps WhatsApp over Facebook data sharing</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-privacy-watchdog-raps-whatsapp-over-facebook-data-sharing" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T16:39:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;France&#039;s data privacy watchdog may fine messaging app WhatsApp if it does not comply with an order to bring its sharing of user data with parent company Facebook into line with French privacy law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-authorities-deploy-new-surveillance-powers-to-plan-attack</id>
      <title>French authorities deploy new surveillance powers to plan attack</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-authorities-deploy-new-surveillance-powers-to-plan-attack" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:50:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;French prosecutors credited recently enhanced surveillance powers for allowing them to foil a planned terror attack directed by Islamic State targeting sites such as Disneyland Paris. Paris prosecutor François Molins said Friday “new techniques” granted under an anti-terror law, which went into effect this summer helped investigators track down a group of militants who he said were “remotely controlled” by a commander in Islamic State territory in Iraq or Syria. The militants received instructions on how to procure themselves weapons via encrypted messages, Mr. Molins said. The enhanced surveillance powers, granted in the wake of the Nov. 13, 2015, attacks that killed 130 people, have rankled civil-liberties groups. Critics have protested the country’s state of emergency, which has been in effect more than a year, and say that the wording of new laws could allow the new measures to be used more widely than terrorism investigations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-class-action-regime-for-data-protection-violations</id>
      <title>France adopts class action regime for data protection violations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-class-action-regime-for-data-protection-violations" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:13:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French government enacted a bill creating a legal basis for class actions against data controllers and processors resulting from data protection violations. The bill aims to facilitate access to justice for French citizens and establishes a general class action regime and includes specific provisions regarding data protection violations. These provisions go beyond the class action provisions already in place for consumers by adding, within the context of the French Data Protection Act of 1978 (“Loi Informatique et Libertés”), a right to class actions for data protection violations regardless of industry sector. Together with the changes to French data protection law ushered in by the recent Digital Republic Bill, the French government is sending a clear signal to companies regarding the importance of data protection as the compliance deadline for the GDPR approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-class-action-regime-for-data-protection-violations-1</id>
      <title>France adopts class action regime for data protection violations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-class-action-regime-for-data-protection-violations-1" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:14:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French government enacted a bill creating a legal basis for class actions against data controllers and processors resulting from data protection violations. The bill aims to facilitate access to justice for French citizens and establishes a general class action regime and includes specific provisions regarding data protection violations. These provisions go beyond the class action provisions already in place for consumers by adding, within the context of the French Data Protection Act of 1978 (“Loi Informatique et Libertés”), a right to class actions for data protection violations regardless of industry sector. Together with the changes to French data protection law ushered in by the recent Digital Republic Bill, the French government is sending a clear signal to companies regarding the importance of data protection as the compliance deadline for the GDPR approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-privacy-row-over-mass-id-database</id>
      <title>French privacy row over mass ID database</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-privacy-row-over-mass-id-database" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:59:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A French state watchdog has called for the suspension of a database that could end up holding the biometric details of 60 million people. The aim of a single &quot;mega-database&quot; is to fight identity fraud and improve efficiency. But there are fears the database could be abused not only by hackers but by state intelligence too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The national digital council calls upon the Government to cancel the setup of the mass ID database and consider alternative means which are more moderate and respectful of human rights. See more details &lt;a href=&quot;http://cnnumerique.fr/cp_fichier_tes/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-second-privacy-shield-legal-challenge-increases-threat-to-eu-u</id>
      <title>A second Privacy Shield legal challenge increases threat to EU-US data flows</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-second-privacy-shield-legal-challenge-increases-threat-to-eu-u" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:55:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Privacy Shield transatlantic data transfer deal is now caught in a pincer action: A week after it emerged that Irish digital rights activists had filed suit to annul the deal come reports that a French campaign group has begun its own legal action. French civil liberties campaign group La Quadrature du Net filed suit against the European Commission, the European Union&#039;s executive body, on October 25. Although the Court of Justice of the EU has not yet published details of the complaint, Brussels-based news agency Euractiv reported Thursday that La Quadrature&#039;s goal is to annul the Commission&#039;s decision that Privacy Shield provides adequate protection under EU law when the personal information of EU citizens is transferred to the U.S. for processing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/entry-into-force-of-the-french-digital-republic-bill</id>
      <title>Entry into Force of the French Digital Republic Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/entry-into-force-of-the-french-digital-republic-bill" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:39:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Digital Republic Bill was enacted after a final vote from the Senate. The Bill aligns the French legal data protection framework with the EU General Data Protection Regulation requirements before the GDPR becomes applicable in May 2018. The Bill significantly increases the maximum level of fines for violations of the French Data Protection Act. The French Data Protection Authority will be able to immediately impose a fine of up to €3 million (previously, fines could not exceed €150,000) until the GDPR becomes applicable. The Bill also gives any consumer the right to obtain, free of charge, a copy of any of his/her data resulting from the use of a service provided by an online communication service provider, except for data that has been “significantly enriched” by the service provider. Any data subject will be able to specify their wishes regarding the retention, erasure and transfer of their personal data after death. These wishes can be recorded by a trusted digital third party certified by the CNIL. The data subject can also request that any of their personal data that was collected as a minor is erased.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-is-unconstitutional-after-all-highest-co-1</id>
      <title>French surveillance law is unconstitutional after all, highest court says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-is-unconstitutional-after-all-highest-co-1" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:44:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Constitutional Council has found unconstitutional a new security law which was approved in July 2015. A key clause of last year&#039;s Surveillance Law essentially allowed security agencies to monitor and control wireless communications without the usual oversight applied to wiretapping operations. This is unconstitutional as the lack of oversight is likely to result in a disproportionate invasion of privacy, the council ruled on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-is-unconstitutional-after-all-highest-co</id>
      <title>French surveillance law is unconstitutional after all, highest court says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-is-unconstitutional-after-all-highest-co" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:34:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French Constitutional Council has taken another look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.com/article/2952512/privacy/french-surveillance-law-is-constitutional-highest-court-says.html&quot;&gt;a new security law it waved through in July 2015&lt;/a&gt;, and found it wanting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key clause of last year&#039;s Surveillance Law essentially allowed security agencies to monitor and control wireless communications without the usual oversight applied to wiretapping operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is unconstitutional as the lack of oversight is likely to result in a disproportionate invasion of privacy, the council ruled Friday. It was responding to &lt;a href=&quot;https://exegetes.eu.org/censure-surveillance-hertzienne-incontrolee/&quot;&gt;a complaint&lt;/a&gt; filed by La Quadrature du Net (LQDN), an association campaigning for online rights, the ISP French Data Network (FDN) and the Federation of Non-Profit ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-overturned-by-constitutional-council</id>
      <title>French surveillance overturned by Constitutional Council</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-overturned-by-constitutional-council" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T12:47:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Constitutional Council overturned on 21 October 2016 the article of the 2015 French Surveillance Law on surveillance. The Constitutional Council adopts the privacy advocates arguments and admits the unconstitutionality of article L. 811-5 of the Internal Security Code. This article enabled surveillance of radio communication, not subject to &quot;any substantive or procedural conditions&quot; and its application not subject to &quot;any guarantee&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ancillary-law-significantly-changes-the-scope-of-sanctions-in-fr</id>
      <title>Ancillary law significantly changes the scope of sanctions in France well in advance of the GDPR</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ancillary-law-significantly-changes-the-scope-of-sanctions-in-fr" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:47:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;French regulatory framework is undergoing an important shift in terms of sanctions imposed by the French Data Protection Authority in case of non-compliance with French Data Protection Law as the administrative fine has been multiplied by 10. This trend is related to the new General Data Protection Regulation which is due to come into force in May 2018. France visibly acts as a precursor and set the example for other data protection authorities. Fines have been seen for a long period of time as the Achilles’ heel of French regulation. That should end, as the new law has multiplied by 10 the fine incurred in case of breach of French Data Protection Law, by increasing the former maximum amount of €300,000 to a new fine of up to €3 million.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-state-of-emergency-overbidding-mass-surveillance</id>
      <title>The state of emergency: overbidding mass surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-state-of-emergency-overbidding-mass-surveillance" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:50:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the latest violent attacks in France, the state of emergency was further prolonged until January 2017. The political response was to increase&amp;nbsp; security measures and lawmakers amended the 2015 Intelligence Act passed last year to legalize domestic mass surveillance. This provision enforces mass surveillance by enabling real time scanning of connection data of individuals suspected of terrorist activity (previously this provision was limited to the 11’700 persons recorded in ‘S’ files, linked to radical Islam).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-changes-its-targeting-to-appease-the-french-data-protec</id>
      <title>Facebook changes its targeting to appease the French Data Protection Authority</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-changes-its-targeting-to-appease-the-french-data-protec" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:59:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The CNIL said Facebook&#039;s tracking of non-users by placing cookies on their browser without informing them when they visit a Facebook page did not comply with French privacy law. It also said that Facebook uses cookies that collect information and is then used for advertising without Internet users&#039; consent. CNIL also stated that Facebook users should have the option of preventing the social network from profiling them in order to serve them personalized ads. In response, the social network states that the tracking of non-users is done for commercial and not security purposes as previously claimed. Facebook put in place additional control tools which enables compliance with CNIL’s requirement for the data subject’s consent. Users can now request that Facebook advertisements do not appear outside the social network while non-users can request not to be tracked by filling a form on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-intervention-against-the-french-data-retention-law</id>
      <title>Civil society intervention against the French data retention law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-intervention-against-the-french-data-retention-law" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:43:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the French Council of State is set to render a first decision on this burning issue this Friday &lt;a title=&quot;On the 12 February at 2pm, the French Council of State is set to give its first decision on the legal challenge against the Military Programming Act (LPM)&quot; href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/#footnote1_39zex0g&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.privacyinternational.org/&quot;&gt;Privacy International&lt;/a&gt; (PI) and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/&quot;&gt;Center for Democracy and Technology&lt;/a&gt; (CDT) have submitted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/Third_party_intervention_PI_CDT_LQDN.pdf&quot;&gt;third party intervention&lt;/a&gt; aiming to support the legal challenges brought by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fdn.fr/&quot;&gt;FDN&lt;/a&gt;, the FDN Federation and La Quadrature du Net. The goal: repeal the provisions enforcing the generalised retention of metadata in France and allow the ECJ to fulfill its role of guardian of fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-attacks-facebook-for-its-bad-handling-of-personal-data</id>
      <title>France attacks Facebook for its bad handling of personal data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-attacks-facebook-for-its-bad-handling-of-personal-data" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T15:03:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In independent but complementary procedures, CNIL and DGCCRF (Competition Directorate-General) warned Facebook to ensure compliance with French law and rectify its practices. DGCCRF pointed at the unfair terms present in the terms and conditions in the use of the social network. More precisely, Facebook’s ‘discretionary power’ was cited which allows it to remove content and unilaterally change the conditions of use. Facebook was given 60 days to rectify this. As for CNIL, it gives Facebook 3 months to react to its more comprehensive list of criticisms, which question the essence of Facbeook’s functioning. CNIL criticizes the social network’s practice of mass collection and processing of sensitive data such as religious or political views. The French authority also expressed its discontent with the aggregation of data of users which enables users’ profiling for advertising purposes. Moreover since the users do not have the option to oppose the collection of data, Facebook is urged to better inform French members on the use of cookies and to delete within six months the history of IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-digital-bill-grants-confidentiality-of-electronic-corresp</id>
      <title>French Digital Bill grants confidentiality of electronic correspondence</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-digital-bill-grants-confidentiality-of-electronic-corresp" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:17:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Digital Bill guarantees the principle of confidentiality of electronic correspondence. Emails shall henceforth be as confidential as physical letters, and may not be analysed by email services, except in order to detect spam and viruses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-looking-at-banning-tor-blocking-public-wi-fi</id>
      <title>France looking at banning Tor, blocking public Wi-Fi</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-looking-at-banning-tor-blocking-public-wi-fi" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:41:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to leaked documents from the Ministry of Interior, the French government is considering two new pieces of legislation: a ban on free and shared Wi-Fi connections during a state of emergency, and measures to block Tor being used inside France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The documents were seen by the French newspaper Le Monde. According to the paper, the new bills could be presented to parliament as soon as January 2016. The new laws are presumably in response to the attacks in Paris last month where 130 people were murdered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first piece of proposed legislation, according to Le Monde, would forbid free and shared Wi-Fi during a state of emergency. The new measure is justified by way of a police opinion, saying that it&#039;s tough to track people who use public hotspots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As for the second proposal, the Ministry of Interior is looking at blocking and/or forbidding the use of Tor completely. Blocking people from using Tor within France is technologically quite complex, but the French government could definitely make it difficult for the average user to find and connect to the Tor network. If the French government needs some help in getting their blockade set up, they could always talk to the only other country in the world known to successfully block Tor: China, with its Great Firewall.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-death</id>
      <title>Digital death</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-death" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:58:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The draft digital bill gives the possibility to decide what will happen to a person’s personal data after its death and the start-ups have already started exploring the possible options. According to the draft law, the internet users can designate a person to execute their wish, if no such specification is made, by default the right will belong to the spouses and/or heirs. If adopted, the law will enable French citizens to instruct Web services what is to be done with their personal data upon their death, which also represent a way of avoiding the multiplication of phantom accounts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/surveillance-of-international-communication-legalized</id>
      <title>Surveillance of international communication legalized</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/surveillance-of-international-communication-legalized" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:48:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Constitutional Court gave its approval to all the legal provisions of the Law on International Surveillance, complementing the Intelligence Bill, the former being much less polemical than the later bill. The Law on International Surveillance was submitted to the court in September after a provision of the Intelligence Bill on International surveillance was censored by the court in July for not providing the conditions for operating and controlling the collected intelligence. The new law legalizes the surveillance of communication emitted or received abroad, namely through the interception of data transiting undersea cables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laquadrature.net/fr/surveillance-France-%C3%A9coute-monde&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-citizens-leaders-in-europe-at-the-application-of-the-righ</id>
      <title>French citizens – leaders in Europe at the application of the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-citizens-leaders-in-europe-at-the-application-of-the-righ" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:54:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;French citizens have submitted 250 000 requests to the Google search engine for the application of right to be forgotten, almost half of the request concerned personal information which was either outdated or inexact. Starting from 24 May 2014, Google received a total of 347 533 such requests in Europe, France being the country with the highest number of applicants.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/hollande-announces-security-pact</id>
      <title>Hollande announces security pact</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/hollande-announces-security-pact" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:44:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hollande announced a set of measures to harden anti-terrorism laws, including changes to France&#039;s constitution. Hollande asked the parliament to vote before the end of the week to extend the state of emergency for three months, with provisions to facilitate administrative, rather than judiciary, searches and house arrests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The articles of the constitution organizing the state of emergency and &quot;full powers&quot; for the president are &quot;no longer suited to the current situation&quot;, he said, and proposed that authorities be allowed &quot;adequate means to take exceptional measures&quot;, without having to have recourse to the state of emergency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hollande also said that terrorists with a double citizenship, &quot;including those who were born French&quot;, should be stripped of their French citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/insufficient-security-of-clients-data-optical-center-fined-eur-5</id>
      <title>Insufficient security of clients’ data: Optical Center fined EUR 50 000</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/insufficient-security-of-clients-data-optical-center-fined-eur-5" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:56:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Data Protection Authority fined Optical Center EUR 50 000 for not ensuring sufficient security and confidentiality of its clients’ data. In December 2014, following an individual complaint, the company was asked to redress its data processing practices and ensure compliance with the law on Information and Data Protection.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-meps-impede-investigations-on-national-surveillance-laws</id>
      <title>French MEPs impede investigations on national surveillance laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-meps-impede-investigations-on-national-surveillance-laws" />
      <updated>2015-11-01T22:07:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Claude Moraes report has been adopted today by the European Parliament. This report was condemning mass surveillance and calling for an investigation of French surveillance laws. But any mention of investigation into French laws has been erased.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La Quadrature du Net, outraged by the political manoeuvres, asks the European Commission to look into such questions on its own initiative in order to, at last, verify the conformity of French surveillance laws to European Law. La Quadrature du Net calls on Europeans to use this text to ask their national deputies and MEPs to put an end to this race towards mass surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-bill-on-international-surveillance</id>
      <title>France adopts bill on international surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-adopts-bill-on-international-surveillance" />
      <updated>2015-11-01T21:59:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;France adopted the bill on international surveillance, legalising mass surveillance beyond French borders, incidentally affecting numerous French people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To enter into force, the bill must be formally approved by the French National Assembly and the French Senate.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-open-letter-to-the-french-parliament-against-surve</id>
      <title>Civil society open letter to the French Parliament against Surveillance Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-open-letter-to-the-french-parliament-against-surve" />
      <updated>2015-10-09T10:02:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week the French National Assembly adopted a Surveillance Bill that would enable mass surveillance of international phone calls and allow the government tap French undersea cables and monitor all internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill is an attempt to repackage a clause from the Intelligence Act that was declared &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conseil-constitutionnel.fr/conseil-constitutionnel/francais/les-decisions/acces-par-date/decisions-depuis-1959/2015/2015-713-dc/decision-n-2015-713-dc-du-23-juillet-2015.144138.html&quot;&gt;unconstitutional&lt;/a&gt; over the summer. Now that the surveillance bill has been adopted in the lower chamber, it will be considered by the French Senate, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/page/s/stop-france&quot;&gt;set to vote&lt;/a&gt; at the end of October. Access strongly opposes this bill, and along with several dozen other NGOs and digital rights groups, we sent an &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/Surveillance_CivilRights_Letter_French_MPs_EN.pdf?utm_content=buffer161da&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;open letter&lt;/a&gt; to members of the French Parliament to articulate our concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-against-the-draft-surveillance-bill</id>
      <title>Open letter against the draft Surveillance Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-against-the-draft-surveillance-bill" />
      <updated>2015-11-01T22:14:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Civil rights groups condemn draft mass surveillance bill to be adopted in France. The bill contains disproportionate surveillance measures to monitor international communications. Based on the principle of massive collections of data, the bill seeks to legitimise the civil and human rights abuses revealed by Edward Snowden about the practice of intelligence agencies such as the ones in the US and the UK. As a crucial part of the global Internet traffic goes through French submarine cables, this law would put France in the list of countries with sweeping surveillance capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bill follows from the Surveillance Law passed in June, which allows the French government, among other measures, to monitor people&#039;s phone calls and emails without judicial approval; and to install black boxes on internet service providers&#039; infrastructure to collect metadata on millions of innocent individuals. Earlier this year, the French Constitutional Council struck down one of the provisions of the Surveillance bill, and the new proposal seeks to re-authorise the international surveillance programme impacted. The draft law will be voted on 1 October by the French National Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/right-to-be-forgotten-rejection-of-googles-internal-appeal</id>
      <title>Right to be forgotten: rejection of Google’s internal appeal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/right-to-be-forgotten-rejection-of-googles-internal-appeal" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T15:51:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CNIL rejected Google’s appeal concerning the application of the right to be forgotten requests on additional geographical extensions (i.e. ‘.com’) besides the European ones (i.e. google.fr, google.es). The reason for the appeal was that Google qualified the extension of the measure as a form of censorship and damage to the right to information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-opens-a-legal-process-against-google-for-not-applying-the</id>
      <title>France opens a legal process against Google for not applying the right to be forgotten globally</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-opens-a-legal-process-against-google-for-not-applying-the" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:21:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Data Protection Authority (CNIL), in June ordered Google to de-list on request search results appearing under a person&#039;s name from all its websites, including Google.com. The company refused in July and requested that the CNIL abandon its efforts, which the regulator officially refused to do on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The President of the CNIL rejects Google&#039;s informal appeal against the formal notice requesting it to apply delisting on all of the search engine&#039;s domain names. Therefore France is the first European country to open a legal process to punish Google for not applying the right to be forgotten globally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-closed-its-proceedings-with-regards-to-the-psg-football</id>
      <title>CNIL closed its proceedings with regards to the PSG FOOTBALL</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-closed-its-proceedings-with-regards-to-the-psg-football" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T16:00:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Data Protection Authority filed inquiries with regards to PSG FOOTBALL databases of persons prohibited access to the stadium. Following clarification provided by PSG FOOTBALL in July 2015, the group confirmed the database contains only information concerning persons measures against whom are still valid.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/legal-actions-against-anti-human-rights-laws</id>
      <title>Legal actions against anti-human rights laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/legal-actions-against-anti-human-rights-laws" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T13:56:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since January 2015, La Quadrature du Net, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fdn.fr/&quot;&gt;FDN&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ffdn.org/&quot;&gt;FDN Federation&lt;/a&gt; have begun a series of legal actions before the French Council of State and the French Constitutional Council against the laws and the implementing decrees that these associations consider fatal to civil liberties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To follow the different stages of these procedures, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/appeals-before-the-french-council-of-state-and-constitutional-counc&quot;&gt;explanatory page&lt;/a&gt; is available.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-google-to-comply-to-the-cjeu-decision-on-delisting-p</id>
      <title>CNIL orders Google to comply to the CJEU decision on delisting personal data from searches</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-google-to-comply-to-the-cjeu-decision-on-delisting-p" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T11:05:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnil.fr/english/&quot;&gt;French Data Protection Authority&lt;/a&gt; (CNIL) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnil.fr/english/news-and-events/news/article/cnil-orders-google-to-apply-delisting-on-all-domain-names-of-the-search-engine/&quot;&gt;ordered Google&lt;/a&gt; to comply with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?num=C-131/12&quot;&gt;judgement&lt;/a&gt; of the Court of Justice of the European Union concerning the so called &quot;right to be forgotten&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the assessment of the complaints received, the CNIL has requested Google to carry out the delisting of several results specifying that the delisting should be effective on whole search engine, irrespective of the extension used.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The President of the CNIL has put Google on notice to proceed, within a period of fifteen (15) days, to the requested delisting on the whole data processing and thus on all extensions of the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-change-of-the-french-surveillance-bill-undermines-ci</id>
      <title>Last minute change of the French Surveillance Bill undermines civil liberties</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-change-of-the-french-surveillance-bill-undermines-ci" />
      <updated>2015-06-19T23:10:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Quadrature du Net reports on a last minute change of the French Surveillance Bill and it calls to French representatives to reject this text during the final vote on the 23rd and 24th June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The change is a defeat for civil liberties and the procedure for the modification itself is characterised as anti-democratic. The new amendment states that any person transiting in France or not being identified as habitually resident is deprived from all the guarantees offered by the preliminary notice and can be directly put under surveillance following authorisation by the French Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-google-to-apply-delisting-on-all-domain-names-of-the</id>
      <title>CNIL orders Google to apply delisting on all domain names of the search engine</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-orders-google-to-apply-delisting-on-all-domain-names-of-the" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:14:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CNIL received hundreds of complaints following Google’s refusals to carry out delisting on Internet links (or URL).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bodytext&quot;&gt;Following the assessment of the complaints, the CNIL has requested Google to carry out the delisting of several results. It was expressly requested that the delisting should be effective on whole search engine, irrespective of the extension used (.fr; .uk; .com …).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;bodytext&quot;&gt;Although the company has granted some of the requests, delisting was only carried out on European extensions of the search engine and not when searches are made from “google.com” or other non-European extensions. In this context, the President of the CNIL has put Google on notice to proceed, within a period of fifteen (15) days, to the requested delisting on the whole data processing and thus on all extensions of the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-now-before-the-senate</id>
      <title>French surveillance law now before the Senate</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-law-now-before-the-senate" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:16:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 5 May 2015, members of the lower chamber of French Parliament &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2015/05/05/despite-opposition-france-approves-dangerous-new-surveillance-law&quot;&gt;approved&lt;/a&gt; the so-called “French Patriot Act”, or “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.senat.fr/leg/pjl14-424.html&quot;&gt;Projet de loi relatif au renseignement&lt;/a&gt;”, despite the serious concerns about users’ rights to privacy and freedom of expression. The bill is currently under analysis by the French Senate and it will be voted upon on 9 June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access, as part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sous-surveillance.fr/#/&quot;&gt;coalition&lt;/a&gt; of 25 other organisations, is opposing this bill. You can find their analysis of the proposed legislation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2015/04/27/feeding-the-all-seeing-spider-france-on-verge-of-passing-repressive-new-sur&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-monitoring-program-2015</id>
      <title>CNIL monitoring program 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-monitoring-program-2015" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:16:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2015, CNIL plans to pursue 550 controls on new technologies or newly established procedures which are part of the daily life of French citizens. For comparison, in 2014 a total of 421 checks were made. The top priority areas include the treatment of personal data in the framework of managing psycho-social risks in companies, Binding Corporate Rules, the national database for driving licenses set up by the Ministry of Interior and others.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/customs-agencies-purchased-mobile-surveillance-technologies-forb</id>
      <title>Customs agencies purchased mobile surveillance technologies forbidden for use before the entry into force of the surveillance bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/customs-agencies-purchased-mobile-surveillance-technologies-forb" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T13:14:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Once the surveillance law enters in force, the IMSI-catchers (technology used for intercepting communication) can be used by secret services to intercept communication, specifically mobile phone calls. However evidence exists that IMSI-catchers have already been in use, for example during the pursuit of the Kouachi brothers as mentioned by Senator Boutant. Moreover, there is official evidence regarding this purchase by public bodies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deputies-plan-to-refer-the-new-intelligence-bill-to-french-const</id>
      <title>Deputies plan to refer the new intelligence bill to French Constitutional Court and the European Commission</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deputies-plan-to-refer-the-new-intelligence-bill-to-french-const" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:25:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Judging that the new bill contains provisions incompatible with the EU Fundamental Rights Chart, a number of deputies plan to the refer to the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-opinion-on-the-creation-of-a-database-for-terrorism-offende</id>
      <title>CNIL opinion on the creation of a database for terrorism offenders (FIJAIT)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-opinion-on-the-creation-of-a-database-for-terrorism-offende" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:31:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The government legislative proposal to create a national database of persons who committed terrorism crimes, foreseeing similar procedural treatment as the existing databases on sexual or violent offenders (database currently examined by the Constitutional Council and the European Court of Human Rights). CNIL opinion covered such aspects as the length of data storage, automatic inscription of certain persons and the recipient of data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The detailed CNIL consultation input is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnil.fr/fileadmin/documents/approfondir/dossier/police-justice/D2015_119_FIJAIT.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-right-to-be-forgotten-first-decision-delivered-in-applicatio</id>
      <title>The right to be forgotten: first decision delivered in application of CJEU jurisprudence</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-right-to-be-forgotten-first-decision-delivered-in-applicatio" />
      <updated>2015-04-18T12:53:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Google Spain decision delivered by the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) on 13 May 2014 upheld the possibility, subject to certain conditions, for Internet users to ask search engine operators to de-reference links appearing in hits for searches on their names. The operators, starting with Google, have put de-referencing request forms online for Internet users to fill in. Since operators have not always complied with these requests, a number of French courts have been called on to deal with a number of cases involving the CJEU’s criteria, and the first judgments under the urgent procedure have been handed down.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deputies-fear-mass-surveillance-in-view-of-the-new-intelligence</id>
      <title>Deputies fear mass surveillance in view of the new intelligence bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/deputies-fear-mass-surveillance-in-view-of-the-new-intelligence" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:40:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;National Assembly Digital Committee fears that the new intelligence bill will enable mass instead of targeted surveillance, especially given the existence of such operating measures as the ‘black-boxes’ and the IMSI-catcher (technology for interception communications), known to have been employed in the NSA practices.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-bill-would-legalize-data-monitoring</id>
      <title>French surveillance bill would legalize data monitoring</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-surveillance-bill-would-legalize-data-monitoring" />
      <updated>2015-03-21T12:50:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;France&#039;s government is pressing a surveillance bill that would give French intelligence services legal backing to vacuum up metadata in hopes of preventing an imminent terror attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill &quot;would pave the way for extremely intrusive surveillance practices with no judicial pre-authorization,&quot; the organization Amnesty International said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill was proposed long before the deadly Paris attacks by Islamic extremists earlier this year, but the government says it takes on added urgency with each person who radicalizes and turns against France.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-opinion-on-recently-adopted-french-intelligence-bill</id>
      <title>CNIL opinion on recently adopted French intelligence bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-opinion-on-recently-adopted-french-intelligence-bill" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:39:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CNIL alerted that the surveillance files have the legal specificity of prohibiting any control from the perspective of compliance with the law on Internet freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ffdn-quadrature-du-net-lodge-an-appeal-against-council-of-state</id>
      <title>FFDN &amp; Quadrature du Net lodge an appeal against Council of State</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ffdn-quadrature-du-net-lodge-an-appeal-against-council-of-state" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T13:25:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FFDN (fournisseurs d&#039;accès associatifs de la federation) &amp;amp; Quadrature du Net lodged an appeal against the Council of State concerning the decree on the application of the law on military programming (adopted in December 2013), more precisely regarding the administrative access to connection data. The appeal comes in the context of the European Court of Justice’s decision of 8 April 2014 to cancel the 2006 Directive on Data Retention. The action is further backed by decisions of certain EU states, such as the Netherlands and Bulgaria, to review their respective legislation in order to ensure compliance with citizens’ privacy rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-seeks-to-sanction-web-companies-for-hate-speech</id>
      <title>France seeks to sanction web companies for hate speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-seeks-to-sanction-web-companies-for-hate-speech" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:18:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;President Francois Hollande said Tuesday in Paris the government will present a draft law next month that makes Internet operators “accomplices” of hate-speech offenses if they host extremist messages. Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he will travel to the U.S. to seek help from the heads of Twitter Inc. and Microsoft Corp. as well as Google and Facebook. Spokesmen for the companies did not immediately return requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-minister-lobbies-meps-on-eu-passenger-bill</id>
      <title>French minister lobbies MEPs on EU passenger bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-minister-lobbies-meps-on-eu-passenger-bill" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:12:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU’s passenger name record bill has been stuck in the European Parliament since 2013 after MEPs in the committee voted it down. The bill requires airlines to hand over to the police the personal details of anyone flying into the EU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Civil liberty defenders question the mass surveillance aspect that underpins the bill, noting that the European Court of Justice last year ruled against data retention. But pressure to get it signed has intensified since the attack in Paris against Charlie Hebdo, with France’s interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve now lobbying individual MEPs. On Wednesday (4 February), he arrived at the European Parliament in Brussels where he spoke to lead MEPs from the committee on reaching a compromise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-privacy-audits-to-increase-by-33-in-2014</id>
      <title>CNIL privacy audits to increase by 33% in 2014</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-privacy-audits-to-increase-by-33-in-2014" />
      <updated>2014-11-20T12:32:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French data protection authority (CNIL) released - on 19 May 2014 - its 2013 Annual Report, detailing its activities for the past year. Additionally, the CNIL published its 2014 strategy on 29 April 2014, outlining the key focus areas in the year ahead. The CNIL stated that it aims to increase privacy audits from 414 in 2013 to 550 in 2014 - an increase of 33%.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
