<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/NL/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in NL</title>
  <updated>2017-10-21T15:58:26+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nl-parliament-makes-open-standards-mandatory-joinup</id>
      <title>NL Parliament makes open standards mandatory</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/nl-parliament-makes-open-standards-mandatory-joinup" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:45:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The use of open standards will be made mandatory for public administrations. A law proposal by MP Astrid Oosenbrug was adopted by the Parliament’s lower house yesterday. According to the MP, the open standards requirement will be one of several changes to the country’s administrative law, introduced next year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-nra-t-mobile-may-continue-to-violate-net-neutrality-1</id>
      <title>Dutch NRA: T-Mobile may continue to violate net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-nra-t-mobile-may-continue-to-violate-net-neutrality-1" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:58:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EDRi member Bits of Freedom asked the Dutch national regulatory authority, Authority for Consumers and Market (ACM), to test the mobile operator T-Mobile’s subscription against the new European rules that protect net neutrality, to verify whether its “Data-free Music” service infringes upon the principle of net neutrality. On 11 October 2017, the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://www.acm.nl/nl/publicaties/t-mobile-mag-dienst-datavrije-muziek-de-lucht-houden&quot;&gt;ACM ruled&lt;/a&gt; T-Mobile to be compliant with the law. Bits of Freedom disagrees and will challenge this decision.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-court-approves-zero-rating-offer-of-telecom-operator</id>
      <title>Dutch court approves zero rating offer of telecom operator</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-court-approves-zero-rating-offer-of-telecom-operator" />
      <updated>2017-04-21T21:04:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Court rules Dutch zero rating prohibition to be in violation with net neutrality regulation. Read the full court decision &lt;a href=&quot;https://uitspraken.rechtspraak.nl/inziendocument?id=ECLI:NL:RBROT:2017:2940&amp;amp;showbutton=true&amp;amp;keyword=netneutraliteit&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (in Dutch).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The telecom operator&#039;s response is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.t-mobile.nl/dvm-uitspraak/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-smart-city-strategy-under-development</id>
      <title>Dutch Smart City strategy under development</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-smart-city-strategy-under-development" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T16:08:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A large number of Dutch cities, companies and scientists have contributed to the National Smart City Strategy. Earlier today, they presented their Strategy to Prime Minister Mark Rutte, who had requested a consolidated Smart City Vision. The G5 of the Netherlands’ largest five cities (Amsterdam, Rotterdam, The Hague, Utrecht and Eindhoven) together with the G32 of middle to large size Dutch towns are keen to take a leading role and have asked central government in The Hague for support. The aim of the National Smart City Strategy is to improve the quality of life in Dutch cities and to introduce innovative solutions to increase their international competitive strength.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Dutch towns and cities are expanding and the pressure on public amenities and infrastructure is growing, it is vital to undertake action now. Around the world, cities are faced with issues such as urbanisation, climate change, employment, digitisation and mobility. The Dutch towns and cities agree that investments in smart technology are necessary to respond to these major social challenges and will provide a substantial contribution to their economic vitality. These initiatives will require the set-up of cross-sector partnerships and active participation from both residents and businesses, focusing on cybersecurity, privacy, interoperability, hyperconnectivity, open source digital infrastructure, standardisation and finance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-government-prohibits-price-discrimination-for-internet-acc</id>
      <title>Dutch government prohibits price discrimination for internet access</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-government-prohibits-price-discrimination-for-internet-acc" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T13:39:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch parliament has approved a proposal from the government to prohibit online price discrimination (“zero rating”). The Netherlands’ vote is in accordance with the country’s history of upholding strong net neutrality law, including the prohibition of zero rating.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-court-to-hear-action-by-tribesmen-devastated-by-drones</id>
      <title>Dutch court to hear action by tribesmen devastated by drones</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-court-to-hear-action-by-tribesmen-devastated-by-drones" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T16:01:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A legal action by two Somali tribesmen whose lives were devastated by an American drone strike last year is to be heard in a Dutch court due to the fact that the Dutch intelligence Service MIVD provided processed data used for a US-directed drone strike.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-gambling-regulator-issues-record-fine</id>
      <title>Dutch gambling regulator issues record fine</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-gambling-regulator-issues-record-fine" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T15:37:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dutch national gaming regulator Kansspelautoriteit has handed out its biggest-ever fine to two companies behind a website that has been operating illegally in the country.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-govt-rules-out-early-cut-in-benelux-roaming-charges</id>
      <title>Dutch govt rules out early cut in Benelux roaming charges</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-govt-rules-out-early-cut-in-benelux-roaming-charges" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T15:41:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch government has ruled out ending roaming charges in the Benelux earlier than the EU deadline of 15 June 2017. In a briefing to parliament, Dutch economic affairs minister Henk Kamp said it was neither realistic nor desirable to scrap the roaming surcharges earlier in the region.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-firm-kpn-starts-network-for-internet-of-things</id>
      <title>Dutch firm KPN starts network for &#039;Internet of Things&#039;</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-firm-kpn-starts-network-for-internet-of-things" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T15:44:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dutch telecoms firm KPN announced Wednesday it had launched in two cities a new wireless technology known as LoRa to wirelessly connect objects, ahead of a country-wide rollout. The network is working in Rotterdam and The Hague from today and will come into effect across the rest of the country in stages in 2016, KPN said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-public-sector-agency-issues-app-security-requirements</id>
      <title>Dutch public sector agency issues app security requirements</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-public-sector-agency-issues-app-security-requirements" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T15:04:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch public sector IT security agency Centrum voor Informatiebeveiliging en Privacybescherming (CIP) has developed with a number of partners 19 security requirements to help developers and suppliers make safe applications for smartphones and tablets. The agency started the project to address the growing use of mobile apps for public services and communication.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-new-law-gives-intelligence-services-broader-powers</id>
      <title>Proposed new law gives intelligence services broader powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-new-law-gives-intelligence-services-broader-powers" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T16:35:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On July 2, the Minister of the Internal Affairs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetconsultatie.nl/wiv&quot;&gt;proposed and published&lt;/a&gt; (source document in Dutch) a new Intelligence and Security Services Act as part of an internet consultation process. The law provides the Dutch intelligence and security agencies with more powers for intercepting communications and searching automated systems.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-concerns-regarding-dutch-ubo-register</id>
      <title>Privacy concerns regarding Dutch UBO register</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-concerns-regarding-dutch-ubo-register" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T23:14:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 9, two major Dutch business lobby organizations expressed privacy concerns in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vno-ncw.nl/SiteCollectionDocuments/Brieven/150609%20brief%20aan%20Kamp%20EZ%20-%20implementatie%204e%20anti%20witwas%20richtlijn%20%283%29.pdf&quot;&gt;letter to the Minister of Economic Affairs and the Minister of Security and Justice&lt;/a&gt; (source document in Dutch) regarding the implementation of the Fourth Anti-Money Laundering Directive. The Directive requires EU member states to establish a register of ultimate beneficiary owners (&quot;UBOs&quot;), which would contain information about persons holding at least 25 percent of the voting rights or capital interest in a company.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/telecoms-firm-tele2-slams-dutch-governments-new-internet-tap-pla</id>
      <title>Telecoms firm Tele2 slams Dutch government’s new internet tap plans</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/telecoms-firm-tele2-slams-dutch-governments-new-internet-tap-pla" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T15:47:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch cabinet’s plans to give the security service far greater powers to tap phones and internet services are impossible to implement and too far reaching, according to telecoms company Tele2. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk put his plans out to consultation earlier this month and Tele2 is the first of the big Dutch telcos to respond. The new rules will give the AIVD and MIVD access to all fixed link and internet traffic in what critics say is a Big Brother charter.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-tax-authority-to-use-imsi-catchers-to-track-smartphones</id>
      <title>Dutch Tax Authority to use IMSI catchers to track smartphones</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-tax-authority-to-use-imsi-catchers-to-track-smartphones" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T23:10:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch Minister of Economic Affairs, Henk Kamp, announced on August 17, 2015, that the Fiscal Intelligence and Investigation Service (Fiscale inlichtingen-en opsporingsdienst, FIOD), a special investigatory unit under the country’s Tax and Customs Administration, will have the authority “to track and tap smartphones and tablets, including pre-paid sim cards&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-igf</id>
      <title>Netherlands IGF</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-igf" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:18:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Netherlands IGF will be held on 1 October 2015 in The Hague.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NL IGF is meant for businesses, non-profit organizations, government (local &amp;amp; national), politicians and other parties who attach value to international cooperation and knowledge sharing around the internet debate and who emphasize the importance of the Internet Governance Forum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NL IGF, has been established recently. In it the ministry of Economic Affairs (Dutch: Ministerie van EZ), SIDN (the Foundation for Internet Domain Registration in the Netherlands) and ECP | Platform for the Information Society. They are collaborating to bring the importance of the IGF to the attention of Dutch stakeholders. On the one hand they do so to realize a firm embedding of the international results into&amp;nbsp;national policy and, on the other hand, to make the Dutch voice heard internationally and to put important Dutch themes on the international agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-dutch-security-act-and-its-impact-on-internet-startup-up</id>
      <title>The new Dutch Security Act and its impact on Internet startup-ups</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-dutch-security-act-and-its-impact-on-internet-startup-up" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:27:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch legal context went through a lot of changes since 2013 when it scored one of the highest privacy ratings in the world. Now, the judicial infrastructure is changing and a new law proposal gives more powers to the Dutch General Intelligence, Security Service and Military Intelligence Agencies to mass survey and wiretap innocent civilians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The law not only has huge implications for Dutch civilians, it also has a huge impact on internationally focused Dutch startups as they fall under the proposed regulation. For example, there is a new law proposal which allows the Dutch General Intelligence, Security Service and Military Intelligence Agencies to mass survey and wiretap innocent civilians.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-government-began-exploring-the-security-of-the-present-int</id>
      <title>Dutch government began exploring the security of the present Internet based election services for oversea voters</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-government-began-exploring-the-security-of-the-present-int" />
      <updated>2015-06-16T00:29:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;The Dutch Minister of the Interior notified the Parliament of the intent to carry out security tests of internet-based voting services to examine whether Internet voting can be feasible to Dutch voters abroad. No reference is made to &lt;a class=&quot;western&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.cyberwar.nl/2015/05/dutch-govt-to-explore-electronic-voting-again/&quot;&gt;ongoing investigations/study into (domestic) electronic voting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-dpa-comments-on-public-private-online-identification-stand</id>
      <title>Dutch DPA comments on public-private online identification standard</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-dpa-comments-on-public-private-online-identification-stand" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T16:38:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 11, the Dutch Data Protection Authority &lt;a href=&quot;https://cbpweb.nl/nl/nieuws/cbp-maakt-eerste-analyse-van-eid-stelsel&quot;&gt;commented on eID&lt;/a&gt; (source document in Dutch), a proposed new standard for online identification for access to both corporate and government services. The authority expressed concerns about the shared responsibility and accountability for the platform and noted that the Data Protection Act requires the appointment of a single responsible party.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/government-leaves-protection-of-online-gamblers-largely-up-to-op</id>
      <title>Government leaves protection of online gamblers largely up to operators</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/government-leaves-protection-of-online-gamblers-largely-up-to-op" />
      <updated>2015-06-16T00:41:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;The government’s proposed new gambling act is leaving the protection of gamblers largely in the hands of the gambling operators. Not a very good idea, according to gaming expert Sytze Kingma, lecturer at the VU Department of Organisation Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-woman-asks-court-to-order-facebook-to-identify-revenge-por-1</id>
      <title>Dutch woman asks court to order Facebook to identify revenge porn perpetrator</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-woman-asks-court-to-order-facebook-to-identify-revenge-por-1" />
      <updated>2015-06-21T11:41:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;A Dutch woman is going to court to try to find out who is responsible for placing a home-made sex film she features in online. The woman’s lawyer, Thomas van Vugt, says this is the first time the Dutch courts are being asked to order Facebook to hand over information about one of its users. ‘The verdict will be of great importance to other victims,’ he said.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-guidelines-in-the-netherlands-come-into-force-on</id>
      <title>Net Neutrality Guidelines in the Netherlands come into force on March 15, 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-guidelines-in-the-netherlands-come-into-force-on" />
      <updated>2015-06-15T23:43:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;The Dutch Department of Economic Affairs issued &lt;a class=&quot;western&quot; href=&quot;https://zoek.officielebekendmakingen.nl/stcrt-2015-13478.html?zoekcriteria=%3Fzkt%3DUitgebreid%26pst%3DTractatenblad%257CStaatsblad%257CStaatscourant%257CGemeenteblad%257CProvinciaalblad%257CWaterschapsblad%257CBladGemeenschappelijkeRegeling%257CParlementaireDocumenten%26vrt%3Dnetneutraliteit%26zkd%3DInDeGeheleText%26dpr%3DAlle%26spd%3D20150519%26epd%3D20150519%26sdt%3DDatumPublicatie%26ap%3D%26pnr%3D1%26rpp%3D10&amp;amp;resultIndex=0&amp;amp;sorttype=1&amp;amp;sortorder=4&quot;&gt;guidelines on net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; for the Authority for Consumers and Markets (ACM). These Net Neutrality Guidelines serve as a basis for the enforcement by ACM of the net neutrality rules in Article 7.4a of the Dutch Telecommunications Act (Net Neutrality Act).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/security-in-times-of-surveillance</id>
      <title>Conference: Security in Times of Surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/security-in-times-of-surveillance" />
      <updated>2015-05-19T20:58:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Eindhoven Institute for the Protection of Systems and Information (Ei/PSI) organized a 1-day event on Security in Times of Surveillance. The event featured eight invited talks covering technical as well as legal and political aspects of security and surveillance. The videos and slides of the conferences are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://projectbullrun.org/surveillance/2015/video-2015.html?hs=true&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-provides-information-after-formal-demand-from-the-dutch</id>
      <title>Facebook provides information after formal demand from the Dutch DPA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-provides-information-after-formal-demand-from-the-dutch" />
      <updated>2015-06-16T00:38:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;The Dutch Data Protection Authority (DPA) imposed a conditional fine on Facebook because it had not provided a part of the information that the Dutch DPA has formally demanded as part of its investigation. The investigation focuses on the privacy conditions of the social media company. The Dutch DPA needs the requested information from Facebook, amongst others, to determine its competence and the applicability of the Dutch data protection act. Facebook indicated to provide the further information regarding the set of questions that concerns the competence of the Dutch DPA and the applicability of the Dutch data protection act. The Dutch DPA will assess the information and has therefore temporarily suspended the conditional fine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-rules-on-right-to-be-delisted-from-search-engines</id>
      <title>Court rules on right to be delisted from search engines</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-rules-on-right-to-be-delisted-from-search-engines" />
      <updated>2015-04-18T13:04:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 12 February 2015, the Amsterdam Court ruled on a case where the plaintiff requested that Google modify its search results based on search queries containing certain words including, but not limited to the plaintiff’s name. This is the second occasion where the Amsterdam Court has been asked to rule on this subject, popularly referred to as the “right to be forgotten”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/3-dutch-supreme-court-upheld-conviction-against-intelligence-ser</id>
      <title>Dutch Supreme Court upheld conviction against intelligence service agent for leaking classified information to Dutch newspaper</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/3-dutch-supreme-court-upheld-conviction-against-intelligence-ser" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T21:18:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;On March 31st 2015, the Supreme Court upheld the conviction of a Dutch General Intelligence &amp;amp; Security Service (AIVD) officer for leaking classified information to journalists from the Dutch newspaper De telegraaf, ruling that that the AIVD official cannot invoke rights granted by Article 10 ECHR concerning protection of journalistic sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;Please find more information in English &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cyberwar.nl/2015/03/supreme-court-of-the-netherlands-upholds-conviction-of-aivd-employee-for-leaking-classified-information-to-newspaper/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in Dutch &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rechtspraak.nl/Organisatie/Hoge-Raad/Nieuws/Pages/Veroordeling-van-medewerker-AIVD-voor-%E2%80%98lekken%E2%80%99-blijft-in-stand.aspx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-civil-rights-group-highlights-dangers-of-isds-in-trade-dea</id>
      <title>Dutch civil rights group highlights dangers of ISDS in trade deals</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-civil-rights-group-highlights-dangers-of-isds-in-trade-dea" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T09:35:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 9 March 2015, EDRi-member Vrijschrift sent a letter to the Dutch Parliament, highlighting the dangers of investor-state dispute settlement clauses (ISDS) in the trade agreements with Canada (CETA) and Singapore (EUSFTA) that the European Union is currently negotiating.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/members-of-dutch-parliament-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-fo</id>
      <title>Members of Dutch parliament want assurances over wider powers for security services</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/members-of-dutch-parliament-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-fo" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:09:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MPs wants guarantees from the government that the decision to give the security services wider powers to tap phones and internet traffic will not be abused, website nu.nl reports on Tuesday. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk and defence minister Jeanine Hennis are due to present their draft legislation for&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MPs wants guarantees from the government that the decision to give the security services wider powers to tap phones and internet traffic will not be abused, website nu.nl reports on Tuesday. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk and defence minister Jeanine Hennis are due to present their draft legislation for expanding the security services’ intelligence-gathering powers shortly. Nu.nl questioned various party representatives about their position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Socialist Party MP Ronald van Raak said the security services could only be given more powers if the influence of US and British secret services was removed. Plasterk, he pointed out, has been unable to say whether Dutch journalists are being spied on by the British security service GCHQ. In addition, ‘the way the NSA has behaved has destroyed trust in the Americans,’ he said. ‘Our security service regulator has also spoken about the breach of trust. Plasterk said he would do something about it, but I have heard nothing.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;left: -99999px; position: absolute;&quot;&gt;Socialist Party MP Ronald van Raak said the security services could only be given more powers if the influence of US and British secret services was removed. Plasterk, he pointed out, has been unable to say whether Dutch journalists are being spied on by the British security service GCHQ. In addition, ‘the way the NSA has behaved has destroyed trust in the Americans,’ he said. ‘Our security service regulator has also spoken about the breach of trust. Plasterk said he would do something about it, but I have heard nothing.’&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more at DutchNews.nl: MPs want assurances over wider powers for security services &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&quot;&gt;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;left: -99999px; position: absolute;&quot;&gt;MPs wants guarantees from the government that the decision to give the security services wider powers to tap phones and internet traffic will not be abused, website nu.nl reports on Tuesday. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk and defence minister Jeanine Hennis are due to present their draft legislation for expanding the security services’ intelligence-gathering powers shortly. Nu.nl questioned various party representatives about their position.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more at DutchNews.nl: MPs want assurances over wider powers for security services &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&quot;&gt;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;left: -99999px; position: absolute;&quot;&gt;MPs wants guarantees from the government that the decision to give the security services wider powers to tap phones and internet traffic will not be abused, website nu.nl reports on Tuesday. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk and defence minister Jeanine Hennis are due to present their draft legislation for expanding the security services’ intelligence-gathering powers shortly. Nu.nl questioned various party representatives about their position.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more at DutchNews.nl: MPs want assurances over wider powers for security services &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&quot;&gt;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;left: -99999px; position: absolute;&quot;&gt;MPs wants guarantees from the government that the decision to give the security services wider powers to tap phones and internet traffic will not be abused, website nu.nl reports on Tuesday. Home affairs minister Ronald Plasterk and defence minister Jeanine Hennis are due to present their draft legislation for expanding the security services’ intelligence-gathering powers shortly. Nu.nl questioned various party representatives about their position.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more at DutchNews.nl: MPs want assurances over wider powers for security services &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&quot;&gt;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2015/02/mps-want-assurances-over-wider-powers-for-security-services/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-telecos-kpn-and-vodafone-fined-for-net-neutrality-violatio</id>
      <title>Dutch telecos KPN and Vodafone fined for net neutrality violations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-telecos-kpn-and-vodafone-fined-for-net-neutrality-violatio" />
      <updated>2015-06-15T23:48:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;p { margin-bottom: 0.08in; direction: ltr; color: rgb(0, 0, 0); }p.western { font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,serif; font-size: 12pt; }p.cjk { font-family: &quot;WenQuanYi Zen Hei&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }p.ctl { font-family: &quot;Lohit Hindi&quot;,&quot;MS Mincho&quot;; font-size: 12pt; }a:visited { color: rgb(128, 0, 128); }a.western:visited {  }a.cjk:visited {  }a.ctl:visited {  }a.western:link {  }a.ctl:link {  }&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; align=&quot;justify&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;The Dutch Authority for Consumer and Market (ACM) said it fined KPN because the free wi-fi hotspots it provided at Dutch airports &quot;blocked various services including several internet calling services. As a result, consumers were unable to use these services. Internet providers are prohibited from deciding what their customers can and cannot do online.&quot; And the Reason to fine Vodafone is the positive discrimination it exerted on consumers in general on its network by offering applications allowing customers to watch pay-TV channel HBO for free on certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0in&quot; align=&quot;justify&quot; lang=&quot;en-GB&quot;&gt;More information in Dutch is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acm.nl/nl/publicaties/publicatie/13762/Boetes-KPN-en-Vodafone-voor-overtreden-regels-netneutraliteit/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in English &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/dutch-data-retention-law-struck-down-for-now/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-advisory-council-on-international-affairs-aiv-adviced-on-i</id>
      <title>Dutch Advisory Council on International Affairs (AIV) adviced on Internet freedom</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-advisory-council-on-international-affairs-aiv-adviced-on-i" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T20:57:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dutch Advisory Council on International Affairs (AIV) published an &lt;a href=&quot;http://aiv-advies.nl/download/7daceb03-a324-4204-8099-3dcbb44e3709.pdf&quot;&gt;advice on internet freedom &lt;/a&gt;(.pdf, in Dutch), following a request for advice that the Minister of Foreign Affairs sent to the AIV in February 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microchip-implants-in-humans-grow-in-popularity</id>
      <title>Microchip implants in humans grow in popularity</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/microchip-implants-in-humans-grow-in-popularity" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T11:50:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Martijn Wismeijer, a Dutch citizen, uses one chip as a savings account for bitcoins – which he says is the safest way to keep them. The chip on his other hand stores the passwords for 900 websites. People who have been chipped can unlock or lock their phones or make payments simply by scanning their hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Worldwide some 2,000 people have been ‘chipped’ and their number is growing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;left: -99999px; position: absolute;&quot;&gt;Martijn Wismeijer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Read more at DutchNews.nl: Microchip implants in humans grow in popularity, some 50 Dutch people are ‘chipped’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2014/12/microchip-implants-in-humans-grow-in-popularity-some-50-dutch-people-are-chipped.php/&quot;&gt;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2014/12/microchip-implants-in-humans-grow-in-popularity-some-50-dutch-people-are-chipped.php/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-intelligence-and-security-agencies-may-gain-bulk-cable-int</id>
      <title>Dutch intelligence and security agencies may gain bulk cable-interception power</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dutch-intelligence-and-security-agencies-may-gain-bulk-cable-int" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T21:00:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The government drafted a legislative proposal to update the Dutch Intelligence and Security Act of 2002 which would expand the existing bulk interception power of the Dutch intelligence agencies AIVD and MIVD from non-cable bound communications to also include cable communications.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-open-government-partnership-self-assessment-report-2</id>
      <title>Netherlands: Open Government Partnership self-assessment report 2014</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-open-government-partnership-self-assessment-report-2" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T21:02:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This first self-assessment report about the Open Government program sets out how the plan was developed as well as the progress made with the implementation so far. The report includes progresses regarding internet consultation, a legislative calendar and the online publication of government documents.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-security-service-does-not-have-to-reveal-phone-and-i</id>
      <title>Netherlands: Security service does not have to reveal phone and Internet tap numbers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-security-service-does-not-have-to-reveal-phone-and-i" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T21:13:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Judges from The Hague ruled on Thursday that Dutch security service AIVD does not have to publicize the number of phone and Internet taps it sets up a year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-the-streamlining-act-came-into-force</id>
      <title>Netherlands: the Streamlining Act came into force</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/netherlands-the-streamlining-act-came-into-force" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T21:18:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On August 1, 2014, the Streamlining Act came into force. As a result of this act, the Establishment Act on the Netherlands Authority for Consumers and Markets, and the laws that&amp;nbsp;ACM&amp;nbsp;enforces have been amended. With these amendments, the different powers, enforcement tools and procedures of the three predecessors of the Netherlands Authority for Consumers and Markets (ACM) have been harmonized, streamlined, and simplified, thereby creating a clear and uniform set of rules for&amp;nbsp;ACM.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/safeguard-public-interests-in-telecommunication-company-takeover</id>
      <title>Safeguard public interests in telecommunication company takeover in the NL</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/safeguard-public-interests-in-telecommunication-company-takeover" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T21:21:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Letter from the Minister of Economic Affairs to the House of Representatives regarding safeguarding public interests in general, and national security in particular, in the event of a takeover of a telecommunications company like KPN, airing out the Dutch government’s concern and baselines in similar takeovers of key IT companies in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
