<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/IT/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in IT</title>
  <updated>2017-06-12T15:13:59+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-now-on-italys-proposal-for-regulating-government-hacking</id>
      <title>Italy proposes regulation for government hacking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-now-on-italys-proposal-for-regulating-government-hacking" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T15:13:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Members of the Italian parliament have advanced a proposal for regulating government hacking activities, including the use of hacking tools, such as Trojans and other software designed to extract data from internet-connected devices. Released in February, the proposed regulations are out for public comment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/censorship-in-italy-child-protection-is-the-excuse-again</id>
      <title>Censorship in Italy: Child protection is the excuse again</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/censorship-in-italy-child-protection-is-the-excuse-again" />
      <updated>2016-10-20T15:02:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the recurrent attempts to control the internet is the excuse of “child protection”. Italy has moved a step to this direction, and is going to release a &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.boingboing.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/bill.pdf&quot;&gt;new law&lt;/a&gt; against “cyberbullying” that confirms this new trend.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/avmsd-refit-or-reform-audio-visual-media-services-in-the-digital</id>
      <title>AVMSD Refit or Reform? Audio Visual Media Services in the Digital Era</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/avmsd-refit-or-reform-audio-visual-media-services-in-the-digital" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:50:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This study aims to analyze the key points of the proposed revision of the Audiovisual Media Services Directive highlighting the strengths and weaknesses, and proposing new policy in the form of final recommendations, with a view to one regulatory scenario that takes into account the diverse positions of the stakeholders involved. The first part of the study examines the current rating audiovisual landscape in Europe, stressing that this is changing quickly thanks to technological advances and market developments and the convergence of media. The second part is devoted to the European Commission&#039;s proposal for amendment of Directive 2010/13/EU, together with the assessment of its impact Italian legal order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study is available in English &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medialaws.eu/avmsd-refit-or-reform-audio-visual-media-services-in-the-digital-era/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/work-in-progress-on-the-digital-agenda-in-italy</id>
      <title>Work in progress on the Digital Agenda in Italy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/work-in-progress-on-the-digital-agenda-in-italy" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T23:16:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Daily information on the monitoring the implementation of the Digital Agenda of Italy is available online. The implementation of the Agenda is being monitored by the Agenzia per l’Italia Digitale (AGID). Among the relevant data available at the beginning of June 2016 on various fields of application, the following can be highlighted.&lt;br /&gt;SPID: on June 2016, 3 identity providers accredited; 64.470 SPID identities provided; 401 types of services made available by SPID;&lt;br /&gt;Electronic payment: 13.850 public administration offices involved; total transactions up to April 2016 were 350.114&lt;br /&gt;Digital civil registry: in the pilot phase, 26 Municipalities activated; 6,5 millions of citizens involved&lt;br /&gt;Electronic invoice: 35 millions of invoices managed&lt;br /&gt;Open Data: 10.348 datasets of public administration made accessible&lt;br /&gt;Digital competence: 105 projects activated&lt;br /&gt;Digital health dossier: 9 Regional governments joined the interoperability system; in 7 Regional governments the service has already been activated;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-approved-the-freedom-of-information-act</id>
      <title>Italy approved the Freedom of Information Act</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-approved-the-freedom-of-information-act" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T21:10:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On May 17, the Italian Presidency of the Council of Ministers approved the Freedom of Information Act, that allows the citizens to freely access the documents of the Public Administration bodies and to request copies. This Act represents an important element of the new Reform of the Public Administration. All the requests presented by citizens cannot be rejected without valid reasons. The approved Act keep into account the suggestions and proposals presented by the Commissions of Parliament and Senate and of the Data Protection National Authority. Great parts of the input of the FOIA campaign have been included. The reasons for restricting access to public information include: national and public security; national defense; international relations; military issues; financial and economic policies of the State; judicial inquiries. Not all the comments positively welcomed the approval of the FOIA. Someone observed that with this formulation the rights to transparency of the Public administration have been bureaucratized: the FOIA limits the transparency granted by the legislative decree no. 33/2013. Duties and responsibilities of the Public Administration by the Decree of 2013 have not been confirmed. Furthermore no sanctions are foreseen for the public bodies that not respect the FOIA.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sharing-economy-act-the-first-italian-legislative-proposal-on-th</id>
      <title>Sharing Economy Act - the first Italian legislative proposal on the subject</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/sharing-economy-act-the-first-italian-legislative-proposal-on-th" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T23:09:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On March 2, a group of deputies belonging to the Innovation Joint Committee presented a legislative proposal about the Sharing economy. Sharing economy is growing up in Italy: there are 186 collaborative platforms, generating around 13 billions of revenue (in the sectors of peer-to-peer finance; accommodation sharing; staffing online; car sharing; sharing of video and music). The proposed legislation contains norms concerning issues such as the protection of privacy of the users data or the taxation to be applied on sharing economy exchange (10%). This proposal was the object of an open consultation on the web until May 16, 2016. Following that, a series of auditions at the Chamber of Deputies will take place, before its discussion and approval by the Chamber. At the same time sharing economy was the object of seminars and meetings involving relevant stakeholders such as the National Antitrust Authority; AGCOM, the Ministry of Finance, enterprises and public administration, lawyers. Among the most relevant one can quote the seminar organized by the European University of Rome, or the workshop on the role of communities in the sharing economy held in May 2016, in the framework of the Forum of the Public Administration.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-code-of-the-public-digital-administration</id>
      <title>The new Code of the Public (Digital) Administration</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-code-of-the-public-digital-administration" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:14:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Italian Council of State published its consensus about the New Code of Public Digital Administration - CAD. After this, the Code will be discussed and then approved by the Parliament. Meanwhile, an important debate is currently ongoing on the measures and interventions needed to change the Italian public administration into a digital one and on the interventions needed to develop the digital capacities of users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new CAD is focused on the issue of digital citizenship and in this framework. It introduces several changes in the existing rules in order to align the old Code to the new purposes and the European law (for instance for what concerns the validity and efficacy of electronic documents as forensic evidence). In this regard it provides for changes or new norms related to electronic documents and their storage and electronic signature and emphasizes the importance of the digital identity (SPID) and of the digital domicile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It also introduces the role of Chief Digital Officer and of Digital Ombudsman in each public administration body and establishes a Permanent Conference for technological innovation; the norms of the new CAD have to be applied not only by public bodies but also in legal trials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of the criticism to the New Code concerns the elimination of important norms related to the obligation for enterprises and other organizations to set up digital disaster recovery and business continuity plan; or the elimination of most of the norms and provisions for implementing and deploying smart cities and communities, or the removal of the obligation for the Public Administration to use free software. Other critics expressed their concern about the excessive anonymisation of data for privacy protection affecting the open data approach and lamented the low level of participation and involvement of stakeholders in the formulation of the new CAD.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-italian-national-framework-on-cyber-security</id>
      <title>The Italian National Framework on Cyber Security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-italian-national-framework-on-cyber-security" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T23:01:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Research Centre of Cyber Intelligence and Information Security of the University “La Sapienza” of Rome and the National Laboratory on Cyber Security of CINI – Consorzio Interuniversitario Nazionale per l’Informatica set up the National Framework for Cyber Security. The Framework – composed by a set of Guidelines on how to reduce and manage cyber risks – was presented in Rome on February 1st 2016, at the presence of Marco Minniti, Under Secretary of State and Head of the Agency for security. The Framework represents the outcome of nine months of work, which involved the most important Italian enterprises and the major public organizations in the field. Also the USA Institute for Standards and Technologies – NIST has been involved. The Framework – with its rules – is a tool that might be easily adapted to the needs and characteristics of each enterprise and/or organization. Cyber security is a priority of the Italian government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cybersecurityframework.it/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-enquiry-of-the-defence-standing-committee-of-the-chamber-o</id>
      <title>Italy: Enquiry of the Defence Standing Committee of the Chamber of Deputies Description</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-enquiry-of-the-defence-standing-committee-of-the-chamber-o" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T22:56:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of January 2016 the Defence Standing Committee of the Chamber of Deputies started an Enquiry on the issues of security and defence of the cyber space in Italy. The Enquiry will have a duration of one year and foresees the audition and consultation of relevant Italian stakeholders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/declaration-of-internet-rights</id>
      <title>Declaration of Rights on the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/declaration-of-internet-rights" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:58:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On July 28th 2015 the final version of the “Declaration of Rights on the&amp;nbsp;Internet&quot; was published in the media. The Declaration was drafted by a Committee established in July 2014 by the Italian President of the Chamber of Deputies and chaired by professor Rodotà. The text is composed by a preamble and 14 articles. A first draft of the Declaration was published in October 2014 and presented at the meeting of the members of the European Parliament in October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the public consultation period the text was accessed more than 14.000 times and 590 opinions were received on the content of the Declaration. At the same time the audition of 46 relevant stakeholders took place during the consultation period. The final version of the Declaration will be presented at the next IGF meeting in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The President of the Chamber of Deputies, Ms Boldrini, hopes that the content of the Declaration might be content of a unitary motion of the Parliament to the Government. The text of the Declaration (in Italian, English, French, German and Spanish) and other related documents are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.camera.it/leg17/1179&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-of-things-industry-questioned-by-privacy-regulator</id>
      <title>Internet of Things industry questioned by privacy regulator</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-of-things-industry-questioned-by-privacy-regulator" />
      <updated>2015-05-12T12:02:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) is becoming exponentially reviewed by regulators. &amp;nbsp;After the report from the Italian telecom regulator (AgCom), the Italian privacy authority just launched a consultation seeking inputs from the industry on how to regulate the IoT.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-the-italian-constituent-for-internet-governance</id>
      <title>Towards the Italian constituent for Internet Governance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-the-italian-constituent-for-internet-governance" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:59:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On April 14, 2015, during a seminar organised with the occasion of the visit of the President of ICANN Mr Fadi Chehadé, the Under Secretary of State Mr Giacomelli launched a program to set up&amp;nbsp;an Italian “constituent committee” to develop a multi-stakeholder model of Internet Governance. The intention is to set up a structure similar to that established in Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Giacomelli is also engaged in promoting a European unitary initiative and position on Internet governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available in Italian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.agendadigitale.eu/smart-cities-communities/la-costituente-italiana-per-una-nuova-governance-di-internet_1547.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.corrierecomunicazioni.it/tlc/33723_internet-governance-e-l-ora-di-una-costituente-italiana.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italian-declaration-of-rights-on-the-internet-work-in-progress</id>
      <title>Italian Declaration of Rights on the Internet – work in progress</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italian-declaration-of-rights-on-the-internet-work-in-progress" />
      <updated>2015-04-15T13:48:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The public online consultation on the draft “Dichiarazione dei diritti in Internet” (Declaration of Rights on the Internet) proposal ended on 31 March 2015. The text was drafted by a special Commission of the Italian Chamber of Deputies and it was initially scheduled to last until the end of February, however the consultation was extended for one more month. Approximately 14.000 visits were recorded, with a total of about 600 comments and proposals for integration. All comments are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://camera.civi.ci&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with the online consultation, auditions with different stakeholders (private, public and non profit organizations) took place. Among the issues discussed during the auditions one can mention: freedom of expression; the relationship between the protection of rights offline and online; Internet as a common good; the authors’ rights and IPR protection; the right to Internet access for all; net neutrality; the right to be forgotten, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Declaration has also been discussed during various public events in February and March, including the Social Media Week in Milan (February 23-27), the Biennale della Democrazia held in Turin (March 25-29,). The reasons for the low level of participation in the public consultation and the need to produce such Declaration have also been debated. The Commission will draft a summary document containing the proposals and suggestions received by the public consultation and during the auditions; a further and improved version of the Declaration will be drafted. The final version of the Declaration might be the content of a motion of the Parliament to the Government.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-approves-plan-to-boost-broadband-networks</id>
      <title>Italy approves plan to boost broadband networks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-approves-plan-to-boost-broadband-networks" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T20:03:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Italian government approved a plan on Tuesday to bring its high-speed broadband network into line with European Union targets, but it held back from forcing operators to replace their copper-wire networks with fiber-optic cable.&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://reuters.us.feedsportal.com/c/35217/f/654208/s/440096f5/sc/46/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-government-pushing-for-broadband-solution</id>
      <title>Italy government pushing for broadband solution</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/italy-government-pushing-for-broadband-solution" />
      <updated>2015-03-02T22:02:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;The Italian government is pushing to speed up the roll-out of ultrafast broadband networks to help its ailing economy, fuelling speculation it could force incumbent Telecom Italia (&lt;span id=&quot;symbol_TLIT.MI_0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/finance/stocks/overview?symbol=TLIT.MI&quot;&gt;TLIT.MI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) into a costly overhaul of its existing infrastructure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;The cabinet of Prime Minister Matteo Renzi meets on Tuesday to approve an 6 billion euro ($6.7 billion) plan to build a nationwide fiber optic network by replacing the aging copper wires that run into subscribers&#039; homes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-bill-of-rights-audizioni-alla-camera</id>
      <title>The Italian Internet Bill of Rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-bill-of-rights-audizioni-alla-camera" />
      <updated>2015-02-25T00:27:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The ambitious Constitution of the rights and obligations on the Internet, strongly supported by&amp;nbsp;Laura Boldrini, the President of the Chamber, who now speaks openly of &quot;Magna Charta&quot; of the Internet, is now a draft which aims to tackle the more complex topics that have evolved with the evolution of the network, such as right to be forgotten, big data, right of access, net neutrality, security and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first draft of this paper was prepared by a committee of experts chaired by Stefano Rodotà, from the Commission on the rights and obligations on the Internet. The online public consultation on the so-called Bill of Rights, or &quot;Declaration of Rights&quot; opened last October 27 and will end on 27 of February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166473927/u/197/f/438866/c/32288/s/43bc1d51/sc/33/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;kydfgiwgpkfwpdxzwhxw&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166473927/u/197/f/438866/c/32288/s/43bc1d51/sc/33/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166473927/u/197/f/438866/c/32288/s/43bc1d51/sc/33/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;kydfgiwgpkfwpdxzwhxw&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166473927/u/197/f/438866/c/32288/s/43bc1d51/sc/33/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/222166473927/u/197/f/438866/c/32288/s/43bc1d51/sc/33/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
