<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/EU/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in EU</title>
  <updated>2018-01-13T17:25:33+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-does-the-eu-commission-really-plan-to-tackle-ill</id>
      <title>Leaked document: Does the EU Commission really plan to tackle illegal content online?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-does-the-eu-commission-really-plan-to-tackle-ill" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:02:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 14 September, Politico published a leaked draft of the European Commission’s Communication “Tackling Illegal Content Online”. The Communication contains “guidelines” to tackle illegal content, while remaining coy in key areas. It is expected to be officially published on 27 September.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-mps-back-end-to-end-encryption-for-all-citizens-bbc-news</id>
      <title>MEPs back end-to-end encryption for all citizens</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-mps-back-end-to-end-encryption-for-all-citizens-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:13:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A European Parliament committee wants end-to-end encryption to be enforced on all forms of digital communication to protect European Union (EU) citizens. A ban on &quot;backdoors&quot; into encrypted messaging apps like WhatsApp and Telegram is also being considered.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recklessly-unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks</id>
      <title>Recklessly unclear Terrorism Directive creates significant risks for citizens’ security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recklessly-unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:44:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 February, the European Parliament voted in favour of the EU Directive on combating terrorism. In EDRI&#039;s opinion, the weak, unclear, ambiguous wording in the Directive presents dangers for the rule of law, the right to privacy and freedom of opinion and expression of people in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-commission-fines-google-242-billion-for-abus</id>
      <title>European Commission fines Google for abusing dominance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-commission-fines-google-242-billion-for-abus" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:15:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission has fined Google €2.42 billion for breaching EU antitrust rules. Google has abused its market dominance as a search engine by giving an illegal advantage to another Google product, its comparison shopping service.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-telecom-regulators-meet-to-analyse-over-500-000-consultation</id>
      <title>EU Telecom Regulators meet to analyse over 500 000 consultation responses</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-telecom-regulators-meet-to-analyse-over-500-000-consultation" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T19:46:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;BEREC, the Body of European Regulators of Electronic Communications must publish new rules on net neutrality by 30 August, which leaves them little time to process the hundreds of thousands of responses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internal-market-committee-to-greenlight-network-and-information</id>
      <title>Internal market committee to greenlight Network and Information Security directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internal-market-committee-to-greenlight-network-and-information" />
      <updated>2017-05-19T23:41:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MEPs sitting on the internal market committee have welcomed plans for a new cybersecurity law, which was &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.co.uk/security/2016/05/cybersecurity-law-given-thumbs-up-by-european-unions-ministers/&quot;&gt;approved by national ministers&lt;/a&gt; in May. The Network and Information Security (NIS) directive will require “essential services” operators and “digital service providers” to notify the authorities about any cyber “incidents&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The committee will vote on Tuesday and is expected to give the plan its blessing. The European Parliament as a whole is then likely to follow suit, paving the way for national laws in the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-under-investigation-for-eu-internet-forum-document</id>
      <title>EU Commission under investigation for EU Internet Forum documents</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-under-investigation-for-eu-internet-forum-document" />
      <updated>2016-05-30T14:01:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past year, EDRi made numerous formal requests to get more information about the EU Internet Forum. This Forum was set up by the EU Commission to persuade companies to do “more” to fight terrorism. After months of obstruction from the European Commission, EDRi made a maladministration complaint to the European Ombudsman. As a result, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ombudsman.europa.eu/cases/correspondence.faces/en/67709/html.bookmark&quot;&gt;formal inquiry has been launched&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-criticises-incompetent-commission-work-on-child-ab</id>
      <title>EU Parliament criticises incompetent Commission work on child abuse</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-criticises-incompetent-commission-work-on-child-ab" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T17:25:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission proposed its badly drafted “Directive on combating sexual abuse, sexual exploitation of children and child pornography” in 2010. In 2011, it was finally adopted by the Council of the European Union and the European Parliament. Under the Directive, the European Commission was legally required to publish an implementation report by 18 December. The Commission ignored its legal obligation and published its report a year late, on 16 December 2016. It published one report on the whole Directive and one on the implementation of Article 25 on the Directive, on internet blocking. Despite taking an extra year to collect information, the 13-page document is almost entirely devoid of useful data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/interview-nordic-baltic-digital-single-market-no-threat-to-eu</id>
      <title>Nordic-Baltic digital single market &#039;no threat to EU&#039;</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/interview-nordic-baltic-digital-single-market-no-threat-to-eu" />
      <updated>2017-12-20T13:27:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&#039;What we want do is add value on top, and do things&#039; such as border controls and free data movement, said Norwegian state secretary Paul Chaffey about Nordic-Baltic digital cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-parliament-has-approved-budget-for-open-source-vide</id>
      <title>The European Parliament has approved budget for Open Source software bug bounty program</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-parliament-has-approved-budget-for-open-source-vide" />
      <updated>2017-12-06T13:25:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament has approved budget to improve the EU’s IT infrastructure by extending the free software security audit programme (FOSSA) and by including a bug bounty approach in the programme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commission intends to conduct a small-scale &quot;bug bounty&quot; activity on open-source software with companies already operating in the market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-money-public-code-show-your-support-for-free-software-in</id>
      <title>Public money, public code: show your support for free software in Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-money-public-code-show-your-support-for-free-software-in" />
      <updated>2017-10-26T16:40:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global movement for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/open-access&quot;&gt;open access&lt;/a&gt; to publicly-funded research stems from the sensible proposition that if the government has used taxpayers&#039; money to fund research, the publication of the results of that research should be freely-licensed. Exactly the same rationale underpins the argument that software code that the government has funded to be written should be made available as Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). &lt;a href=&quot;https://publiccode.eu/&quot;&gt;Public Money, Public Code&lt;/a&gt; is a campaign of the Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE) that seeks to transform that ideal into European law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-writes-to-eu-commissioner-gabriel-about-tackling-illegal-co</id>
      <title>EDRi writes to EU Commissioner Gabriel about tackling illegal content online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-writes-to-eu-commissioner-gabriel-about-tackling-illegal-co" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:52:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In order to be constructive and support the European Commission in developing a balanced, rights-friendly and harmonised approach to deal with illegal content online in the future, EDRi has written a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/letter_coherent_rightsbasedapproach_illegalcontent_20171020.pdf&quot;&gt;letter to the Digital Economy Commissioner Mariya Gabriel&lt;/a&gt;. They propose the Commission to adopt at least three workstreams: a “fundamental rights framework”, “learning from experience”, and “effective and predictable frameworks for addressing illegal content”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tisa-impact-assessment-report-ignores-crucial-human-rights-conce</id>
      <title>TiSA impact assessment report ignores crucial human rights concerns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tisa-impact-assessment-report-ignores-crucial-human-rights-conce" />
      <updated>2017-10-22T20:39:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the European Commission decided to subject the draft Trade in Services Agreement (TiSA) to a Trade Sustainability Impact Assessment (SIA) in support of the negotiations. The Final Report, which was published in July 2017, fails to address several key fundamental rights concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-press-release-on-eus-efforts-to-tackle-illeg</id>
      <title>European Commission press release on EU&#039;s efforts to tackle illegal content online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-press-release-on-eus-efforts-to-tackle-illeg" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:04:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission publishes a set of guidelines and principles for online platforms, aimed to fight against illegal content online in cooperation with national authorities, Member States and other relevant stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-berec-misses-opportunity-to-lead-the-way</id>
      <title>Net Neutrality: BEREC misses opportunity to lead the way</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-berec-misses-opportunity-to-lead-the-way" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:58:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In November 2015, the European Union adopted the Net Neutrality Regulation (2015/2120), which contained a number of compromises that needed clarification. The Body of European Regulators for Electronic Communications (BEREC) was given the task of developing implementation guidelines to ensure a consistent application of the Regulation throughout Europe and, in practice, settle the remaining ambiguities of the adopted Regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-freedom-index-easing-access-to-information-on-rights-issues</id>
      <title>The Freedom Index – easing access to information on rights issues</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-freedom-index-easing-access-to-information-on-rights-issues" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:28:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A diverse group of human rights defenders in the EU has launched an ambitious project that aims to radically change the way information relating to human rights is organised. If successful, the initiative will create a system that can permanently identify and preserve all human rights data across all languages, and radically improve its availability to anyone who is working on the same issues in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-commission-is-thinking-about-government-hacking</id>
      <title>The European Commission is investigating MLAT processes</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-commission-is-thinking-about-government-hacking" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:05:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;he European Commission has recognised the need to address the flaws in the mutual legal assistance treaties&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt; process so it has launched an investigation into cross-border access to “e-evidence” both within and beyond the EU, with a goal to simplify and optimise the malfunctioning process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-digital-assembly-fireworks-and-data-flows</id>
      <title>Europe’s Digital Assembly: Fireworks and data flows</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-digital-assembly-fireworks-and-data-flows" />
      <updated>2017-08-15T20:30:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the Maltese presidency is coming to an end, those of us in the tech policy Brussels bubble spent two days in the beautiful city of La Valetta to attend the Digital Assembly, organised by the EU Commission.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-leaders-call-for-immediate-open-access-to-all-scientifi</id>
      <title>European leaders call for ‘immediate’ open access to all scientific papers by 2020</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-leaders-call-for-immediate-open-access-to-all-scientifi" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:19:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a 2-day meeting in Brussels, EU member states have agreed on an ambitious new open-access (OA) target involving that all scientific papers should be freely available by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-faces-fine-from-eu-over-market-dominance</id>
      <title>Google faces fine from EU over market dominance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-faces-fine-from-eu-over-market-dominance" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:18:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU officials are expected to announce in the coming weeks that Google has been guilty of manipulating its search engine results to favour its new Google Shopping service and will be facing a record-breaking fine from Brussels of more than €1bn (£875m).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/keynote-speech-by-vice-president-ansip-in-charge-of-the-digital-1</id>
      <title>Keynote speech by Vice-President Ansip in charge of the Digital Single Market</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/keynote-speech-by-vice-president-ansip-in-charge-of-the-digital-1" />
      <updated>2017-08-15T20:16:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Andrus Ansip speech at the Digital Assembly 2017 in Valletta on 15 June 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/regulating-ethereum-eu-parliament-weighs-blockchains-big-issues</id>
      <title>Regulating Ethereum? EU Parliament weighs blockchain&#039;s big issues</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/regulating-ethereum-eu-parliament-weighs-blockchains-big-issues" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T18:53:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MEP Jakob von Weizsäcker stressed the desire of the European Union to monitor, not suffocate [blockchain technology], and pointed out that its role is to respond to the needs of constituents. To this end, the EP wants to get a feel for the sector, since &quot;there is a public interest in what&#039;s going on&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/imco-committee-adopts-report-on-the-draft-geo-blocking-regulatio</id>
      <title>IMCO Committee adopts report on the draft Geo-blocking Regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/imco-committee-adopts-report-on-the-draft-geo-blocking-regulatio" />
      <updated>2017-04-25T22:12:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament IMCO Committee adopted on 25 April the Report on the draft Geo-blocking Regulation by MEP Roza Thun.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks-for-citize</id>
      <title>Unclear Terrorism Directive creates significant risks for citizens’ security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks-for-citize" />
      <updated>2017-03-01T08:40:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 February 2017, the European Parliament voted in favour of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/terrorism-directive-document-pool/&quot;&gt;EU Directive on combating terrorism&lt;/a&gt;. Weak, unclear, ambiguous wording in the Directive presents dangers for the rule of law, the right to privacy and freedom of opinion and expression of people in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/imco-committee-discusses-draft-report-on-geo-blocking</id>
      <title>IMCO Committee Discusses Draft Report on Geo-blocking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/imco-committee-discusses-draft-report-on-geo-blocking" />
      <updated>2017-04-25T22:21:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 25 January, the Internal Market and Consumer Protection (IMCO) Committee of the European Parliament considered the draft &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//NONSGML+COMPARL+PE-595.745+01+DOC+PDF+V0//EN&amp;amp;language=EN&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;, written by rapporteur Róża Thun (EPP, Poland), on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/docs_autres_institutions/commission_europeenne/com/2016/0289/COM_COM(2016)0289_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/a&gt; for a Regulation addressing geo-blocking. The consideration provided an opportunity for the Rapporteur to present her report, and also allowed other MEPs, including the shadow rapporteurs, to give their feedback on the draft report and on the proposal as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/2017-important-consultations-for-your-digital-rights</id>
      <title>2017: Important Consultations for your Digital Rights!</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/2017-important-consultations-for-your-digital-rights" />
      <updated>2017-01-25T20:56:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this blogpost, EDRi lists all the public consultations relevant for digital rights in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-countries-agree-data-roaming-charges</id>
      <title>EU countries agree data roaming charges</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-countries-agree-data-roaming-charges" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:46:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mobile operators will be able to charge each other for the use of data by their customers in Europe and to apply a surcharge when too many people use their network.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/terrorism-directive-document-pool</id>
      <title>Terrorism Directive: Document pool</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/terrorism-directive-document-pool" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:47:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Terrorism is a very complex issue and laws must be balanced, smart and work in times of crisis. European Digital Rights (EDRi) has been working extensively with the Civil Liberties Committee (LIBE) and with Permanent Representations of the European Union Member States to adopt a sound approach in the Terrorism Directive.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statement-by-vice-president-ansip-and-commissioner-oettinger-wel-1</id>
      <title>Statement by Vice-President Ansip and Commissioner Oettinger welcoming the adoption of the first EU-wide rules to make public sector websites and apps more accessible</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statement-by-vice-president-ansip-and-commissioner-oettinger-wel-1" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:52:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European Commission - Statement Statement Statement Strasbourg, 26 October 2016 European Commission Vice-President Andrus Ansip, responsible for the Digital Single Market, and Commissioner Günther H. Oettinger, in charge of the Digital Economy and Society, welcome the decision by the European Parliament to formally approve the Directive on the accessibility of the websites and mobile applications of public sector bodies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ai-predicts-outcome-of-human-rights-cases</id>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence predicts outcome of human rights cases</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ai-predicts-outcome-of-human-rights-cases" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:39:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A research project has found that an AI could accurately predict the outcome of legal cases nearly 80% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-urges-eu-leaders-to-protect-citizens-data-in-trade</id>
      <title>Civil society urges EU leaders to protect citizens’ data in trade agreements</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-urges-eu-leaders-to-protect-citizens-data-in-trade" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T14:14:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European Digital Rights (EDRi), together with 20 civil rights organisations and individual signatories, sent a letter to the leaders of the European Union. In the letter, a broad coalition urges the European Commission and Member State representatives to resist pressure and come forward with proposals which will not sacrifice citizens’ fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mep-reports-how-youtube-took-down-its-video</id>
      <title>MEP reports how YouTube took down its video</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mep-reports-how-youtube-took-down-its-video" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T14:45:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marietje Schaake uploaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLLtD25721Ug7pWiZs-oWYbd8jWLLs_oXv&quot;&gt;a series of videos&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube of a debate in the Parliament and then she received a notice that one of her videos was removed by YouTube because it was against &quot;community guidelines&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-weaken-security-says-uks-new-european-commi</id>
      <title>Encryption backdoors weaken security says UK’s new European Commissioner</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-weaken-security-says-uks-new-european-commi" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T15:16:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julian King, the UK’s new European Commissioner said that he believed encryption backdoors would weaken the online ecosystem as a whole. Regarding data protection questions he would “respect purpose limitations,” citing recent court rulings in the Digital Rights Ireland and the Max Schrems cases. Moreover, despite the ongoing controversy over PNR, King said he wanted to implement existing instruments “to the full.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/introductory-remarks-by-commissioner-designate-sir-julian-king-t</id>
      <title>Introductory remarks by Commissioner-designate Sir Julian King to the LIBE Committee</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/introductory-remarks-by-commissioner-designate-sir-julian-king-t" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:57:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sir Julian King introductory remarks are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_SPEECH-16-3018_en.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-to-give-detailed-results-of-e-commerce-inquiry-on-thursday</id>
      <title>EU to give detailed results of e-commerce inquiry on Thursday</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-to-give-detailed-results-of-e-commerce-inquiry-on-thursday" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:53:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Online and electronics retailers will find out on Thursday whether European Union antitrust regulators plan to take any action after a year-long investigation into restrictions on cross-border online sales within the bloc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/juncker-demands-better-eu-telecom-roaming-charge-plan</id>
      <title>Juncker demands better EU telecom roaming charge plan</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/juncker-demands-better-eu-telecom-roaming-charge-plan" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T16:01:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission withdrew proposals on Friday that would limit next year&#039;s abolition of mobile phone roaming charges after criticism that the rules should do more to favor telecoms firms&#039; customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a dramatic U-turn, four days after officials published rules to restrict how many days consumers could use phones abroad without extra fees, President Jean-Claude Juncker ordered the draft revised in what allies and officials said showed that the EU executive wanted to be seen to listen to ordinary voters.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-the-truth-behind-the-hate-speech-code</id>
      <title>New documents reveal the truth behind the Hate Speech Code</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-the-truth-behind-the-hate-speech-code" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T20:15:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EDRi obtained &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asktheeu.org/en/request/code_of_conduct_against_hate_spe&quot;&gt;documents&lt;/a&gt; revealing different drafts of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/fundamental-rights/files/hate_speech_code_of_conduct_en.pdf&quot;&gt;Code of Conduct against Hate Speech&lt;/a&gt; and the correspondence exchanged between the European Commission and the four big companies that concluded the agreement on 31 May 2016: Facebook, Google, Twitter and Microsoft. These documents complement an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/files/2016/09/Commissioner-Jourova-to-Mr-Jeppesen.pdf&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; sent by Commissioner Jourová to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdt.org/insight/letter-to-european-commissioner-on-code-of-conduct-for-illegal-hate-speech-online/&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; from the Center for Democracy &amp;amp; Technology (CDT) on 21 June 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/berec-guidelines-on-the-implementation-by-national-regulators-of</id>
      <title>BEREC Guidelines on the Implementation by National Regulators of European Net Neutrality Rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/berec-guidelines-on-the-implementation-by-national-regulators-of" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:50:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;BEREC Guidelines on the Implementation by National Regulators of European Net Neutrality Rules have been drafted. They are designed to provide guidance on the implementation of the obligations of NRAs and include the obligations to closely monitor and ensure compliance with the rules to safeguard equal and non-discriminatory treatment of traffic in the provision of internet access services and related end-users rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-wins-in-europe</id>
      <title>Net neutrality wins in Europe!</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-wins-in-europe" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:36:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New net neutrality guidelines from the Body of European Regulators for Electronic Communications (BEREC) confirm strong protection for net neutrality, and for the free and open internet, in the European Union.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-telecom-regulators-meet-to-analyse-over-500000-consultation-r-1</id>
      <title>EU Telecom Regulators meet to analyse over 500,000 consultation responses</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-telecom-regulators-meet-to-analyse-over-500000-consultation-r-1" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:40:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, telecom regulators from all over the EU will gather in Brussels for a uniquely challenging task: analysing over half a million responses to their consultation on net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/oversight-of-the-new-europol-regulation-likely-to-remain-superfi</id>
      <title>Oversight of the new Europol regulation likely to remain superficial</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/oversight-of-the-new-europol-regulation-likely-to-remain-superfi" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:51:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 1 May 2017, the new regulation on Europol will enter into force. The compromise agreed on during the trilogue procedure establishes more detailed provisions on oversight of the activities of Europol by the European Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/filtering-blocking-and-take-down-of-illegal-content-on-the-inter</id>
      <title>Filtering, blocking and take-down of illegal content on the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/filtering-blocking-and-take-down-of-illegal-content-on-the-inter" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:20:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe commissioned the Swiss Institute of Comparative Law a comparative study in respect of filtering, blocking and take-down of illegal content on the Internet in the 47 member States of the Organisation. The study describes and assesses the legal framework but also the relevant case-law and practice in the field. It is divided in two main parts: country reports and comparative considerations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the complete study for download &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coe.int/en/web/freedom-expression/study-filtering-blocking-and-take-down-of-illegal-content-on-the-internet&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-adopts-new-rules-on-the-creation-of-advisory</id>
      <title>European Commission adopts new rules on the creation of advisory expert groups</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-adopts-new-rules-on-the-creation-of-advisory" />
      <updated>2016-05-30T14:43:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, the Commission has adopted new rules on the creation and functioning of the advisory expert groups which provide external expertise to help inform the policy-making process. The Decision provides a single set of rules and principles aimed at increasing transparency, avoiding conflicts of interest and ensuring a balanced representation of interests. The new rules are binding on all Commission departments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-calls-time-on-geo-blocking-in-new-regulation-propo</id>
      <title>EU Commission calls time on geo-blocking in new regulation proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-calls-time-on-geo-blocking-in-new-regulation-propo" />
      <updated>2016-09-05T15:48:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 25 May 2016, the European Commission published a draft new Regulation which will prohibit geo-blocking and various related acts by traders which discriminate by reference to nationality or country of residence or establishment within the EU. The scope of the proposed Regulation is broad and would prevent geo-blocking and discrimination in pricing, sales or payment conditions for online sales.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/launch-of-draft-berec-net-neutrality-guidelines-public-consultat</id>
      <title>Launch of draft BEREC Net Neutrality Guidelines public consultation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/launch-of-draft-berec-net-neutrality-guidelines-public-consultat" />
      <updated>2016-07-25T10:32:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 6 June 2016, from 14.30 to 16.00, BEREC will launch the public consultation on draft BEREC Guidelines on the Implementation by National Regulators of European Net Neutrality Rules and hold a public debriefing for presenting the results from its 27th plenary meeting to take place on 2 and 3 June 2016 in Vienna.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/joint-civil-society-statement-addresses-net-neutrality-in-europe</id>
      <title>Joint Civil-Society Statement Addresses Net Neutrality in Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/joint-civil-society-statement-addresses-net-neutrality-in-europe" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:08:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/NN_letter_BEREC_20160502.pdf&quot;&gt;joint letter&lt;/a&gt;, 73 organisations from 31 countries call on the European Telecom Regulators to uphold net neutrality in their current negotiations about the future of the Internet in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;After 2 years the EU adopted a net neutrality law which leaves many core questions up for interpretation. The Telecom Single Market regulation &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/Net-Neutrality-Major-Setback-for-Internet&quot;&gt;was adopted&lt;/a&gt; in October 2015 in second reading in the European Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Body of European Regulators of Electronic Communication (BEREC) and the 28 telecom regulators are currently negotiating guidelines that clarify the recently adopted ambigous European net neutrality law. The regulators have time until August 2016 to publish their final guidelines and will hold a public consultation in June to July.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/NN_letter_BEREC_20160502.pdf&quot;&gt; the letter&lt;/a&gt; of the 73 organizations addressed to the BEREC.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-internet-freedom-programme-endangered-by-commission</id>
      <title>EU internet freedom programme endangered by Commission</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-internet-freedom-programme-endangered-by-commission" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T23:58:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission appears to have shelved a landmark programme that gave out aid money to help human rights workers, protestors and journalists access the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-cybersecurity-directive-finalised-the-knights-who-say-nis</id>
      <title>EU Cybersecurity Directive finalised</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-cybersecurity-directive-finalised-the-knights-who-say-nis" />
      <updated>2016-04-01T15:51:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union has finalised its first pan-European cybersecurity rules. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2015/12/pdf/st15229-re02_en15_pdf/&quot;&gt;Directive on the Security of Network and Information Systems&lt;/a&gt; (NIS) is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security&quot;&gt;EU cybersecurity strategy&lt;/a&gt; launched in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NIS Directive requires EU member states to develop and implement strict security and notification requirements for “operators of essential services” such as internet exchange points, and more flexible rules for so-called digital service providers, meaning companies that provide cloud computing services, online search engines, and online marketplaces. As we discuss below, there are potential risks for privacy in this approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-the-european-parliament-adopts-the-second-version</id>
      <title>Net neutrality: the European Parliament adopts the second version of the text</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-the-european-parliament-adopts-the-second-version" />
      <updated>2016-01-10T20:02:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The MEPs adopted during the second reading the regulation on the measures concerning access to the internet modifying the 2002 Directive on telecommunications. The totality of amendments proposed by the MEPs promoting net neutrality has been rejected.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-of-justice-rules-that-videos-on-newspapers-website-can-fal</id>
      <title>Court of Justice rules that videos on newspapers&#039; website can fall within AVMS Directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-of-justice-rules-that-videos-on-newspapers-website-can-fal" />
      <updated>2015-11-02T17:48:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 21 October 2015, the European Court of Justice &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=170123&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=486649&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; that the video section of an online newspaper could be considered an audiovisual service and therefore may be regulated by the Audiovisual Media Services Directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ECJ held that, in order to determine the principal purpose of a service offering videos in an online newspaper, the focus must be on whether the video subdomain service had content and form independent of the journalistic activity of the newspaper, and was not merely an &quot;indissociable complement&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-asks-public-opinion-on-geo-blocking</id>
      <title>EU asks public opinion on geo-blocking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-asks-public-opinion-on-geo-blocking" />
      <updated>2015-09-24T15:32:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission started two public consultations Thursday, as part of its Digital Single Market strategy. One is about the role of &lt;a href=&quot;https://euobserver.com/news/128806&quot;&gt;online platforms&lt;/a&gt; such as Google and Amazon, and asks whether they should be more transparent. The other asks citizens about their opinion and experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://euobserver.com/connected/128143&quot;&gt;geo-blocking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commission wants to hear from citizens, manufacturers, retailers (especially SMEs), right holders, data and cloud service providers and users, as well as all those involved in the collaborative economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please see the press release &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-15-5704_en.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-consultation-on-european-telecommunication-framework</id>
      <title>Public consultation on European Telecommunication Framework</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/public-consultation-on-european-telecommunication-framework" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:22:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission published, on September 11, 2015, a public consultation on the evaluation and review of the regulatory framework for electronic communications networks and services. The public consultation is a first step in the future reform of the regulatory framework, which constitutes one of the 16 strategic measures that will be implemented before the end of 2016 in order to create a Digital Single Market, in accordance with the 10 priorities defined by the Commission on July 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-sharing-agreement-to-be-analyzed-by-eu-court</id>
      <title>EU-US data-sharing agreement to be analyzed by EU court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-sharing-agreement-to-be-analyzed-by-eu-court" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T12:07:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The case stems from a complaint filed by 27-year-old Austrian law student Max Schrems against Facebook with the Irish data protection commissioner, who monitors compliance with privacy laws. Schrems argued the company helped the NSA harvest email and other private data from European citizens by forwarding data to servers in the United States and asked the Irish watchdog to investigate whether the United States was providing adequate data protection. The Irish regulator rejected the request on the grounds that it was bound by the EU Safe Harbour agreement of 2000 which allows companies to transfer EU citizens&#039; data to the United States because it is held to have sufficient privacy safeguards in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Justice Advocate General Yves Bot will deliver his opinion in Luxembourg on Wednesday at around 9:30 CET. While the court&#039;s judges are not bound by the opinion, they follow it in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-explanatory-note-on-it-search</id>
      <title>European Commission&#039;s explanatory note on IT search</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-explanatory-note-on-it-search" />
      <updated>2015-09-24T13:22:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission has published on its website an updated version of its explanatory note on how it conducts dawn raids where it suspects that a company has breached antitrust law. The revised note goes into more detail concerning the IT aspects of a European Commission dawn raid and it touches upon cloud services and personal data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The explanatory note is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/competition/antitrust/legislation/explanatory_note.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-european-commission-consultation-on-online-platforms</id>
      <title>Leaked European Commission consultation on online platforms</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-european-commission-consultation-on-online-platforms" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T18:38:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission is imminently expected to commence a public consultation on the subject of online platforms as part of the Commission’s Digital Single Market strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The consultation may be of particular interest to technology companies operating online platforms, rights holders, major users of online platforms (such as banks), data providers (such as market data or demographic data companies) and consumer or digital rights groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The draft of the consultation paper, containing 92 questions, has been leaked onto the Internet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Platforms-consultation.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-meps-adopt-report-to-help-boost-europes-drones-industry</id>
      <title>MEPs adopt report to help boost Europe&#039;s drones industry</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-meps-adopt-report-to-help-boost-europes-drones-industry" />
      <updated>2015-09-19T23:46:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New rules are needed to ensure safe use of drones, the European Parliament&#039;s transport committee has recommended in a new report. No-fly zones are considered, while no new privacy legislation needed, according to UK conservative MEP Jacqueline Foster, steering the new rules through a Parliament plenary vote end of October.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-eu-rules-on-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>New EU rules on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-eu-rules-on-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T17:58:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU has &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-15-5265_en.htm&quot;&gt;agreed&lt;/a&gt; new rules requiring ISPs to ensure net neutrality. The rules take effect on 30 April 2016 and will allow national regulators to impose major financial and other penalties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new EU rules are almost identical to US rules introduced earlier this year. But they don’t go as far as Dutch law, which has some of the strictest net neutrality rules in the world. A comparative table is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freshfields.com/en/global/Digital/blog/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-open-data-incubator-programme-launched</id>
      <title>European open data incubator programme launched</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-open-data-incubator-programme-launched" />
      <updated>2015-09-10T00:09:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Open Data Incubator for Europe (ODINE) is set to award a total of €650,000 to the first seven business selected for its two year open data incubator programme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The startups and SMEs hail from the UK, Italy, France, Estonia and Austria, and provide open data solutions to pressing issues across Europe, including infectious childhood diseases, the recycling of bio-waste and cycling safety in European cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between 50 and 70 open data-focused businesses will be welcomed on to the programme in two month instalments up until August 2016. ODINE has €5m EU grant funding still to award and urges interested companies &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://opendataincubator.eu/&quot;&gt;to register&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/3rd-europol-interpol-cybercrime-conference</id>
      <title>3rd Europol-INTERPOL Cybercrime Conference</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/3rd-europol-interpol-cybercrime-conference" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:10:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The 3rd Europol-INTERPOL Cybercrime Conference will be held at Europol&#039;s European Cybercrime Centre (EC3) in The Hague 30 September - 2 October 2015.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-negociations-on-data-sharing-close-to-wrap-up</id>
      <title>EU-US negociations on data sharing close to wrap up</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-negociations-on-data-sharing-close-to-wrap-up" />
      <updated>2015-08-19T13:19:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;The European Commission is working with the United States on the final details of the Safe Harbour agreement which was put up for renegotiation after the exposed U.S. mass surveillance practices. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Under the new deal, U.S. registered companies will face stricter rules when transferring data to third parties.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;Brussels has demanded guarantees from the United States that the collection of EU citizens&#039; data for national security purposes would be limited to what is necessary and proportionate. The new deal would allow both sides to monitor the functioning of Safe Harbour, including how the limitations on U.S. authorities&#039; access to the data are being applied.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;U.S. President Barack Obama in June signed a bill reforming a government surveillance program. He also plans to extend certain protections enjoyed by U.S. citizens to foreigners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaders-set-to-cherry-pick-eu-digital-strategy-while-the-digital</id>
      <title>Leaders set to cherry pick EU digital strategy while the digital single market 2015 target is not met</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaders-set-to-cherry-pick-eu-digital-strategy-while-the-digital" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T21:14:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU leaders discussed a European Commission plan for a digital single market at the second day of their summit on Friday (26 June), but there are already signs that member states prefer to pick and choose from the list of initiatives which was supposed to be a package deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If national governments do end up stripping down the strategy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://euobserver.com/digital/128602&quot;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; by commissioners Andrus Ansip and Guenther Oettinger last month, it will be a repetition of what happened to the previous commission&#039;s digital action plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the fast pace of the digital developments, the member states have not been able to match that pace when it comes to finding agreement with the European Parliament on a previous commission plan called Connected Continent, also known as the Telecoms Single Market package. The plan was introduced by then digital commissioner Neelie Kroes in September 2013. It aimed to introduce EU-wide rules for telecoms operators, increase consumer rights, and coordinate the assignment of radio spectrum at an EU level.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-the-next-front-in-the-battle-for-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>European battle on net neutrality summed up</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-the-next-front-in-the-battle-for-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T21:36:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The Commission, the Parliament and the Council need to agree on a common position before the final text goes to the vote and becomes a European Regulation. This takes place in a series of “trialogues”, of which three have taken place so far, the most recent on June 2. With the delivery by the Parliament of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.contexte.com/docs/6759/trilogues-neutralite-du-net-18-juin-2015-3.pdf&quot;&gt;second revised compromise proposal&lt;/a&gt; last week, the stage is set for a fourth and final trialogue, probably next week.&lt;p&gt;A campaign website by European digital rights groups at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savetheinternet.eu/&quot;&gt;https://www.savetheinternet.eu&lt;/a&gt; allows Europeans to contact Members of the European Parliament (MEPs) by phone, e-mail or Twitter for free, to encourage them to stand firm on net neutrality, and insist on a strong regulation rather than a loophole-ridden compromise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/echr-decision-websites-are-liable-for-users-comments</id>
      <title>ECtHR decision: Commercial websites could be liable for users’ comments</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/echr-decision-websites-are-liable-for-users-comments" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:15:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Human Rights (ECtHR) has ruled that the Estonian news site Delfi may be held responsible for anonymous and allegedly defamatory comments from its readers. This goes against the European Union’s e-commerce directive, which guarantees liability protection for intermediaries that implement notice-and-takedown mechanisms on third-party comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, one of the worrying aspects of the ECtHR decision is that it may encourage the idea that intermediaries are liable for &quot;manifestly unlawful&quot; content, without specifying what &quot;manifestly unlawful&quot; actually means.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-confirms-it-wants-to-trade-net-neutrality-for-end-of-roa</id>
      <title>Council confirms it wants to trade net neutrality for end of roaming charges</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-confirms-it-wants-to-trade-net-neutrality-for-end-of-roa" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T18:50:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Council [is] willing to move on end of roaming if [the European Parliament] engages on all open issues”, Commissioner Oettinger &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edri/status/609294487630807040&quot;&gt;said this morning&lt;/a&gt;. In other words, the Council is proposing to end &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/paper08_20131023_web.pdf&quot;&gt;net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; in exchange for the end of roaming charges”, argued Joe McNamee, European Digital Rights (EDRi)’s Executive Director. “&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-and-digital-rights-the-booklet</id>
      <title>TTIP and Digital Rights: the Booklet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-and-digital-rights-the-booklet" />
      <updated>2015-06-08T23:16:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, European Digital Rights (EDRi) is publishing its latest booklet, “TTIP and digital rights”: The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) is a trade agreement that is currently being negotiated between the United States and the European Union. TTIP has already raised many concerns among civil society, trade unions, consumer groups, some businesses, and European and national institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-tries-to-rip-citizens-off-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>EU Commission introduces new document on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-tries-to-rip-citizens-off-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:16:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission attacks Net Neutrality again, by introducing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/20150604_Commission_NN.pdf&quot;&gt;“compromise document”&lt;/a&gt; that refuses to enshrine a definition of this crucial principle into the law. A strong coalition including the EU Council, the European Commission and a handful of MEPs is working against the general interest by including &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.laquadrature.net/Trilogue/Trilogue_neutralit%C3%A9_du_net&quot;&gt;loopholes &lt;/a&gt; that will be used by the telecom lobby to circumvent the proposed protections against discrimination, thereby undermining fundamental rights and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission had promised on June 2 to propose a compromise document as negotiations are deadlocked between the European Parliament and the Council of the European Union. The very few improvements in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/20150604_Commission_NN.pdf&quot;&gt;text&lt;/a&gt;, which gives up on any explicit reference to Net Neutrality, leaves important loopholes that must be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-discussions-in-europe-come-close-to-an-end</id>
      <title>Net neutrality discussions in Europe come close to an end</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-discussions-in-europe-come-close-to-an-end" />
      <updated>2015-05-27T12:34:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As negotiations on the Telecoms Single Market (TSM) come close to an end, the Parliament may break its promise to deliver net neutrality. Crucial to the net neutrality developments will be the next Council meeting of Telecommunications ministers on June 12th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past two months the EU Commission, the EU Parliament, and the Council of the EU have gathered almost every week to try to strike a deal on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/policy/Network-Discrimination-Europe&quot;&gt;Telecoms Single Market regulation&lt;/a&gt;. What began as an omnibus draft regulation has been whittled down to two proposals: one to end data roaming in the EU — which would make make mobile connectivity much cheaper across the continent — and one to enshrine net neutrality, the principle according to which all data should be treated equally, not discriminating among users, websites, or services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/second-high-level-conference-on-the-eu-cybersecurity-strategy</id>
      <title>Second High-level Conference on the EU Cybersecurity Strategy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/second-high-level-conference-on-the-eu-cybersecurity-strategy" />
      <updated>2015-05-25T16:10:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conference is organised on the 28 May by the European Commission and it will discuss trust and security in the digital world. The conference will be opened by Gunther Oettinger, Commissioner for Digital Economy and Society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Conference will be an opportunity to explore the way forward regarding the proposal for a Network and Information Security Directive, the EU cybersecurity industrial strategy and the next steps for capacity building for cyber defence and fighting cybercrime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/events/cf/cybersecurity-strategy-second-high-level-conference/register.cfm&quot;&gt;Registration&lt;/a&gt; is open and the agenda is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/information_society/newsroom/cf/dae/document.cfm?action=display&amp;amp;doc_id=9534&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/la-quadrature-du-net-warns-that-the-european-commission-must-pro</id>
      <title>La Quadrature du Net warns that the European Commission must protect fundamental rights in the digital age</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/la-quadrature-du-net-warns-that-the-european-commission-must-pro" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T22:53:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/news/2015/05/20150506_en.htm&quot;&gt;published on 6 May&lt;/a&gt; its strategy for 2020 and the setting up of the Digital Single Market. Several important digital issues are concerned by this agenda: from copyright to crime, from telecommunications to VAT harmonisation. While La Quadrature du Net welcomes the Commission&#039;s engagement with these issues, it does this only with caution as previous attempts were harmful to the protection of fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission&#039;s strategy already started with the proposal on personal data protection and the proposal on telecommunications. These two currently negotiated regulations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/council-of-the-european-union-to-kill-net-neutrality-we-must-act&quot;&gt;raise&lt;/a&gt; serious concerns on the risks they represent to a number of fundamental principles of the Internet and the right of personal data protection.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/regional-cyber-security-summit-in-bucharest</id>
      <title>Regional cyber security summit in Bucharest</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/regional-cyber-security-summit-in-bucharest" />
      <updated>2015-05-11T11:52:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A regional summit on cyber security organized by the Romanian Ministry for Information Society together with the U.S. Department of Commerce and the U.S. Embassy in Bucharest is taking place between May 11 and May 13. Representatives of 17 countries in Central and Eastern Europe will attend the summit and present their cyber security policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo</id>
      <title>Leaked Digital Single Market strategy addresses copyright and geo-blocking, e-privacy and the role of ISPs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T11:17:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leaked copies of the upcoming Digital Single Market Strategy and its supporting Evidence file show the European Commission is ready to propose vast regulatory reforms that could affect everything from sales taxes and e-privacy to Internet searches and big data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-issue-joint-statement-on-information-society</id>
      <title>EU, US Issue Joint Statement On Information Society</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-issue-joint-statement-on-information-society" />
      <updated>2015-04-15T13:51:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union and the United States today held the 13th bilateral Information Society Dialogue and issued a statement highlighting issues discussed and agreed. The two government entities covered topics such as the EU Digital Single Market, digital skills, open internet, the data-driven economy, internet governance, the United Nations review of the 2003-2005 World Summit on the Information Society (WSIS), and cooperation on international telecommunications policy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-of-europe-holds-consultations-on-draft-internet-freedom</id>
      <title>Council Of Europe holds consultations on draft Internet freedom text</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-of-europe-holds-consultations-on-draft-internet-freedom" />
      <updated>2015-04-15T13:53:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A committee of the Strasbourg-based Council of Europe is drafting a recommendation on internet freedom and is requesting public comments until the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-spends-millions-to-make-next-facebook-european</id>
      <title>EU spends millions to make next Facebook European</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-spends-millions-to-make-next-facebook-european" />
      <updated>2015-04-06T17:30:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU Commissioner Oettinger believes Europe’s industrial competitiveness will in the future depend to a large extent on the capacity to develop high quality software and using the most modern computing technologies. EU is investing €80 million in up to 1,000 start-ups to promote the use of Fiware, a public-private partnership between the EU and a consortium of companies that started in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recommendation-of-the-committee-of-ministers-to-member-states-on</id>
      <title>Recommendation of the Committee of Ministers to member States on the free, transboundary flow of information on the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recommendation-of-the-committee-of-ministers-to-member-states-on" />
      <updated>2015-04-02T16:46:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recommendation CM/Rec(2015)6 of the Committee of Ministers to member States on the free, transboundary flow of information on the Internet was adopted by the Committee of Ministers on 1 April 2015, at the 1224th meeting of the Ministers’ Deputies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-trade-secrets-bill-prompts-concern</id>
      <title>EU trade secrets bill prompts concern</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-trade-secrets-bill-prompts-concern" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T13:20:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;NGOs and left-leaning MEPs have voiced concern that an EU bill on trade secrets could harm the public&#039;s access to information on matters of vital interest.&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/44bb112f/sc/19/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;MEPs are trying to walk a fine line between business interests and civil liberties in a new bill on trade secrets. The directive is to unify member states’ legislation on how to protect business from illegal access and disclosure of secret information, for instance, on upcoming patents or innovative technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/transition-period-for-ch-domain-names</id>
      <title>Transition period for &quot;.ch&quot; domain names</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/transition-period-for-ch-domain-names" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T01:47:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new Ordinance on Internet Domains (passed by the Federal Council on 5 November 2014) imposing a separation between the functions of registry and registrar (both performed by SWITCH so far) entered into force in January 2015. On 20 March 2015, OFCOM and SWICH renewed their contract for the management of ‘.ch’ until mid-2017, allowing for a gradual transfer of ‘.ch’ holders to other marketers of domain names.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-reverses-course-on-net-neutrality-legislation-ars-technic</id>
      <title>Europe reverses course on net neutrality legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-reverses-course-on-net-neutrality-legislation-ars-technic" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T16:12:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Less than a year after the European Parliament voted to enshrine net neutrality in law, the principle has come under attack by the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A package of reforms put together by former Digital Agenda Commissioner &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neeliekroeseu&quot;&gt;Neelie Kroes&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2014-03/18/eu-roaming-net-neutrality&quot;&gt;voted through parliament in March 2014&lt;/a&gt;. It included &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2014-04/03/eu-net-neutrality-victory&quot;&gt;strong safeguards&lt;/a&gt; for net neutrality, banning service providers from blocking or slowing internet services provided by competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a majority of the 28 EU member states in the European council have now voted in favour of changing the rules to bar discrimination in internet access but allow the prioritisation of some &quot;specialised&quot; services that required high quality internet access to function.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-proposals-on-open-internet</id>
      <title>EU Council proposals on open internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-proposals-on-open-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T17:57:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After one year of negotiations, a second element of the telecoms regulation was also agreed by the EU Council: arbitrary, ad hoc law enforcement by internet companies. The Council has decided that this is something that internet companies may do, may not do and may do (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/nn_roaming_final.pdf&quot;&gt;Council text, pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/after-the-european-parliament-voted-to-protect-net-neutrality-in</id>
      <title>EDRi comments EU Council proposals on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/after-the-european-parliament-voted-to-protect-net-neutrality-in" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T18:19:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the European Parliament &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/european-parliament-leads-world-open-internet-vote&quot;&gt;voted to protect net neutrality&lt;/a&gt; in April of last year, the EU Council of Ministers has just adopted its &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/nn_roaming_final.pdf&quot;&gt;text on net neutrality (pdf)&lt;/a&gt;*. It claims to aim to defend the open internet, but would, in fact, permit every imaginable breach of net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-criticizes-the-latest-net-neutrality-proposal-in-the-eu</id>
      <title>Access criticizes the latest Net Neutrality proposal in the EU</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-criticizes-the-latest-net-neutrality-proposal-in-the-eu" />
      <updated>2015-03-05T13:59:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, 28 member states of the European Union presented a joint proposal on the Telecoms Single Market — legislation that will determine whether Net Neutrality will become a reality throughout Europe. The proposal officially triggered the start of joint negotiations between the EU Commission, the EU Parliament, and the Council of the EU to produce a final text.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-political-youth-organizations-demand-strict-net-neutrali</id>
      <title>Europe&#039;s political youth organizations demand strict net neutrality rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-political-youth-organizations-demand-strict-net-neutrali" />
      <updated>2015-03-02T20:58:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;European political youth organizations have demanded that European countries draft strict and clear net neutrality rules that prevent ISPs from discriminating against certain Internet traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to keep the Internet open, &lt;a href=&quot;http://youth4netneutrality.eu/&quot;&gt;all data on the Internet should be treated equally&lt;/a&gt;, 51 youth organizations said in a manifest sent to European ministers on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministers, gathered in the Council of the EU, are in the process of discussing a new EU telecom law as proposed by the European Commission and the European Parliament that contains clauses on net neutrality and roaming. The Parliament in April last year &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.idg.com.au/article/542046/eu_votes_net_neutrality_into_law_abolishes_mobile_roaming_charges/&quot;&gt;voted to enshrine net neutrality in EU law, so that all traffic would be treated equally and without discrimination&lt;/a&gt;. However, the Council is trying to get some traffic discrimination back into the draft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-resolution-on-ttip</id>
      <title>European Parliament resolution on TTIP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-resolution-on-ttip" />
      <updated>2015-03-02T21:10:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament is going to adopt a Resolution on TTIP. A resolution is a political statement which does not have binding effects. However, a strong resolution from the Parliament could be a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Committee on International Trade (INTA) is in charge of the dossier and it will be guided by Opinions from 14 other Committees before it submits its report to Plenary (vote scheduled 18-21 May).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-summary-on-net-neutrality-in-europe</id>
      <title>EDRi summary on net neutrality in Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-summary-on-net-neutrality-in-europe" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:51:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the US FCC’s ruling on net neutrality, what is going on in Europe?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September 2013, the European Commission produced a badly drafted, incoherent “&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/connected-continent-legislative-package&quot;&gt;Telecoms Single Market Regulation&lt;/a&gt;”, which included proposals that claimed to support net neutrality, but which would actually destroy it. In March, 2014, the European Parliament adopted its first reading of that proposal, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://edri.org/european-parliament-leads-world-open-internet-vote/&quot;&gt;closing the loopholes in the badly written text&lt;/a&gt;. This improved text was supported by a big majority in the Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, the third institution in the EU framework, the Council of the European Union (made up of Member State Ministers) is about to adopt its position. After almost exactly a year of discussions, the Council has deleted most of the elements of the badly-written, badly-planned Regulation, leaving just the parts on net neutrality and roaming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Council’s draft &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-6405-2015-INIT/en/pdf&quot;&gt;(pdf)*&lt;/a&gt;, discussed on 27 February at Working Group level, will be finalised next Wednesday by Member State Representatives. As a result of extensive pressure from the large Member States (especially Spain), loopholes that would undermine net neutrality have been re-inserted.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europol-and-security-vendors-disrupt-massive-ramnit-botnet</id>
      <title>Europol and security vendors disrupt massive Ramnit botnet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europol-and-security-vendors-disrupt-massive-ramnit-botnet" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T15:09:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;European law enforcement agencies seized command-and-control servers used by Ramnit, a malware program that steals online banking credentials, FTP passwords, session cookies and personal files from victims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ramnit started out in 2010 as a computer worm capable of infecting EXE, DLL, HTM, and HTML files. However, over time it evolved into an information-stealing Trojan that’s distributed in a variety of ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ramnit is capable of hijacking online banking sessions, stealing session cookies which can then be used to access accounts on various sites, copying sensitive files from hard drives, giving attackers remote access to infected computers and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-joins-letter-citing-impact-of-sanctions-in-crimea-on-free</id>
      <title>Access joins letter citing impact of sanctions in Crimea on free expression and digital security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-joins-letter-citing-impact-of-sanctions-in-crimea-on-free" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:03:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Access joined EFF, Global Voices Advocacy, New America’s Open Technology Institute, and Ferrari &amp;amp; Associates, P.C. in a letter calling for the OFAC—the agency charged with enforcing the sanctions—to issue a general license that would protect internet users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Crimea sanctions require American technology firms, including Google, to stop updating software, to terminate small business applications, to shut down web hosting accounts, and to deny other services to users they believe are located in the affected region. Journalists, human rights defenders, and ordinary people living in Crimea – or even just traveling there – depend on a variety of information services, software, and hardware that are covered by these sanctions. The sanctions add barriers for information technology, drastically impacting free expression and privacy, and only contribute to the isolation and instability in the region. Not only are basic personal communications tools such as email and cryptography software impacted, but Google has stopped updating its popular Chrome browser in the region. This means that computer security is threatened by the blocking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-mustnt-backtrack-on-its-support-of-encryption-and-rejecti</id>
      <title>Europe mustn’t backtrack on its support of encryption and rejection of surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-mustnt-backtrack-on-its-support-of-encryption-and-rejecti" />
      <updated>2015-02-13T23:44:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julia Reda: Without &lt;strong&gt;cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;, every email you send and every word you type into a form on a website can easily be intercepted, read and even modified.&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Encryption&amp;nbsp;is essential to protect the integrity of the communications of individuals and businesses in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And in the light of the abject failure&amp;nbsp;of the&amp;nbsp;European Union to&amp;nbsp;stop the &lt;strong&gt;mass surveillance&lt;/strong&gt; of its people politically, it is&amp;nbsp;the best available (though unsatisfactory)&amp;nbsp;way to&amp;nbsp;safeguard our rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/isds-one-month-after-the-results-of-the-public-consultation</id>
      <title>ISDS – one month after the results of the public consultation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/isds-one-month-after-the-results-of-the-public-consultation" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:26:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;National sovereignty of the EU Member States and the rule of law would be endangered if Investor-State Dispute Settlement (ISDS) was part of the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP). Respondents to the public consultation conducted by the European Commission (EC) between March and July 2014 made it clear that they oppose ISDS, but the Commission doesn’t seem to be taking their opinion into account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 13 January 2015 the EC presented the results of the public consultation on ISDS. A month later, the Commission’s strategy seems to be a quiet but strong defence of ISDS.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-internet-firms-to-hand-over-encryption-keys</id>
      <title>EU wants internet firms to hand over encryption keys</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-internet-firms-to-hand-over-encryption-keys" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:37:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A top EU official wants internet and telecommunication companies to hand over encryption keys to police and spy agencies as part of a wider crackdown on terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU’s counter-terrorism co-ordinator Gilles de Kerchove, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statewatch.org/news/2015/jan/eu-council-ct-ds-1035-15.pdf&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; leaked by London-based civil liberties group Statewatch, says the European Commission should come up with rules that require the firms to help national governments snoop on possible suspects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/calls-for-isps-to-filter-content-could-be-illegal-eu-council-doc</id>
      <title>Calls for ISPs to filter content could be illegal, EU council documents suggest</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/calls-for-isps-to-filter-content-could-be-illegal-eu-council-doc" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:45:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week justice ministers from across the European Union called on ISPs to conduct voluntary censorship of online content—but documents in preparation for a meeting of telecoms ministers suggest such a move could be illegal. The documents, prepared by the Latvian presidency of the Council of the EU, note that calls to allow Internet service providers to block or filter content in the “public interest” as part of a proposed net neutrality law could violate privacy laws that protect the confidentiality of communication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-establish-intergroup-on-the-digital-agenda-for-europe</id>
      <title>MEPs establish Intergroup on the Digital Agenda for Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-establish-intergroup-on-the-digital-agenda-for-europe" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:07:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The intergroup on the Digital Agenda is an informal network of Members of European Parliament, cross-party and cross-nationality, who are interested in digital technologies and in how they can benefit society. “We recognise the profound impact that digital technologies have on the lives of people. We wish to take an active role in shaping that impact and smart policies by improving the knowledge of the functioning and impact of technologies,” says Schaake (ALDE). Weidenholzer (S&amp;amp;D) adds: “The Digital Single Market offers great opportunities. This intergroup will strive for policies that realise the potential while ensuring the privacy and data protection rights of European citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-message-on-strengthening-internet-governance</id>
      <title>Geneva message on strengthening Internet Governance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-message-on-strengthening-internet-governance" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T20:29:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Geneva Internet Conference outcome document has been published.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-proposed-trade-secrets-directive-risks-eu-free-speec</id>
      <title>Open Letter: Proposed trade secrets directive risks EU free speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-proposed-trade-secrets-directive-risks-eu-free-speec" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:35:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Quadrature du Net signs an open letter written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://haieurope.org/&quot;&gt;Health Action International Europe&lt;/a&gt; against the directive&#039;s project on trade secrets. Initiated by the business community, put forward by the Member States and the European Commission, it gives the possibility for private companies to sue any person that &quot;unlawfully acquires, uses or discloses&quot; the &quot;trade secrets&quot;. Whistleblowers are poorly protected in this text, the directive creates a judiciary insecurity as it will dissuade from leaking from private companies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/two-meps-votes-againts-closed-sessions-on-safe-harbour</id>
      <title>Two MEPs voted againts closed sessions on Safe Harbour</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/two-meps-votes-againts-closed-sessions-on-safe-harbour" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:18:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eu Observer reports that MEP German Cornelia Ernst along with Dutch liberal Sophie In&#039;t Veld voted to suspend the so-called in-camera session on Safe Harbour. In-camera sessions are not open to the public. It also means MEPs are under threat of sanctions should they discuss the issue outside the room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Safe Harbour is enforced by the US Federal Trade Commission and is supposed to ensure US firms follow EU data protection laws when processing the personal data of EU citizens. Last November, the former EU justice commissioner Viviane Reding published 13 recommendations that the Americans needed to implement in order to keep the agreement viable. The commission official, invited to update the MEPs on the negotiations, revealed that Washington has an issue with three of the 13 recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;display: none !important; &quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-wants-an-agreement-on-pnr</id>
      <title>European commissioner wants an agreement on PNR</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-wants-an-agreement-on-pnr" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:40:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament recently&amp;nbsp;voted in favour of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/news-room/content/20141121IPR79818/html/MEPs-refer-EU-Canada-air-passenger-data-deal-to-the-EU-Court-of-Justice&quot;&gt; resolution&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to refer the EU-Canada agreement on PNR to the Court of Justice to deliver an opinion of its compliance with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:C:2010:083:0389:0403:en:PDF&quot;&gt; Charter of Fundamental Rights&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;After this vote, members of the European Parliament and digital rights activists expected the legislative debate on the EU PNR directive to be postponed until the CJEU’s assessment was released. Unfortunately, Commissioner Avramopoulos decided not to wait for the opinion and signaled his desire to quickly reach an agreement on the 2011 directive. To the surprise of many Parliamentarians at the hearing,&amp;nbsp;the Home Affairs Commissioner said the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2014/04/11/a-closer-look-at-eu-courts-ruling-and-what-it-means-for-the-future-of-data-&quot;&gt; landmark CJEU&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ruling on data retention was “&lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_SPEECH-14-2351_en.htm&quot;&gt;a different scheme than the PNR&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-is-critiszing-the-eu-approach-on-net-neutrality</id>
      <title>EDRi critics the EU approach on net neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-is-critiszing-the-eu-approach-on-net-neutrality" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:55:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, the European Parliament had a strong position on net neutrality after adopting its first reading of the Telecoms Single Market Regulation in April. Meanwhile, the Council does not have an agreed position on the subject. Also, since the beginning of November, the new European Commission has taken office, with “better regulation” at the centre of its stated priorities. However, despite the efforts of the Parliament to improve the previous Commission&#039;s net neutrality proposals, there are persistent rumours that the new Commission may withdraw it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDRi has re-launched their campaign platform savetheinternet.eu and they ask everyone to play their part. They also wrote to the Council of the EU and issued a press release.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-as-a-global-hub-for-internet-governance</id>
      <title>Geneva as a global hub for Internet Governance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/geneva-as-a-global-hub-for-internet-governance" />
      <updated>2015-04-14T20:25:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the Geneva Internet Conference (17-19 November) organised by the Geneva Internet Platform, media reports highlighted the role of Geneva as a global hub for IG.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-andrus-ansip-backs-net-neutrality-principl</id>
      <title>European Commissioner Andrus Ansip backs net neutrality principle</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-andrus-ansip-backs-net-neutrality-principl" />
      <updated>2014-10-08T11:26:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU commissioner-designate and vice-president Andrus Ansip told MEPs he backs robust net neutrality rules.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-ngos-and-industry-join-forces-in-an-open-letter-t</id>
      <title>Net neutrality: NGOs and industry join forces in an open letter to EU ministers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-ngos-and-industry-join-forces-in-an-open-letter-t" />
      <updated>2014-10-08T12:29:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EDRi together with several NGOs, consumer groups and industry representatives sent an open letter to the Council of the European Union, calling for Telecoms ministers to support strong net neutrality rules in the EU. The Council is currently reviewing the proposal of the Telecoms Single Market Regulation, &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://edri.org/european-parliament-leads-world-open-internet-vote/&quot;&gt;voted on by the European Parliament in April&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/defending-the-open-internet</id>
      <title>Neelie kroes speech for IGF - Defending the open internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/defending-the-open-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:25:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;A_Standard__35__20_Normal&quot;&gt;NETMundial has established a solid foundation and we now need to follow through in putting the multistakeholder model on much sounder footing. We need to invest and build a governance structure for the Internet that people can trust! Trust, trust, trust is the key.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/speech-a-transatlantic-digital-single-market</id>
      <title>Speech - A transatlantic digital single market?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/speech-a-transatlantic-digital-single-market" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T13:34:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;A_Standard__35__20_Normal&quot;&gt;The EU is all about bringing down barriers: barriers to movement, to trade, to opportunity. And that needs to continue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;A_Standard__35__20_Normal&quot;&gt;The evidence shows that – within the EU alone – a digital single market could be worth 4% of GDP; that&#039;s on average an extra 1500 dollars a year pocket of each of our half a billion citizens. Make that digital single market transatlantic – and the benefits are there to see: for innovation, for prosperity, for freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fighting-for-a-free-and-open-internet</id>
      <title>Fighting for a free and open internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fighting-for-a-free-and-open-internet" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T12:07:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;A__35__20_Normal_P4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T4&quot;&gt;Access to internet is critical for fundamental freedoms and economic development. Continued access to a free and open internet depends on effective governance.&lt;/span&gt; In the wake of large-scale internet surveillance and reduced trust in the internet, governance of the internet must become more transparent, accountable and inclusive. 2014 is a critical year for global internet governance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-position-for-internet-governance-forum-2014</id>
      <title>European Commission position for Internet Governance Forum 2014, Istanbul 2-5 Sept</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-position-for-internet-governance-forum-2014" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T12:03:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ministers and Internet leaders including &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NeelieKroesEU&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;@NeelieKroesEU&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;A__T1&quot;&gt;will discuss the theme &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T2&quot;&gt;Connecting Continents for Enhanced Multi-stakeholder Internet Governance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T1&quot;&gt;&quot;. The 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T3&quot;&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T1&quot;&gt; IGF will also address topics raised at the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netmundial.br/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T8&quot;&gt;NETmundial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T1&quot;&gt; conference in Brazil earlier this year, including net neutrality, the role and responsibilities of different stakeholders, jurisdiction issues and the application of Internet governance principles. IGF participants will also respond to the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://netmundial.br/netmundial-multistakeholder-statement/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T10&quot;&gt;NETmundial statement&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;A__T1&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-eu-commission-wants-to-exchange-views-with-civil-society-in</id>
      <title>EDRi: EU Commission wants to exchange views with civil society in preparation of the IGF – we want your input!</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-eu-commission-wants-to-exchange-views-with-civil-society-in" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T13:04:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In preparation of the next &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://edri.org/%20http://www.intgovforum.org/cms/component/content/article?id=1557:2014&quot;&gt;Internet Governance Forum (IGF),&lt;/a&gt; which will be held in Istanbul on 2-5 September 2014, the European Commission organises an exchange views with civil society and invited us to participate in a webinar on 7 August. The IGF is a platform where activists, industry, academics and policy-makers discuss and develop solutions to Internet governance problems.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
