<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/DE/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in DE</title>
  <updated>2018-02-28T13:13:18+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-to-rule-on-enforceability-of-german-press-publishers-right</id>
      <title>CJEU to rule on enforceability of German press publishers&#039; right</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-to-rule-on-enforceability-of-german-press-publishers-right" />
      <updated>2017-05-19T23:43:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, Germany adopted a new neighbouring right over news content and in favour of press publishers (Leistungsschutzrecht für Presseverlege, LSR). The newly created sections 87f, 87g and 87h of the German Copyright Act provide for the exclusive right of press publishers to exploit their contents commercially for one year, thus preventing search engines and news aggregators from displaying excerpts from newspaper articles without paying a fee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the latest development in relation to the neighbouring right in favour of press publishers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.berlin.de/gerichte/presse/pressemitteilungen-der-ordentlichen-gerichtsbarkeit/2017/pressemitteilung.589394.php&quot;&gt;today&#039;s decision&lt;/a&gt; of the Landgericht Berlin to make a reference to the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) in the context of litigation between the collecting society responsible to collect royalties in favour of publishers and Google, to receiving guidance on the actual enforceability of the German press publishers&#039; right.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coalition-agreement-of-cducsu-and-spd-asks-to-consider-modern-wa</id>
      <title>Coalition agreement of CDU/CSU and SPD asks to consider modern ways of IPR utilization and ancillary copyright for press publishers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/coalition-agreement-of-cducsu-and-spd-asks-to-consider-modern-wa" />
      <updated>2018-02-28T13:13:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The coalition agreement of CDU/CSU and SPD, who could form the next German government, includes some considerations on how the IPR legislation should be developed in the EU. In particular, the agreement suggests an ancillary copyright for press publishers, as well as regulations to cover modern ways of IPR utilization. However, it remains unclear which forms exactly shall be tackled. In addition, a national strategy to strengthen Open Access shall be developed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-opposition-calls-for-abolition-of-online-hate-speech-law-1</id>
      <title>German opposition calls for abolition of online hate speech law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-opposition-calls-for-abolition-of-online-hate-speech-law-1" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:13:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Germany’s opposition parties on Sunday called for the abolition of a new law that aims to rid social media of hate speech, saying it was wrong for private companies to be making decisions about whether posts are unlawful. The legislation, which came into force on Jan. 1, can impose fines of up to 50 million euros ($60.1 million) on sites that fail to remove hate speech promptly, raising fears that Twitter, Facebook and other social media platforms could block more content than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-hate-speech-law-tries-to-regulate-facebook-and-others-wil</id>
      <title>German ‘hate-speech’ law tries to regulate Facebook and others - will it work?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-hate-speech-law-tries-to-regulate-facebook-and-others-wil" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T16:42:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;In September 2017, a law with the euphonious name ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzer.de/s1.htm?a=1&amp;amp;g=NetzDG&quot;&gt;Netzwerkdurchsetzungsgesetz&lt;/a&gt;’ (‘network enforcement law’) was adopted in Germany. Its goal is to force social networks to remove hate speech and certain other unlawful content within 24 hours in obvious cases, otherwise within 7 days upon being notified. The transition period ended on 31 December 2017 - meaning the new rules can now be enforced. Failure to delete content within the given deadlines can result in heavy administrative fines of up to EUR 50m.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-bgh-asks-cjeu-what-a-quotation-is-only-unaltered-reprod</id>
      <title>German court asks CJEU what a &#039;quotation&#039; is: only unaltered reproductions or also something else?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-bgh-asks-cjeu-what-a-quotation-is-only-unaltered-reprod" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:15:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;Germany&#039;s Federal Court of Justice has referred a new copyright case to the Court of Justice of the European Union: &lt;a href=&quot;http://juris.bundesgerichtshof.de/cgi-bin/rechtsprechung/document.py?Gericht=bgh&amp;amp;Art=pm&amp;amp;Datum=2017&amp;amp;Sort=3&amp;amp;nr=79067&amp;amp;pos=0&amp;amp;anz=124&quot;&gt;I ZR 228/15 - Reformistischer Aufbruch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;According to the relevant press release (and its Google Translate translation), similarly to the two other references mentioned above, also this new case seeks guidance on – among other things – the interplay between copyright protection and the protection of third-party rights and freedoms (including freedom of the press), as well as the proper interpretation of relevant exceptions in the InfoSoc Directive – in this case, news reporting and quotation within, respectively, Article 5(3)(c) and (d) of the InfoSoc Directive.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-court-orders-google-to-stop-linking-to-lumen-database</id>
      <title>German court orders Google to stop linking to Lumen Database</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-court-orders-google-to-stop-linking-to-lumen-database" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:13:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;A German court has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lhr-law.de/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Beschluss-OLG-M%C3%9C-Lumen-geschw.pdf&quot;&gt;issued an injunction&lt;/a&gt; against Google, preventing it from linking to Lumen in the context of a claim for defamation.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-for-copyright-regarding-science-published</id>
      <title>Draft law for copyright regarding science published</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-law-for-copyright-regarding-science-published" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T18:19:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A draft law for adjusting regulations in the copyright law regarding science was published by the Ministry of Justice. The law contains a list of conditions under which a protected work might be, for instance, copied for scientific purposes. A general clause, as it was proposed before, was not implemented in the draft law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/liability-for-links-first-decisions-after-the-ecj-judgement</id>
      <title>Liability for links: First decisions after the ECJ judgement</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/liability-for-links-first-decisions-after-the-ecj-judgement" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T18:14:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A decision of the district court Hamburg caused legal uncertainty by following the arguments of the latest ECJ judgement: According to the district court, a person operating a website that contains a link to illegal content is liable for this content as long as he somehow intents to realize a profit by running the website. This would potentially affect all companies and freelancer running own websites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gemas-current-practice-to-give-music-publishers-a-lump-sum-share</id>
      <title>GEMAs current practice to give music publishers a lump-sum share is illegal according to the Court of Appeal in Berlin</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gemas-current-practice-to-give-music-publishers-a-lump-sum-share" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T18:18:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Court of Appeal in Berlin has decided that GEMA is not entitled to reduce the royalties attributable to the artists as authors to “publisher shares”. The current practice of GEMA to give music publishers a lump-sum share of the proceeds from the copyrights is therefore illegal.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-directive-201426eu-transposed-into-national-law</id>
      <title>Germany: Directive 2014/26/EU transposed into national law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/germany-directive-201426eu-transposed-into-national-law" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T18:22:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new law transposing directive 2014/26/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 26 February 2014 on collective management of copyright and related rights and multi-territorial licensing of rights in musical works for online use in the internal market into national law went into force on 24 May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-leistungsschutzrecht-used-to-prohibit-publication-of-copy</id>
      <title>German Leistungsschutzrecht used to prohibit publication of copyright infringement evidence</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-leistungsschutzrecht-used-to-prohibit-publication-of-copy" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T18:04:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a German first court decision about Leistungsschutzrecht (also known as Lex-Google), a copyright holder was prohibited to use a screenshot as evidence for copyright violation&lt;span id=&quot;result_box&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;span title=&quot;dem das Gericht der Verfügungsbeklagten untersagt, einen bestimmten Screenshot öffentlich zugänglich zu machen, der 2 Artikelanrisse nebst Überschriften enthielt.&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-where-the-good-samaritan-meets-the-trojan-horse</id>
      <title>TTIP: where the Good Samaritan meets the Trojan Horse</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-where-the-good-samaritan-meets-the-trojan-horse" />
      <updated>2014-09-15T16:33:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU and US are currently negotiating a Trans-Atlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP). The US negotiator, the United States Trade Representative, is reported to be soliciting support for inclusion of provisions from Article 230 of the Communications Decency Act (CDA) in TTIP and other trade agreements being negotiated by the US. So far so good – the CDA creates liability protections for internet intermediaries, thereby reducing the risk of restrictive measures being imposed by them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
