<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/BE/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in BE</title>
  <updated>2017-09-14T17:31:21+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-to-keep-watch-on-belgiums-rights-harming-dispropor</id>
      <title>EU Commission to keep watch on Belgium’s rights-harming, disproportionate Passenger Name Record system</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-to-keep-watch-on-belgiums-rights-harming-dispropor" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:29:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Access Now received a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2017/02/Commission-Letter-Belgium-PNR.pdf&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; from the European Commission regarding the organization&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/access-now-notifies-european-commission-belgiums-plan-pnr-system-breaches-eu-law/&quot;&gt;notification&lt;/a&gt; in November that Belgium’s plan for a Passenger Name Record (PNR) system breaches EU law. Since then the Belgian Parliament has adopted its proposed PNR law, despite the lack of evidence to show it will help stop crime or terrorism. This has set in motion what is essentially a rights-harming exercise in security theatre.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-wins-privacy-case-against-belgian-data-protection-autho</id>
      <title>Facebook wins privacy case against Belgian data protection authority</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-wins-privacy-case-against-belgian-data-protection-autho" />
      <updated>2017-09-14T17:31:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Belgian data protection authority on Wednesday lost a legal battle with Facebook in which it sought to stop the social network from tracking the online activities of non-Facebook users in Belgium who visit the social network’s pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Belgian Privacy Commission said the Brussels Appeals Court had dismissed its case on the grounds that the regulator has no jurisdiction over Facebook Inc, which has its European headquarters in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-court-orders-facebook-to-stop-tracking-non-members</id>
      <title>Belgian court orders Facebook to stop tracking non-members</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-court-orders-facebook-to-stop-tracking-non-members" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:04:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Judge threatens social network with fines of €250,000 a day over ‘datr’ cookie, which records visits to many websites whether or not user has Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Belgian court on Monday gave Facebook 48 hours to stop tracking internet users who do not have accounts with the social network or risk fines of up to €250,000 a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook said it would appeal against the order, which followed a case lodged by Belgium’s privacy watchdog in June saying the US company indiscriminately tracks internet users when they visit pages on the site or click “like” or “share”, even if they are not members.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-accused-of-spying-on-belgian-citizens-like-the-nsa-1</id>
      <title>Facebook accused of spying on Belgian citizens like the NSA</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-accused-of-spying-on-belgian-citizens-like-the-nsa-1" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T11:20:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/jun/15/belgium-facebook-court-privacy-breaches-ads&quot;&gt;Belgian Privacy Commission (BPC) brought a lawsuit against Facebook&lt;/a&gt; after accusing it of not complying with Belgian and European privacy law. In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/31/facebook-tracks-all-visitors-breaching-eu-law-report&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/may/15/facebook-must-stop-tracking-users-non-users-legal-action&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; the BPC detailed Facebook’s alleged breaches, including the tracking of non-users and logged-out Facebook users for advertising purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BPC is threatening Facebook with fine of €250,000 ($280,213) a day for failing to respond to its demands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-coalition-demands-suspension-of-the-ttip-negotiations</id>
      <title>Belgian coalition demands suspension of the TTIP negotiations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-coalition-demands-suspension-of-the-ttip-negotiations" />
      <updated>2015-07-03T02:03:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 26 June 2015, the Belgian EDRi member Liga voor Mensenrechten, together with a wide coalition of other Belgian human rights and consumer organisations, trade union confederations, and environmental and development NGOs, published a declaration asking for an immediate suspension of the negotiations for the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) that are currently ongoing between the United States (US) and the European Union (EU).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-privacy-watchdog-sues-facebook-1</id>
      <title>Belgian privacy watchdog sues Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-privacy-watchdog-sues-facebook-1" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:15:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Belgium&#039;s national privacy watchdog is taking US internet company Facebook to court, arguing that the way the social network website tracks the behaviour of both members and non-members is illegal under Belgian and European law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-constitutional-court-repeals-the-transposition-of-the-da</id>
      <title>Belgian Constitutional Court repeals the transposition of the data retention directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-constitutional-court-repeals-the-transposition-of-the-da" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:14:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following two actions for annulment brought independently, the Belgian Constitutional Court ruled yesterday against the mass collection of communications metadata. This ruling falls in line with a recent ruling from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) invalidating the directive behind Belgian law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-constitutional-court-repeals-the-transposition-of-the-data-r</id>
      <title>The Constitutional Court repeals the transposition of the data retention directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-constitutional-court-repeals-the-transposition-of-the-data-r" />
      <updated>2016-08-08T13:08:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following two actions for annulment brought independently, the Belgian Constitutional Court ruled yesterday against the mass collection of communications metadata. This ruling falls in line with a recent ruling from the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) invalidating the directive behind Belgian law.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-tramples-on-european-law</id>
      <title>Belgian Data Protection Authority&#039;s first recommendation on Facebook&#039;s privacy policy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-tramples-on-european-law" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T09:22:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the introduction of new worldwide terms of use by Facebook, a number of European privacy commissions started investigations. Facebook did not accept that it was bound by the national privacy legislation of Belgium, the Netherlands and Germany and it rejected their competence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 13 May the Belgian Privacy Commission adopted a first recommendation on Facebook. The document establishes that the Belgian Privacy Commission is competent and that Facebook disregards European and Belgian privacy legislation in several ways.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
