<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/FR/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in FR</title>
  <updated>2016-10-24T16:02:26+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-french-law-targeting-automated-image-referencing-service</id>
      <title>The new French law targeting &quot;automated image referencing services&quot;: does EU law allow it?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-french-law-targeting-automated-image-referencing-service" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T14:35:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Earlier this year France adopted&lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexte.do?cidTexte=JORFTEXT000032854341&amp;amp;dateTexte=&amp;amp;categorieLien=id&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Loi No 2016-925&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;freedom of creation, architecture and cultural heritage which - among other things - introduced&amp;nbsp;new provisions &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to regulate&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;exercise of the exclusive rights of reproduction and representation vis-à-vis automated image referencing services. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;As explained by Brad Spitz in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kluwercopyrightblog.com/2016/10/17/new-french-act-google-images-will-pay-royalties/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;published on the Kluwer Copyright Blog, &quot;the new provisions will apply to ‘automated image search services’, which&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichCodeArticle.do;jsessionid=3617E96425EC4111641600ED83CC2C57.tpdila12v_1?idArticle=LEGIARTI000032857367&amp;amp;cidTexte=LEGITEXT000006069414&amp;amp;dateTexte=20171017&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article L.136-1 IPC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;defines as any online public communication service that reproduces and makes available to the public for purposes of indexing and SEO, plastic, graphic or photographic works, collected in an automated way from online public communication services (i.e. internet websites). In other words, these provisions target search engine services like Google Images.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; Spitz also adds that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Article L.136-1 IPC&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;specifies that the images have to be ‘reproduced and made available’ by the image search services. This suggests that an act of reproduction is needed in order to trigger the entire mechanism envisaged by Loi No 2016-925. Lacking reproduction, no permission would be needed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;But: permission from whom?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Article 136-2(1) CPI answers that, by saying that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;he publication of a plastic artwork, graphic or photographic work by an online communication service will be now subject to the consent -&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;not&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;of authors - but rather one or more collecting societies appointed to this end by the French Ministry of Culture.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-mining-the-law-should-not-hinder-french-research</id>
      <title>Data mining: the law should not hinder French research</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-mining-the-law-should-not-hinder-french-research" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T15:16:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure copyright protection, current French law forbids scientists to reuse published scientific articles. The legislators risk heavily undermining public research by creating multiple legal hurdles to text and data mining. Unlike their counterparts abroad, copyright and databases laws do not allow French scientists to reuse scientific articles, even their own or those they purchased. Therefore it is imperative that the Digital Republic Bill takes this into consideration and allows for an exception to copyright laws that would enable and encourage text and data mining. This would enable the French research community to seize new scientific opportunities and would curtail researchers’ departure abroad.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/reconciling-digital-and-intellectual-property-issues</id>
      <title>Reconciling digital and intellectual property issues</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/reconciling-digital-and-intellectual-property-issues" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T16:02:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Within its study entitled “Intellectual property and digital transformation of the economy”, the National Institute of Intellectual Property compiled 18 articles by researchers and experts, contributing to the national debate in the context of emerging problems posed by big data, the internet of things, algorithms, 3D printers. The institute also suggests some future directions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-to-modify-its-intellectual-property-code</id>
      <title>France to Modify its Intellectual Property Code</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-to-modify-its-intellectual-property-code" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T16:55:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;French Minister of Culture Fleur Pellerin has presented a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.assemblee-nationale.fr/14/projets/pl2319.asp&quot;&gt;bill &lt;/a&gt;which would implement &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=celex:32011L0077&quot;&gt;Directive 2011/77/EU&lt;/a&gt; amending Directive 2006/116/EC on the term of protection of copyright and certain related rights, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2012:299:0005:0012:EN:PDF&quot;&gt;Directive 2012/28/EU&lt;/a&gt; on certain permitted uses of orphan works.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-to-follow-turkeys-lead-on-lawless-internet-censorship</id>
      <title>France to follow Turkey’s lead on lawless Internet censorship</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-to-follow-turkeys-lead-on-lawless-internet-censorship" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T17:00:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite many setbacks, bad publicity, budget cuts and a change of government, France is persisting with its Hadopi, a “three strikes law” and government agency to enforce copyright laws and fight online&amp;nbsp;“piracy”. Even more worrying, the country’s Minister of Culture is now making moves to curb online rights even further.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
