<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/ES/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in ES</title>
  <updated>2018-02-20T15:04:59+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-draft-of-the-spanish-digital-tax-bill-leaked-no-lessons-lear</id>
      <title>New draft of the Spanish Digital Tax bill leaked: no lessons learned</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-draft-of-the-spanish-digital-tax-bill-leaked-no-lessons-lear" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T05:06:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Association of Internet users publishes and discusses the new leaked draft of the Digital Tax bill (known as Canon Digital), that would amend the Intellectual Property Law, if approved. In the opinion of the authors, the new draft doubles down in hurtful practices, abiding to the will of the industry and hurting the consumers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-guardia-civil-blocks-access-to-23-webs-that-provided-mov</id>
      <title>Spanish Guardia Civil blocks access to 23 webs that provided movie downloads</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-guardia-civil-blocks-access-to-23-webs-that-provided-mov" />
      <updated>2018-02-20T15:04:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spanish Guardia Civil has announced an operation to block access to up to 23 websites that provided links to contents protected by copyright, including games, music, movies and TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-is-removed-from-the-us-content-piracy-blacklist-cultura-ho</id>
      <title>Spain is removed from the US content piracy blacklist</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-is-removed-from-the-us-content-piracy-blacklist-cultura-ho" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:57:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US Department of Commerce has published their annual &#039;301 Special Report&#039; that removes Spain from the content piracy watch list and recognizes Spanish efforts illegal digital contents.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-supreme-court-rejects-the-request-of-the-content-creator</id>
      <title>Spanish Supreme Court rejects the request of the content creators industry to be compensated for digital canon</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-supreme-court-rejects-the-request-of-the-content-creator" />
      <updated>2017-04-26T20:18:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After declaring illegal the allocation to the General Budget of the State of equitable compensation for private copying (aka &quot;digital canon&quot;), the Spanish Supreme Court rejects the request from the industry for 120 million euros.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-rules-immediate-closure-of-rojadirecta-website-el</id>
      <title>Spanish Court rules immediate closure of Rojadirecta website</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-rules-immediate-closure-of-rojadirecta-website-el" />
      <updated>2017-02-08T22:27:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Supreme Court of Justice has ruled the definitive closure of the website Rojadirecta, including all their domain names, after having agreed to the complete demands from plaintiff DTS (Canal +, today Movistar +) against Puerto 80 Projects, the company that manages and exploits the site offering links to pirated contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ruling maintains that Rojadirecta has violated the complainant&#039;s intellectual property rights through public communication of its broadcasts and transmissions. The court decision, which is not final since it can be appealed, also includes the right of the plaintiff to be compensated in the amount that is determined in a subsequent proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-rules-precautionary-closure-for-spanish-online-portal-roja</id>
      <title>Judge rules precautionary closure for Spanish online portal Rojadirecta</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/judge-rules-precautionary-closure-for-spanish-online-portal-roja" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T22:30:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After years of resistance, between lawsuits and trials, finally the Trading Court in A Coruña has ruled the precautionary closure of the online portal Rojadirecta, popular for offering links to unofficial broadcasts of football games and other sporting events.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-constitutional-court-suspends-adsl-tax</id>
      <title>Spanish Constitutional Court suspends ADSL tax</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-constitutional-court-suspends-adsl-tax" />
      <updated>2015-09-19T23:43:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Late last year the Parliament of Catalonia approved a tax for ADSL operators, charging 25 cents each per month and client. However, this afternoon the Constitutional Court has suspended this fee by admitting an appeal against the Central Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This rate was initially approved with the intention of getting funding for cultural dissemination and Catalan audiovisual productions. The motivation for suspending this decision is because of overlapping obligations as for VAT. This is not&amp;nbsp;the Constitutional Court&#039;s final decision on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-minister-of-culture-declares-war-against-piracy</id>
      <title>Spanish Minister of Culture declares war against piracy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-minister-of-culture-declares-war-against-piracy" />
      <updated>2015-09-10T13:42:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On September 9, 2015, the Ministry of Culture had a meeting with representatives of the Coalición de Creadores (an association publishing piracy studies) in order to study together with the industry what new copyright measures can be put in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More statistics and how the new Spanish Intellectual Property Law was implemented are available in Spanish &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xataka.com/legislacion-y-derechos/el-ministro-de-cultura-calma-a-las-entidades-de-gestion-con-cifras-antiguas-y-promesas-antidescargas?hs=true&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-new-spanish-copyright-reform</id>
      <title>A new Spanish copyright reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-new-spanish-copyright-reform" />
      <updated>2015-08-20T02:32:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new Spanish Minister of Education, Culture and Sports announced to make another reform of the Copyright Act. This &quot;partial&quot; reform intends to address the measures taken at the level of the European Union against downloads on peer-to-peer networks. In addition, the Minister also mentioned reform measures on how the Spanish films are financed, hoping to achieve &quot;greater transparency in financial management&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to this announcement, the minister showed statistics on the copyright enforcement measures taken by the Second Committee of the Intellectual Property. Prior to the Committee&#039;s establishment, there were 30 torrent portals among the 250 most visited websites in Spain. Now the numbers dropped to 13.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/legislative-changes-in-spain-after-the-ecj-ruling-svensson</id>
      <title>Legislative changes in Spain after the ECJ ruling Svensson</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/legislative-changes-in-spain-after-the-ecj-ruling-svensson" />
      <updated>2015-06-21T10:09:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the ECJ court decision and several reactions from the US (mentioned in the 301 report), there have been a series of legislative changes in Spain regarding managing links. The Sinde-Wert Committee was created to clarify whether links infringe intellectual property rights. Contrary to the national civil and criminal courts decisions so far, the Committee reached the conclusion that it does represent an infringement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-criminal-court-orders-hacker-to-pay-compensation-for-facil</id>
      <title>Spain: Criminal court orders hacker to pay compensation for facilitating downloading movies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-criminal-court-orders-hacker-to-pay-compensation-for-facil" />
      <updated>2015-04-08T13:40:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The hacker known as Triplorita was convicted for intellectual property infringement and has to pay 167,398 euros to Egeda company and 83,600 euros to Columbia Tristar Entertainment.&lt;span lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Between March 2009 and February 2010 he facilitated downloading copies of newly released movies in theaters.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-approves-new-intellectual-property-law</id>
      <title>Spain approves new Intellectual Property Law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-approves-new-intellectual-property-law" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:57:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Senate just approved the new Intellectual Property Law Reform, including the new AEDE tax in its 32.2 article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-passes-much-debated-intellectual-property-law</id>
      <title>Spain Passes Much-Debated Intellectual Property Law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-passes-much-debated-intellectual-property-law" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T15:07:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spain passed its Intellectual Property Law, with its hotly debated, so-called Google tax that allows for fines on aggregators that show snippets of content without paying for it. Critics of the law argue that in addition to the confusion of including private copy in the law, the wording on what constitutes as piracy is &quot;vague&quot; and &quot;weak,&quot; failing to offer a clear-cut definition to rule against sites that violate property rights. Additionally, Spain is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/spains-popular-piracy-sites-stop-685791&quot;&gt;altering its penal code&lt;/a&gt; to move more forcefully against copyright violation by closing down sites that link to illegal content.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-copyright-amendments-will-shakedown-news-sites-and-censo</id>
      <title>Spanish Copyright Amendments Will Shakedown News Sites and Censor the Web</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-copyright-amendments-will-shakedown-news-sites-and-censo" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T17:05:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;We&#039;ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/01/european-newspapers-seek-royalties-simply-linking-and-citing-news-content&quot;&gt;reported before&lt;/a&gt; on how news publishers in Germany and Ireland have demanded that Google pay royalties for the reproduction of news snippets and image thumbnails next to search results in its Google News product. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/article/2662716/techology-business/update--google-and-agence-france-presse-settle-lawsuit.html&quot;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/article/2662716/techology-business/update--google-and-agence-france-presse-settle-lawsuit.html&quot;&gt;Belgium&lt;/a&gt; publishers took this claim to the courts resulting in an eventual settlement from Google, whilst in Germany, lawmakers unwisely caved in and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/02/technology/german-copyright-law-targets-google-links.html?_r=1&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;passed legislation&lt;/a&gt; in 2013 to grant the special copyright-like rights in news snippets that the publishers had demanded.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
