<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/UK/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in UK</title>
  <updated>2018-07-14T21:09:49+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-fined-for-data-breaches-in-cambridge-analytica-scandal</id>
      <title>Facebook fined for data breaches in Cambridge Analytica scandal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-fined-for-data-breaches-in-cambridge-analytica-scandal" />
      <updated>2018-07-14T21:09:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Facebook is to be fined £500,000, the maximum amount possible, for its part in the Cambridge Analytica scandal, the information commissioner has announced. The fine is for two breaches of the Data Protection Act. The Information Commissioner’s Office concluded that Facebook failed to safeguard its users’ information and that it failed to be transparent about how that data was harvested by others.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-judges-may-be-asked-to-rule-on-legality-of-uk-surveillance-po-1</id>
      <title>EU judges may be asked to rule on legality of UK surveillance powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-judges-may-be-asked-to-rule-on-legality-of-uk-surveillance-po-1" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:09:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a fresh challenge that could impact the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/nov/19/extreme-surveillance-becomes-uk-law-with-barely-a-whimper&quot;&gt;Investigatory Powers Act&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign group Privacy International has argued in court on Monday that interception of social media that is not targeted and subject to sufficient safeguards is forbidden by a previous European judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-security-agencies-unlawfully-collected-data-for-17-years-cour</id>
      <title>UK security agencies unlawfully collected data for 17 years, court rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-security-agencies-unlawfully-collected-data-for-17-years-cour" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:10:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;British security agencies have secretly and unlawfully collected massive volumes of confidential personal data, including financial information, on citizens for more than a decade, senior judges have ruled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investigatory powers tribunal, which is the only court that hears complaints against MI5, MI6 and GCHQ, said the security services operated an illegal regime to collect vast amounts of communications data, tracking individual phone and web use and other confidential personal information, without adequate safeguards or supervision for 17 years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/labour-bought-data-on-1m-mothers-and-their-children</id>
      <title>Labour bought data on 1m mothers and their children</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/labour-bought-data-on-1m-mothers-and-their-children" />
      <updated>2018-07-14T21:07:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The British Labour party bought data on more than 1 million new and expectant mothers and their children from a leading baby club ahead of the 2017 general election. The Information Commissioner’s Office has issued a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ico.org.uk/media/2259363/emmas-diary-noi-redacted.pdf&quot;&gt;notice of intent&lt;/a&gt; to fine Emma’s Diary £140,000 for the infraction.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-loses-right-to-be-forgotten-case-bbc-news</id>
      <title>Google loses &#039;right to be forgotten&#039; case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-loses-right-to-be-forgotten-case-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:05:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A businessman fighting for the &quot;right to be forgotten&quot; has won a UK High Court action against Google. The man, who has not been named due to reporting restrictions surrounding the case, wanted search results about a past crime he had committed removed from the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-uk-news-the-g</id>
      <title>UK mass digital surveillance regime ruled unlawful</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-mass-digital-surveillance-regime-ruled-unlawful-uk-news-the-g" />
      <updated>2018-02-12T11:11:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The court of appeal ruling on Tuesday said the powers in the Data Retention and Investigatory Powers Act 2014, did not restrict the accessing of confidential personal phone and web browsing records to investigations of serious crime, and allowed police and other public bodies to authorise their own access without adequate oversight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-to-decide-whether-uk-mass-surveillance-revealed-b</id>
      <title>European Court to decide whether UK mass surveillance revealed by Snowden violates human rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-to-decide-whether-uk-mass-surveillance-revealed-b" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T17:36:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;British spy agencies are under scrutiny in a landmark court case challenging the legality of top-secret mass surveillance programs revealed in documents leaked by whistleblower Edward Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A panel of 10 judges at the European Court of Human Rights in Strasbourg held a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.echr.coe.int/Pages/home.aspx?p=hearings&amp;amp;w=5817013_07112017&amp;amp;language=en&quot;&gt;hearing&lt;/a&gt; to examine the U.K. government’s large-scale electronic spying operations, following three separate challenges brought by a dozen human rights groups, including Amnesty International, Privacy International, the American Civil Liberties Union, Big Brother Watch, the Open Rights Group, and the Irish Council for Civil Liberties.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-releases-statement-of-intent-describing-new-data-p</id>
      <title>UK government releases statement of intent describing new data protection bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-releases-statement-of-intent-describing-new-data-p" />
      <updated>2017-08-11T16:17:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK has released a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/635900/2017-08-07_DP_Bill_-_Statement_of_Intent.pdf&quot;&gt;statement of intent&lt;/a&gt; describing a forthcoming bill that would make major revisions to the the country&#039;s data protection law. The new rules would follow the EU&#039;s General Data Protection Regulation by strengthening rules for obtaining consent, making it easier for consumers to withdraw consent, and improving consumers&#039; ability to access, move, and remove data about themselves. The bill would also expand the definition of &quot;personal data&quot; to include DNA and IP addresses and would make it a crime to re-identify individuals from anonymized data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-plans-age-verification-for-porn-websites-from-2018-bbc-news</id>
      <title>UK plans age verification for porn websites from 2018</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-plans-age-verification-for-porn-websites-from-2018-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2017-07-17T14:11:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;People in the UK will have to prove they are 18 before being allowed to access pornography websites from next year (2018), the government is to announce.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-will-the-uk-election-mean-for-online-privacy</id>
      <title>What will the UK election mean for online privacy?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/what-will-the-uk-election-mean-for-online-privacy" />
      <updated>2017-06-05T13:56:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/what-will-the-uk-election-mean-for-online-privacy-78769&quot;&gt;recent Manchester attacks&lt;/a&gt;, this article tries to map how are the main UK-wide political parties propose to tackle online security and privacy after the 2017 general election.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-pushes-for-companies-to-weaken-encryption</id>
      <title>UK government pushes for companies to weaken encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-pushes-for-companies-to-weaken-encryption" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T18:39:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The terrorist attack in Manchester on 22 May has led to a relaunch of the encryption debate in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In December 2016, the UK parliament passed the Investigatory Powers Act. This wide-ranging surveillance law gives government ministers the power to issue Technical Capability Notices (TCNs), which can force companies to modify their products.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-proposes-porn-viewing-id-numbers</id>
      <title>UK government proposes porn-viewing ID numbers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-proposes-porn-viewing-id-numbers" />
      <updated>2016-10-20T14:55:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government wants to stop people under 18 from looking at pornography and it proposes to make all the porn sites operating in Britain implement age-verification systems.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spy-agencies-broke-privacy-rules-says-tribunal-bbc-news</id>
      <title>UK spy agencies broke privacy rules says tribunal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spy-agencies-broke-privacy-rules-says-tribunal-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2016-10-18T14:13:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UK spy agencies broke privacy rules by collecting large amounts of UK citizens&#039; data without adequate oversight, the Investigatory Powers Tribunal has ruled.&amp;nbsp;The ruling said some data collection did not comply with the European Convention on Human Rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-police-listened-in-to-9-percent-more-calls-last-year</id>
      <title>UK police listened in to 9 percent more calls last year</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-police-listened-in-to-9-percent-more-calls-last-year" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T13:02:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.K. government has published a report on the staggering scale of surveillance in the country last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iocco-uk.info/docs/56850%20HC%20255%20ICCO%20Web%20only.pdf&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt;, compiled by the Interception of Communications Commissioner&#039;s Office (IOCCO), covers the surveillance activities of the U.K.&#039;s three main intelligence agencies (MI5, the Secret Intelligence Service, and GCHQ, the Government Communications Headquarters), the tax authority, and a number of police forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It shows that warrants for the interception of communications rose 9 percent&amp;nbsp;and that authorities continue to collect communications metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-report-finds-rising-digital-privacy-concerns</id>
      <title>UK report finds rising digital privacy concerns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-report-finds-rising-digital-privacy-concerns" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T19:15:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive study of Brits’ usage of and attitudes to digital media, conducted annually by telecoms watchdog Ofcom, suggests there is growing concern among web and app users about the privacy of their personal data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spy-agencies-have-collected-bulk-personal-data-since-1990s</id>
      <title>UK spy agencies have collected bulk personal data since 1990s</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spy-agencies-have-collected-bulk-personal-data-since-1990s" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T19:18:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A cache of more than 100 memorandums, forms and policy papers, &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;https://privacyinternational.org/node/843&quot;&gt;obtained by Privacy International&lt;/a&gt; during a legal challenge over the lawfulness of surveillance, demonstrates that collection of bulk data has been going on for longer than previously disclosed while public knowledge of the process was suppressed for more than 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/investigatory-powers-bill-lacks-clarity-mp-warns</id>
      <title>Investigatory powers bill lacks clarity, MP warns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/investigatory-powers-bill-lacks-clarity-mp-warns" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T13:17:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The government’s investigatory powers bill lacks clarity and is sowing confusion among tech firms about the extent to which “internet connection records” will be collected, a parliamentary select committee has warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The highly critical report by the House of Commons science and technology committee says there are widespread doubts about key definitions in the legislation, “not to mention the definability, of a number of the terms”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-open-rights-group-crowdfunds-mass-surveillance-explainer</id>
      <title>UK Open Rights Group crowdfunds mass surveillance explainer</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-open-rights-group-crowdfunds-mass-surveillance-explainer" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:51:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Civil rights campaign organisation, the Open Rights Group, is running a crowdfunding campaign to try to raise £20,000 to fund a challenge to the U.K. government’s own massive PR machine which is in the midst of driving the draft Investigatory Powers bill through Parliament and onto the statute books this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The draft IP bill, presented to parliamentary in November — and now being interrogated by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/11/27/ipbill-committee-rubberstamp/&quot;&gt;joint select committee of MPs and Peers&lt;/a&gt;, due to report next month — is the U.K. government’s attempt to update and crystalize the law on surveillance powers in the post-Snowden era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-the-uk-investigatory-powers-bill-will-affect-internet-servic</id>
      <title>How the UK Investigatory Powers Bill will affect Internet Service Providers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-the-uk-investigatory-powers-bill-will-affect-internet-servic" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:02:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Rights Group explains that the Investigatory Powers Bill would force ISPs to create and retain even more data about their customers. Moreover, the terms of the Bill mean that ISPs would be prevented from discussing orders they receive the Home Secretary. At the same time, the police and other government departments would use a “filter” that would analyse data to identify what may be of interest.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-statement-against-uk-surveillance-bill</id>
      <title>Apple statement against UK surveillance bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-statement-against-uk-surveillance-bill" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:24:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Guardian reports that Apple has submitted a formal statement to the bill committee working on a new complex and controversial surveillance law in the U.K. The submission was just released, and Apple is staying on course when it comes to privacy, saying that government backdoors could be used by anyone and weaken the security of hundreds of millions of devices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dont-spy-on-us-condemns-the-fast-tracking-of-uk-new-surveillance</id>
      <title>Don&#039;t Spy on Us condemns the fast-tracking of UK new surveillance legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dont-spy-on-us-condemns-the-fast-tracking-of-uk-new-surveillance" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:25:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The decision by the UK government to reduce parliamentary scrutiny of the Investigatory Powers Bill has been condemned by civil liberties groups and technology experts. The draft Bill and explanatory notes, which run to 299 pages, will now only receive three weeks scrutiny in order to drive the legislation through parliament in the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-response-to-uk-draft-investigatory-powers-bill</id>
      <title>Open Rights Group response to UK draft Investigatory Powers Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-response-to-uk-draft-investigatory-powers-bill" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:31:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Rights Group has responded to the publication of the UK&#039;s proposed new surveillance law, the draft Investigatory Powers Bill.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-investigatory-powers-bill-now-published</id>
      <title>UK Investigatory Powers Bill now published</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-investigatory-powers-bill-now-published" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:28:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government has published the draft Investigatory Powers Bill which will decide the surveillance powers that the police and intelligence have for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-revised-version-of-gchq-activities</id>
      <title>Open Rights Group revised version of GCHQ activities</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-revised-version-of-gchq-activities" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:34:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Rights Group has revised and republished a report taking into account the information from the ISC, Anderson and RUSI review. The report is divided in two sections; a technical review of the evidence (part one) and an analysis of the policy and legal considerations (part two). Because of its length, the report was published as an ebook.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-police-is-lobbying-for-mandatory-retention-of-browsing-histor</id>
      <title>UK police is lobbying for mandatory retention of browsing history</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-police-is-lobbying-for-mandatory-retention-of-browsing-histor" />
      <updated>2015-10-31T08:33:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The requirement that telecommunication firms retain the online browsing history of their customers for a 12 month period was a key feature of the so-called &lt;a draggable=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2003/mar/12/internet.comment&quot;&gt;“snooper’s charter”&lt;/a&gt; that was blocked by Liberal Democrats in the last parliament.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, UK internet providers may still be required to keep browsing data since senior police officers are lobbying the government for mandatory retention of internet connection records. Such a measure might re-appear in the investigatory powers bill which is due to be published next week.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-mass-surveillance-program-tracks-web-users-online-identi</id>
      <title>British mass surveillance program tracks web users’ online identities</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-mass-surveillance-program-tracks-web-users-online-identi" />
      <updated>2015-09-30T14:11:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The mass surveillance operation — code-named KARMA POLICE — was launched by British spies about seven years ago without any public debate or scrutiny. It was just one part of a giant global Internet spying apparatus built by the United Kingdom’s electronic eavesdropping agency, Government Communications Headquarters, or GCHQ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The revelations about the scope of the British agency’s surveillance are contained in documents obtained by The Intercept from National Security Agency whistleblower Edward Snowden. Previous reports based on the leaked files have exposed how GCHQ taps into Internet cables to monitor communications on a vast scale, but many details about what happens to the data after it has been vacuumed up have remained unclear.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-steps-in-enforcing-the-right-to-be-forgotten</id>
      <title>UK steps in enforcing the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-steps-in-enforcing-the-right-to-be-forgotten" />
      <updated>2015-08-24T22:00:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Information Commissioner’s Office &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/aug/20/google-ordered-to-remove-links-to-stories-about-right-to-be-forgotten-removals&quot;&gt;issued a notice to Google&lt;/a&gt; to remove from its search results newspaper articles that discussed details from older articles that had themselves been subject to a successful right to be forgotten request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new reports included, wholly unnecessarily, the name of the person who had requested that Google remove reports of a ten-year-old shoplifting conviction from search results. Google agreed with this right to be forgotten request and de-linked the contemporary reports of the conviction, but then refused to do the same to new articles that carried the same details. Essentially, Google had granted the subject’s request for privacy, and then allowed it to be reversed via the back door.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts and even the ICO have hinted that Google’s efforts to publicise the very details it is supposed to be minimising &lt;a href=&quot;http://informationrightsandwrongs.com/2014/09/13/dancing-to-the-beat-of-the-google-drum/&quot;&gt;might be viewed as a privacy breach or unfair processing&lt;/a&gt; with regard to those making right to be forgotten requests.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-privacy-special-rapporteur-believes-in-a-geneva-convention-fo</id>
      <title>UN privacy special rapporteur believes in a Geneva convention for the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-privacy-special-rapporteur-believes-in-a-geneva-convention-fo" />
      <updated>2015-08-24T22:12:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first UN privacy chief has said the world needs a Geneva convention style law for the Internet to safeguard data and combat the threat of massive clandestine digital surveillance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joseph Cannataci singled out British surveillance oversight as being worse than anything George Orwell could have foreseen and believes proper oversight is the only way of progressing, and hopes more people will think about and vote for privacy in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-high-court-opinion-on-data-retention-law</id>
      <title>UK High Court opinion on data retention law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-high-court-opinion-on-data-retention-law" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T14:51:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the UK High Court issued an opinion explaining how emergency legislation passed last summer — the Data Retention and Investigatory Powers Act of 2014 (DRIPA) — violates EU law. Access analyzed the ruling and considered the implications for the future of privacy and data retention in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-told-to-review-counter-terrorism-legislation-by-un-human-righ</id>
      <title>UK told to review counter-terrorism legislation by UN human rights committee</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-told-to-review-counter-terrorism-legislation-by-un-human-righ" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T20:41:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UN human rights committee, a body of 18 international experts who monitor the implementation of the international covenant on Civil and political rights, issued a series of recommendations for UK to review its counter-terrorism legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report raised concerns that the current legal regime governing the interception of communications and data “allows for mass interception” and “lacks sufficient safeguards against arbitrary interference with the right to privacy”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-rules-surveillance-law-unconstitutional</id>
      <title>UK court rules surveillance law unconstitutional</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-rules-surveillance-law-unconstitutional" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:02:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The controversial surveillance legislation discussed last summer in the UK parliament has been ruled unlawful by the UK High Court.&amp;nbsp; The court argued that the vague terms and descriptions of powers in the Data Retention and Investigatory Powers Act 2014 (DRIPA) renders the act incompatible with human rights under European law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-joins-letter-to-uk-officials-criticizing-gchq-for-spying</id>
      <title>Access joins letter to UK officials criticizing GCHQ for spying on human rights groups</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/access-joins-letter-to-uk-officials-criticizing-gchq-for-spying" />
      <updated>2015-07-01T21:56:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, Access joined a coalition letter to the Foreign Secretary of the United Kingdom sharply criticizing the government for spying on international human rights groups. The letter responded to revelations in a ruling by the Investigatory Powers Tribunal, which disclosed that Government Communications Headquarters (GCHQ) had spied on organizations in South Africa and Egypt. The UK is a member of the so-called Five Eyes coalition of governments — including the U.S., Canada, Australia, and New Zealand — that collaborates on intelligence gathering.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-uk-law-would-give-government-access-to-encrypted-internet-me</id>
      <title>New UK law would give government access to encrypted Internet messaging apps</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-uk-law-would-give-government-access-to-encrypted-internet-me" />
      <updated>2015-07-01T22:14:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new Investigatory Powers Bill, announced in yesterday&#039;s Queen&#039;s Speech, will include legislation to force Internet companies to give access to encrypted conversations of suspected terrorists and criminals. According to The Telegraph: &quot;New laws will require WhatsApp, which is owned by Facebook, Snapchat and other popular apps to hand messages sent by their users to MI5, MI6 and GCHQ about suspects under investigation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-intelligence-agency-hacked-pakistan-internet-exchange</id>
      <title>British intelligence agency hacked Pakistan Internet Exchange</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-intelligence-agency-hacked-pakistan-internet-exchange" />
      <updated>2018-01-06T12:26:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;British’s intelligence agency GCHQ had reportedly gained access to Pakistan Internet Exchange as revealed by The Intercept. According to the article, GCHQ has the ability to tap on any Internet user residing in Pakistan and “re-route selected traffic across international links towards GCHQ’s passive collection systems.” This happened because of a massive hacking plan called Computer Network Exploitation operations which occurred prior to 2008.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-cybersecurity-legislation</id>
      <title>UK government quietly rewrites cybersecurity legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-cybersecurity-legislation" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T11:01:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government has passed new legislation that exempts GCHQ, police, and other intelligence officers from prosecution for hacking into computers and mobile phones. The changes to the Computer Misuse Act were introduced over a year ago without a real public debate and entered into force on May 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Privacy International&#039;s legal experts, the amended Computer Misuse Act &quot;grants UK law enforcement new leeway to potentially conduct cyber attacks within the UK.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-must-destroy-documents-containing-legally-privileged-commun</id>
      <title>GCHQ must destroy documents containing legally privileged communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-must-destroy-documents-containing-legally-privileged-commun" />
      <updated>2015-04-29T22:19:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GCHQ, Britain’s national security surveillance agency, has been ordered to destroy legally privileged communications it unlawfully collected from a Libyan rendition victim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ruling marks the first time in its 15-year history that the investigatory powers tribunal has upheld a specific complaint against the intelligence services, lawyers have said. It is also the first time the tribunal has ordered a security service to give up surveillance material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-safari-users-win-right-to-sue-google-over-privacy</id>
      <title>UK: Safari users win right to sue Google over privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-safari-users-win-right-to-sue-google-over-privacy" />
      <updated>2015-04-15T13:54:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;story-body__introduction&quot;&gt;Google has lost a Court of Appeal bid to stop consumers having the right to sue in the UK over alleged misuse of privacy settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The case revolves around a so-called Safari workaround, which allegedly allowed Google to avoid the Safari web browser&#039;s default privacy setting to place cookies, that gathered data such as surfing habits, social class, race, ethnicity, without users&#039; knowledge. A group of users claim that Google bypassed security settings on the Safari browser to install tracking cookies on their computers in order to target them with advertising.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/handful-of-uk-spies-accessed-private-information-inappropriately</id>
      <title>Handful of UK spies accessed private information inappropriately, report says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/handful-of-uk-spies-accessed-private-information-inappropriately" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T16:33:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spies have been dismissed and disciplined for inappropriately accessing private information on citizens in recent years, the intelligence and security committee (ISC) report on privacy has found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report reveals a small number of staff at the intelligence agencies misused their surveillance powers, but it is not specific about how the information was wrongly accessed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Deliberate abuse of access to GCHQ’s systems would constitute gross misconduct (depending on the circumstances) – to date there has only been one case where &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/gchq&quot;&gt;GCHQ&lt;/a&gt; have dismissed a member of staff for misusing access to GCHQ’s systems,”the report states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-surveillance-laws-need-total-overhaul-says-landmark-report</id>
      <title>UK surveillance laws need total overhaul, says landmark report</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-surveillance-laws-need-total-overhaul-says-landmark-report" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T16:30:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Britain’s laws governing the intelligence agencies and mass surveillance require a total overhaul to make them more transparent, comprehensible and up to date, the intelligence and security committee of parliament (ISC) has said in a landmark report prompted by the revelations of &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/edward-snowden&quot;&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt;, the former US National Security Agency (NSA) contractor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223514888862/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/44500cde/sc/7/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;yctqrqhcuttdalzmsxrq&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223514888862/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/44500cde/sc/7/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/223514888862/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/44500cde/sc/7/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/more-than-500000-communications-data-intercepts-authorised-in-uk</id>
      <title>More than 500,000 communications data intercepts authorised in UK last year</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/more-than-500000-communications-data-intercepts-authorised-in-uk" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T16:31:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than half a million authorisations for police and intelligence officers to see communications data were issued last year, according to the commissioner who oversees interceptions by the security forces and local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 517,236 authorisations and notices to look at communications data – but not the content – is not the highest figure ever recorded. The commissioner, Sir Anthony May, found that there was no “significant institutional&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;overuse of communications data powers”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of the authorisiations, 88.9%, were granted by police forces and law enforcement agencies, 9.8% by the intelligence agencies and the remaining 1.3% by local authorities and other public authorities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223514878873/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/444ff036/sc/7/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;yctqrqhcuttdalzmsxrq&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/223514878873/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/444ff036/sc/7/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/223514878873/u/0/f/663871/c/34708/s/444ff036/sc/7/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spying-report-to-be-published</id>
      <title>UK spying report to be published</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-spying-report-to-be-published" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T16:36:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot; id=&quot;story_continues_1&quot;&gt;The legal framework surrounding surveillance is &quot;unnecessarily complicated&quot; and &quot;lacks transparency&quot;, a Parliamentary committee says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://b1cba9b3-a-5e6631fd-s-sites.googlegroups.com/a/independent.gov.uk/isc/files/20150312_ISC_P%2BS%2BRpt%28web%29.pdf?attachauth=ANoY7cozxKwLml2l9evijDLUHV_NrQ5_GO_ifLitT3Kh5pWVy6AzBmM8mLSVJkmXva6e-7xxC91erGB1z-mHcyaoHuhVfp5gAiqdkk4QyRn_VIkZwrYxAPz0sFSiHRqXQtok1QzyzKIl9Ng-Yg0oVcbYHSdjNnOkU6SlMV0Xuj46EoreqbUnwsChdbO5TWf2zVqk1HViKBG6jHzasSxH270lREsvwqoo0bi1P4vR6bERhCWOf0PR6H0e1bvCUXlIxUPmtvuASOxX&amp;amp;attredirects=0&quot;&gt;The Intelligence and Security Committee (ISC) report&lt;/a&gt; also says there should be a single law to govern access to private communications by UK agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its inquiry has considered the impact of such activities on people&#039;s privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/scottish-identity-database-plans-carry-privacy-risk-ministers-wa</id>
      <title>Scottish identity database plans carry privacy risk, ministers warned</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/scottish-identity-database-plans-carry-privacy-risk-ministers-wa" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T16:14:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scottish ministers have been warned by the UK information commissioner that plans for a Scotland-wide ID database risks personal privacy and civil liberties, and had not been fully thought through. The Information Commissioner’s Office said that proposals to put every Scottish citizen on a central database accessed by 120 public bodies, and give each person a unique number, risked breaching data protection laws and privacy standards.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-admits-unlawfully-monitoring-legally-privileged-communication</id>
      <title>UK admits unlawfully monitoring legally privileged communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-admits-unlawfully-monitoring-legally-privileged-communication" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:19:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The regime under which UK intelligence agencies, including MI5 and &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/mi6&quot;&gt;MI6&lt;/a&gt;, have been monitoring conversations between lawyers and their clients for the past five years is unlawful, the British government has admitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The admission that the activities of the security services have failed to comply fully with human rights laws in a second major area – this time highly sensitive legally privileged communications – is a severe embarrassment for the government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It follows hard on the heels of the &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/feb/06/gchq-mass-internet-surveillance-unlawful-court-nsa&quot;&gt;British court ruling on 6 February&lt;/a&gt; declaring that the regime surrounding the sharing of mass personal intelligence data between America’s national security agency and Britain’s GCHQ was unlawful for seven years.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-finds-secret-spying-docs-made-surveillance-illegal</id>
      <title>UK court finds secret spying docs made surveillance illegal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-finds-secret-spying-docs-made-surveillance-illegal" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T18:15:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several human rights groups are celebrating a major victory against the Five Eyes, an intelligence alliance comprising Australia, Canada, New Zealand, the UK and the US, as the UK surveillance tribunal ruled on 6 February that the Government Communications Headquarters (GCHQ) acted unlawfully in accessing millions of private communications collected by the National Security Agency (NSA) up until December 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision marks the first time that the Investigatory Powers Tribunal (IPT), the only UK court empowered to oversee GCHQ, the domestic security agency MI5 and the foreign intelligence service MI6, has ever ruled against the intelligence and security services in its fifteen-year history. The case was only possible thanks to the NSA whistleblower Edward Snowden whose leaked documents provided the facts needed to challenge the long-standing intelligence sharing relationship.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ripa-drafters-did-not-consider-its-use-to-access-journalists-dat</id>
      <title>UK: Ripa drafters did not consider its use to access journalists&#039; data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ripa-drafters-did-not-consider-its-use-to-access-journalists-dat" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T18:32:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It transpires that when the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act (Ripa) was being drafted no-one realised it could be used to access journalists’ communications and thus compromise their confidential sources. One of those who helped to draft the act, Michael Drury, who was GCHQ’s director of legal affairs between 1996 and 2010, said journalism was barely considered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drury told the audience that during the period of drafting attention was focused on privacy rights under Article 8 of the European Convention on Human Rights (ECHR), rather than the right to freedom of expression under Article 10.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-snoopers-loophole-why-winning-against-gchq-is-bittersweet</id>
      <title>The Snoopers’ Loophole: why winning against GCHQ is bittersweet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-snoopers-loophole-why-winning-against-gchq-is-bittersweet" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T16:03:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Investigatory Powers Tribunal stated that GCHQ was acting unlawfully in accessing NSA databases filled with billions of emails and messages, but with a few technical adjustments the intelligence services have managed to insure themselves against any further challenge, at least in domestic courts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-political-parties-approach-to-digital-issues</id>
      <title>UK political parties&#039; approach to digital issues</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-political-parties-approach-to-digital-issues" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:09:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ed Vaizey, the minister for culture and the digital economy, called for technology firms to “meet politicians halfway” on sensitive issues around privacy and internet safety, rather than react furiously with accusations that politicians do not understand the technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“So the prime minister, I think, is entitled to say: ‘We have a very sophisticated technology industry and encryption and so on… on the one hand I want to promote those industries and I want a successful technology economy, but I also have a duty as prime minister to keep our citizens as safe as possible. And we need to meet somewhere in the middle and talk about this’.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaizey was speaking at a Big Digital Debate event in London organised by techUK, Computer Weekly and BCS – The Chartered Institute for IT, which aimed to give the three major parties a platform to set out their approach to digital issues.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-datasharing-with-the-nsa-deemed-unlawful</id>
      <title>GCHQ datasharing with the NSA deemed unlawful</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-datasharing-with-the-nsa-deemed-unlawful" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:14:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two years after Edward Snowden’s allegations concerning mass surveillance, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipt-uk.com/&quot;&gt;Investigatory Powers Tribunal&lt;/a&gt;, the UK intelligence agencies complaints tribunal, has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/feb/06/gchq-mass-internet-surveillance-unlawful-court-nsa&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; that the manner in which the UK’s GCHQ shared intelligence from the US National Security Agency was unlawful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipt-uk.com/docs/Liberty-Order6Feb15.pdf&quot;&gt;brief ruling&lt;/a&gt; that follows a lengthy and more complex one in December, the tribunal at the same time announced its view that previous legal defects have been corrected, and that it is now satisfied that GCHQ is acting lawfully. At least, that is what you might think the IPT has decided. But in the peculiar point at which the law, intelligence and secrecy mix, things are not always what they seem.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-declared-that-the-secrecy-behind-gchq-surveillance-prog</id>
      <title>UK court declared that the secrecy behind GCHQ surveillance program was illegal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-court-declared-that-the-secrecy-behind-gchq-surveillance-prog" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:15:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A UK court &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/feb/06/gchq-mass-internet-surveillance-unlawful-court-nsa&quot;&gt;vindicated Edward Snowden’s whistleblowing on Friday&lt;/a&gt; by ruling that the secrecy surrounding one of the programs he exposed was, in fact, illegal. The decision is more evidence that not only were the Snowden revelations necessary and justified, but are also slowly forcing changes in both US and UK, even as both governments fiercely resist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a stunning ruling, the Investigatory Powers Tribunal (IPT) – which oversees (and usually rubber stamps) Britain’s spy agencies – declared that the intelligence-sharing rules between the NSA and GCHQ (Britain’s NSA equivalent and partner-in-crime) governing their mass surveillance program violated UK human rights laws because they were kept secret for so long.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-nsa-intelligence-sharing-unlawful-says-uk-surveillance-trib</id>
      <title>GCHQ-NSA intelligence sharing unlawful, says UK surveillance tribunal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gchq-nsa-intelligence-sharing-unlawful-says-uk-surveillance-trib" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T16:07:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;British intelligence services &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipt-uk.com/docs/Liberty-Order6Feb15.pdf&quot;&gt;acted unlawfully&lt;/a&gt; in accessing millions of people’s personal communications collected by the NSA, the Investigatory Powers Tribunal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipt-uk.com/docs/Liberty_Ors_Judgment_6Feb15.pdf&quot;&gt;ruled&lt;/a&gt; today. The decision marks the first time that the Tribunal, the only UK court empowered to oversee GHCQ, MI5 and MI6, has ever ruled against the intelligence and security services in its 15 year history.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/senior-peers-drop-attempt-to-revive-snoopers-charter</id>
      <title>Senior peers drop attempt to revive Communications Data Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/senior-peers-drop-attempt-to-revive-snoopers-charter" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:12:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Four senior peers have given up their last-minute attempt to revive the “snooper’s charter” and get it onto the statute book in the aftermath of the Paris attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former Conservative defence secretary Lord King has told the &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/lords&quot;&gt;House of Lords&lt;/a&gt; that this attempt to fill “the gap in access to communications data” was opposed by both the government and the official opposition so had little chance of making it into law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-communications-data-bill-supported-by-peers</id>
      <title>UK Communications Data Bill supported by peers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-communications-data-bill-supported-by-peers" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:13:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, several proposed adding whole sections of the defeated Communications Data Bill to the counter-terrorism legislation.&amp;nbsp;The move did not receive enough support last week but the peers hope to push through the proposals on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposed amendments sought to require internet service providers to log more of what people do online and to make that data more easily accessible to law enforcement and security services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation has already cleared its first hurdle in the House of Lords, and undergone detailed scrutiny in committee. Peers will now embark on the first of two days&#039; report-stage scrutiny, during which amendments will be proposed and changes made to the bill in committee considered.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/databox-concept-research-on-personal-data-management-and-protect</id>
      <title>Databox concept - research on personal data management and protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/databox-concept-research-on-personal-data-management-and-protect" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:15:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the Databox concept, scientists at British universities have begun an attempt to win back control of information about us. In a &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1501.04737&quot;&gt;paper by computer scientists&lt;/a&gt; from Queen Mary University of London and Cambridge University, the &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.technologyreview.com/view/534526/how-a-box-could-solve-the-personal-data-conundrum/&quot;&gt;Databox&lt;/a&gt; concept is described as a piece of software that collects personal data and then manages how that information is made available to third parties. In essence, it’s “a networked service that collates personal information from all of your devices and can also make that data available to organisations that the owner allows”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-agrees-privacy-policy-changes-with-data-protection-watchd</id>
      <title>Google agrees privacy policy changes with data protection watchdog</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-agrees-privacy-policy-changes-with-data-protection-watchd" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:14:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google has agreed to rewrite its privacy policy after pressure from the UK Information Commissioner&#039;s Office. The firm must make it easier for users to find out how their data is collected and what it is used for and submit to a two-year review. The deal follows an investigation by the regulator. Similar reviews are continuing elsewhere in Europe. It is understood that Google will seek to strike a similar deal with other European regulators. The Information Commissioner&#039;s Office (ICO) found that Google was &quot;too vague when describing how it uses personal data gathered from its web services and products&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-snoopers-charter-blocked</id>
      <title>UK snoopers charter blocked</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-snoopers-charter-blocked" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:13:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A former Conservative cabinet minister who chaired the parliamentary inquiry into the snooper’s charter has told four senior peers not to go ahead on Monday with their last-minute attempt to sneak it into law before the general election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lord Blencathra, a former Home Office minister, has written to the former Tory defence secretary Lord King, voicing strong concerns over his attempt to “insert the whole of the discredited draft communications data bill” into the counter-terror legislation being fast-tracked through the House of Lords.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-ripa-changes-may-allow-access-to-phone-and-email-records-of-j</id>
      <title>UK RIPA changes may allow access to phone and email records of journalists, lawyers, doctors, MPs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-ripa-changes-may-allow-access-to-phone-and-email-records-of-j" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:59:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An urgent campaign has been launched in the UK for a “freedom of expression” law to protect confidential journalists’, MPs’ and lawyers’ phone and communications records being secretly snooped on by police. Senior editors and lawyers condemned as “wholly inadequate” safeguards put forward in a code of practice by the home secretary, Theresa May, to meet concerns over the police use of surveillance powers linked to the Regulation of Investigatory Powers Act 2000 (Ripa). The campaign comes as the prime minister, &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/jan/12/david-cameron-pledges-anti-terror-law-internet-paris-attacks-nick-clegg&quot;&gt;David Cameron, called for an extension of the laws that give snooping powers to security services&lt;/a&gt; with a plan to ban &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jan/13/cameron-ban-encryption-digital-britain-online-shopping-banking-messaging-terror&quot;&gt;encrypted messages&lt;/a&gt; in the wake of the Charlie Hebdo Paris attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-prime-minister-wants-intelligence-agencies-to-be-able-to-trac</id>
      <title>UK Prime Minister wants intelligence agencies to be able to track all communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-prime-minister-wants-intelligence-agencies-to-be-able-to-trac" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:02:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mr. Cameron said that a Tory Government would pass a new law to ensure that the intelligence agencies would be able to track phone calls and internet messages. He said that this power to track “who made which call, to which person, and when” was “absolutely crucial not just in terrorism but finding missing people, murder investigations, almost every single serious crime. &quot;What matters is that we can access this communications data whether people are using fixed phones, mobile phones or more modern ways of communicating via the internet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-public-consultation-on-privacy-and-civil-liberties</id>
      <title>UK public consultation on Privacy and Civil Liberties</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-public-consultation-on-privacy-and-civil-liberties" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:56:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This consultation seeks views on a measure within the Counter-Terrorism and Security Bill which will enable the Home Secretary to create a Privacy and Civil Liberties Board to support the Independent Reviewer of Terrorism Legislation. The consultation invites comments on a number of details (such as membership of the board) that will be set out in the regulations. These regulations will be subject to affirmative resolution. The consultation is open until 30 January 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-surveillance-agency-releases-encryption-app-for-kids</id>
      <title>British surveillance agency releases encryption app for kids</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/british-surveillance-agency-releases-encryption-app-for-kids" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T15:13:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;British surveillance agency &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk/gchq&quot;&gt;GCHQ&lt;/a&gt; has launched an app teaching children to understand “basic encryption techniques”, despite its director having criticised technology firms for making more advanced tools available to their users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hmg.cryptoy&quot;&gt;Cryptoy is a free app for Android tablets&lt;/a&gt;, and it teaches children about four encryption techniques – shift, substitution, Vigenère and Enigma – as well as the history behind their use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/215951250045/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/415ff1a5/sc/4/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-specialist-for-catching-dark-net-pedophiles</id>
      <title>UK specialist for catching dark net pedophiles</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-specialist-for-catching-dark-net-pedophiles" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:19:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IT Worlds brings to attention the fact that the U.K. will set up a specialist unit that will use high-tech capabilities to hunt down pedophiles on the Tor anonymity network and other dark corners of the Web. The unit will combine the investigatory expertise of the U.K.’s National Crime Agency (NCA) with those of the Government Communications Headquarters (GCHQ), the U.K’s intelligence service, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-announces-new-global-action-to-deal-with-online-child-abuse&quot;&gt;tackle the worst cases of child sexual exploitation online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spotting-terrorist-behaviour-online-is-harder-than-finding-child</id>
      <title>Spotting terrorist behaviour online is harder than finding child ​abuse images</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spotting-terrorist-behaviour-online-is-harder-than-finding-child" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T17:26:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap drop-cap--wide&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;drop-cap__inner&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;hy are we outraged by the suggestion that Facebook users’ messages should be screened for potential terrorist threats yet we accept that airline passengers are screened for terrorist threats before boarding a plane? What’s the difference between moving people or information around the world? This is the question raised by the UK parliament’s &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; href=&quot;http://isc.independent.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;intelligence and security committee&lt;/a&gt; when it suggests Facebook and other internet platforms should “take responsibility” for detecting terrorist activity online.&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zgwubmmiljsqhyjftdto&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zgwubmmiljsqhyjftdto&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zgwubmmiljsqhyjftdto&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zgwubmmiljsqhyjftdto&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612381526/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/411e90c4/sc/4/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-becoming-a-surveillance-state</id>
      <title>UK becoming a surveillance state?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-becoming-a-surveillance-state" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T15:46:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UK has the highest density of CCTV in the world. Its GCHQ surveillance is considered highly effective. Commercial use of Big Data is on the rise. People are increasingly concerned about their privacy. However, UK citizens are fairly conservative. They trust the state to protect them and, in doing so, to find a balance and take appropriate steps. But the issues are complex and at an early stage of debate.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-emergency-legislation-on-data-retention-pushed-through</id>
      <title>UK: Emergency legislation on data retention pushed through</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-emergency-legislation-on-data-retention-pushed-through" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T16:04:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government brought in emergency legislation, a Data Retention and Investigatory Powers Bill (DRIP), to not only declare data retention to be still lawful but also expand the scope of both retention and lawful intercept in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the UK government has awarded itself the extra-territorial power to demand assistance with surveillance of UK persons from foreign companies that provide communications services to people in Britain. This means that the UK security and intelligence services can demand that Google UK wiretap someone associated with Britain, rather than filing an application via the relevant mutual legal assistance treaty.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
