<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/ES/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in ES</title>
  <updated>2018-04-13T19:06:48+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-dpa-fines-facebook-12-million-euro</id>
      <title>Spanish DPA fines Facebook 1,2 million euro</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-dpa-fines-facebook-12-million-euro" />
      <updated>2017-09-13T20:28:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Data Protection Authority fined Facebook with 1,2 million euro for several breaches of the Spanish Data Protection Law. This investigation is a part of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agpd.es/portalwebAGPD/noticias-inicio/common/pdf/2017/05_may_17/Common_Statement_16_May_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;joint initiative&lt;/a&gt; of DPAs from Belgium, France, Hamburg and The Netherlands. Facebook appealed the decision. Full press release of the Spanish DPA is available&amp;nbsp;in English &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.agpd.es/portalwebAGPD/revista_prensa/revista_prensa/2017/notas_prensa/news/2017_09_11-iden-idphp.php&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-fines-whatsapp-and-facebook-for-s</id>
      <title>Spanish Data Protection Agency fines Whatsapp and Facebook for sharing and processing personal data without consent</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-fines-whatsapp-and-facebook-for-s" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:06:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Data Protection Agency (AEPD) just published a resolution imposing fines of €300k to WhatsApp and Facebook each for exchanging, sharing and crossing personal data data without appropriate user consent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-recognizes-an-individuals-right-to-be-forgotten-ag</id>
      <title>Spanish Court recognizes an individual&#039;s right to be forgotten against Google</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-recognizes-an-individuals-right-to-be-forgotten-ag" />
      <updated>2018-01-11T23:20:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spanish Audiencia Nacional Court has supported a resolution from the Data Protection Agency mandating Google to take the necessary measures to avoid the name of an individual to appear in the search results linked to a resolution from ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-government-presents-first-draft-of-new-data-prot</id>
      <title>Spanish government presents first draft of new data protection law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-government-presents-first-draft-of-new-data-prot" />
      <updated>2017-06-30T18:10:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Government has presented the first draft of the new data protection law that tries to harmonize this piece of legislation in anticipation of the GDPR. It also includes new aspects like the treatment of data pertaining to deceased people.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-imposes-first-fine-ever-for-bootl</id>
      <title>Spanish Data Protection agency imposes fine for using cookies without consent</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-imposes-first-fine-ever-for-bootl" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:09:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish DPA (AEPD) issued a fine for using cookies without the informed consent of the users. The AEPD considers that Lolabits.es used data recovery storage devices (DARDs) or cookies illegally and has therefore decided to issue a fine of 5,000 euros. The complaint against the web was filed in February 2016 by Agedi, AIE, Cedro, Egeda, Fedicine and SGAE for violation of the Data Protection Act (LOPD).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-joins-kids-tv-channel-clan-to-pro</id>
      <title>Spanish Data Protection Agency joins kids TV channel Clan to promote good internet practices among youngsters</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-data-protection-agency-joins-kids-tv-channel-clan-to-pro" />
      <updated>2016-09-05T13:33:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Data Protection Agency (AEPD) and the public television program &quot;Big Band Clan&quot; (from Clan channel) are launching a campaign to promote good Internet practices among youngsters, including videos highlighting the value of privacy, such as &quot;Beware of what you share&quot;, or &quot;Beware the information you share with strangers&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/governments-increasingly-requesting-more-data-from-facebook</id>
      <title>Governments increasingly requesting more data from Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/governments-increasingly-requesting-more-data-from-facebook" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T22:29:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In its recent &quot;Global Government Requests Report&quot;, Facebook publishes the amount of censored articles and the number of information requests on their users, that different governments all around the world have performed during the first half of the year (2015).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Spain the number of requests rises to 41%.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-law-there-is-still-some-hope</id>
      <title>Spanish Citizens’ Security law: There is still some hope</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-law-there-is-still-some-hope" />
      <updated>2015-04-09T00:49:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite considerable global criticism, the Spanish Citizens’ Security law was passed on 26 March 2015, together with the reforms of the Criminal Code, which include punishment of badly-defined “terrorist crimes” online. The Citizens’ Security law was greatly opposed by political parties, but that was not enough against the majority in the Parliament of the Popular Party in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-10-threats-to-freedom-of-expression-and-information-of-the-n</id>
      <title>The 10 threats to freedom of expression and information of the new Spanish Criminal Code</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-10-threats-to-freedom-of-expression-and-information-of-the-n" />
      <updated>2015-02-24T23:54:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today the Spanish Congress debates and votes on amending the Criminal Code on matters of terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, the Platform in Defense of Freedom of Information (PDLI) emphasizes the setbacks for the fundamental rights that this reform represents.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-endorses-cjeu-decision-on-the-right-to-be-forgotte</id>
      <title>Spanish court endorses CJEU decision on the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-court-endorses-cjeu-decision-on-the-right-to-be-forgotte" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:20:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the first 18 sentences of its decision, the Spanish Audiencia Nacional court has endorsed, without any changes, the European ruling on the so called &#039;Right to be forgotten&#039; on the Internet. Citizens can demand search engines, Google in this case, the removal of personal information from URLs if they consider it harmful, assuming accessing these links can not be justified neither on public interest grounds nor because of the public relevance of the affected individual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-bill-undermines-digital-rights</id>
      <title>Spanish citizens’ security bill undermines digital rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-bill-undermines-digital-rights" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:21:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In December 2014, the Spanish Congress passed the Citizens’ Security bill by 181 votes to 141. Now, the bill will be discussed in the Senate until the end of March 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not only does the proposed bill introduce several restrictions to the freedoms of assembly and expression in protests, but it also lays down measures that would severely undermine digital rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizen-security-law-implications-for-the-internet</id>
      <title>Spanish Citizen Security Law implications for the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizen-security-law-implications-for-the-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:21:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Among the new aspects included in the new Citizen Security Law is the possibility of holding someone responsible for a street rally if he or she makes a public statement or a call for participation, like a simple Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ruling-party-rams-controversial-security-legislation-through-con</id>
      <title>Criticism to the Spanish Citizen Safety Law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ruling-party-rams-controversial-security-legislation-through-con" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:56:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Spanish opposition heavily criticizes the Citizen Safety Law. The bill was first introduced in November 2013 and it was immediately described as a tailor-made tool for the Popular Party to quell public displays of social unrest over the government’s handling of the economic crisis and rampant political corruption. The original draft included heavy fines for street protestors who carried signs “harmful to Spain or the regions,” and granted private security guards the right to help the police break up demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-criticises-uk-house-of-lords-analysis-on-the-right-to-be-fo</id>
      <title>EDRi criticises UK House of Lords analysis on the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-criticises-uk-house-of-lords-analysis-on-the-right-to-be-fo" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T09:09:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The House of Lords adopted a &lt;a title=&quot;Lords report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/ld201415/ldselect/ldeucom/40/4004.htm#a6&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on the Google/Spain case. EDRi says the report made it very clear that the nonsense around the term “the right to be forgotten” is indeed simply that… nonsense. However, EDRi observed that sadly, none of the facts of the case mattered in the way of a good story.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
