<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/CZ/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in CZ</title>
  <updated>2018-01-13T17:08:33+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposal-to-revoke-data-retention-filed-with-the-czech-court</id>
      <title>Proposal to revoke data retention filed with the Czech Court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposal-to-revoke-data-retention-filed-with-the-czech-court" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T17:08:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 20 December 2017, EDRi member Iuridicum Remedium (IuRe) filed a request with the Constitutional Court of the Czech Republic to revoke the Czech data retention related legislation. The filing of the request was achieved in close cooperation with the Czech Pirate Party, whose 22 deputies were for the first time elected to the Chamber of Deputies of the Czech Parliament in October 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-police-want-more-information-on-citizens-digital-communica</id>
      <title>Czech police want more information on citizens’ digital communication</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-police-want-more-information-on-citizens-digital-communica" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T01:16:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While some other EU countries already react on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf;jsessionid=9ea7d0f130d53fb7e5eab3f04e44a9338f0b793ae415.e34KaxiLc3eQc40LaxqMbN4ObhaQe0?text=&amp;amp;docid=153045&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=233593&quot;&gt;ECJ decision&lt;/a&gt; on abolishing the European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32006L0024&quot;&gt;Directive 2006/24/EC&lt;/a&gt; on data retention by preparing steps towards abolishing their respective transpositions of laws in their national legislative, the Czech Republic seems to head in the opposite direction. The Czech police officials call for enhancing the data retention regulation. One of the novelties is that the Czech police want to have an access to data on the IP address and port of the target point of the connection. Moreover, there is no news that the politicians or government are in preparation of any amendments of the Czech data retention law or even appeal to the Czech constitutional court.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-big-brother-awards-shine-light-on-privacy-invasions</id>
      <title>Czech Big Brother Awards shine light on privacy invasions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-big-brother-awards-shine-light-on-privacy-invasions" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T09:08:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EDRi-member Iuridicum Remedium (IuRe) organised the Czech Big Brother Awards 2014, which marks the the tenth time the event has been held. The Awards ceremony took place in the DOX Centre for Contemporary Art in Prague on 25 February 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of the Big Brother Awards was created by Privacy International in the UK in 1998, and today the awards are given annually in about a dozen countries around the globe. The goal is to draw attention to violations of the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-ttip-agreement-negotiations</id>
      <title>Czech Republic: TTIP agreement negotiations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-ttip-agreement-negotiations" />
      <updated>2015-03-25T14:22:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although there have been more than seven rounds of negotiations between EU, USA and Canada, the position of the Czech Government is somewhat uncertain. Based on several announcements and notes from government officials, the position seems to be rather positive. However, an official platform for discussion or information campaign has yet to be established. So far the Czech Ministry of Industry and Trade, which is responsible for this agenda, issued only a few news announcements informing about achieved results. The ministry only passively seeks for invitation to any debates regarding both agreements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this perspective a Czech NGO Iuridicum Remedium joined the European STOP TTIP initiative. Iuridicum Remedium addresses issues of blanket infringements on individual rights in the fields of Social Exclusion; Human Rights and Technologies; and Human Rights and Public Administration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Czech Stop TTIP initiative can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vttip.cz/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Basic information about TTIP agreements can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinfo.cz/cs/clanky/transatlanticka-dohoda-o-obchodu-a-investicich-mezi-eu-a-usa-ttip-41079.html#!&amp;amp;chapter=1&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-privacy-competition-for-children-and-youth</id>
      <title>Czech Republic: Privacy competition for children and youth</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/czech-republic-privacy-competition-for-children-and-youth" />
      <updated>2015-03-25T14:16:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Czech Office for Personal Data Protection announced a competition for children and youth in the context of the Personal Data Protection Day 2015. Young competitors may write a story, essay, or screenplay, they even may perform the invented story before a camera and produce a film or depict the narration in form of cartoon. Well-read children and youth will have the opportunity to write a text explaining in which book or movie they encountered the issue of privacy and personal data protection or what historic event reflects, in their view, privacy protection as a key element, regardless of how the event came off, well or badly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-czech-government-adopted-the-national-strategy-for-cyber-sec</id>
      <title>The Czech government adopted the National Strategy for Cyber Security for the next five years</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-czech-government-adopted-the-national-strategy-for-cyber-sec" />
      <updated>2015-02-24T23:56:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This strategy closely follows a promulgation of the Cybersecurity Act (181/2014) and builds upon the original strategy for cybersecurity, which was intended for the period 2012 to 2015. The new strategy for 2015-2020 aims at active international cooperation, protection of national critical information infrastructure and important information systems, cooperation with private sector, support of research and education, active participation on creation and implementation of European and international regulation. Specific details will be elaborated in an action plan to be introduced by the Czech National Cyber Security Centre in the second quarter of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
