<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/RO/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in RO</title>
  <updated>2018-02-09T19:48:01+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-ii-definitiveaz-poziia-oficial-de-negociere-pentru-refor</id>
      <title>România to define its national position on the EU copyright proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-ii-definitiveaz-poziia-oficial-de-negociere-pentru-refor" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T19:48:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 17 January 2018, the Romanian Ministry of Culture organised a debate on the EU copyright reform proposal. With the room full with about fifty participants, three quarters were representing press publishers, record labels and collective management associations. It seemed almost like a full-fledged campaign meeting organised for and by traditional newspapers and rightsholders organisations to rally support for Articles 11 and 13 of the Copyright Directive proposal – a support meeting coincidentally (or not) organised just prior to national officials presenting their country’s position on the copyright reform in Brussels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More information is available in English &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/romania-culture-ministry-rallies-copyright-lobbyists/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-discussed-in-romania</id>
      <title>Copyright Directive discussed in Romania</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-discussed-in-romania" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:42:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 23 June 2017, EDRi member Asociația pentru Tehnologie și Internet (ApTI) along with The National Association of Librarians and Public Libraries of Romania (ANBPR) and the Center for Independent Journalism (CJI) organised a meeting on the topic of the proposed EU Copyright Directive. Member of the European Parliament (MEP) Victor Negrescu took part in the event.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/largest-football-club-in-romania-loses-its-brand-in-court</id>
      <title>Largest football club in Romania loses its brand in court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/largest-football-club-in-romania-loses-its-brand-in-court" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T20:19:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Romania’s High Court of Cassation and Justice (ICCJ) ruled against Becali’s football club in a case in which the Army’s Sports Club, which is also called “Steaua Bucuresti” asked the court to cancel the registration of the Steaua Bucharest Football Club, which was made in January 2004, at the State Office for Inventions and Trademarks – OSIM.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/international-intellectual-property-alliance-report-on-copyright</id>
      <title>International Intellectual Property Alliance Report on Copyright and Protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/international-intellectual-property-alliance-report-on-copyright" />
      <updated>2014-11-25T12:11:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the midst of steady and significant piracy rates in Romania, enforcement conditions have only deteriorated. High-level Romanian authorities support the private sector in promoting anti-piracy messages, but their efforts have not translated into concrete steps to bring copyright criminals to justice, and enforcement actions in the past year have dropped. As a result, piracy remains widespread in Romania for all forms of copyright works, especially in the online space, where international pirates seek safe haven from better-enforced terrain elsewhere in Europe. Making matters worse, in 2013 the Court of Appeal held that the making available right in Romania is subject to mandatory collective administration, contradicting Romania’s obligations under the WIPO Treaties to provide an exclusive making available right and the means to enforce it. We encourage the Romanian Government to address this troubling development, adapt the country’s laws to the modern environment, encourage a national policy of cooperation against online infringement, ensure police officials are competent and well-equipped to conduct raids and investigations efficiently, and give targeted prosecutors and courts the authority and training to bring piracy cases to speedy conclusion, with deterrent sentences and penalties. The support and assistance of the U.S. Embassy in Bucharest continues to be an invaluable part of the continued effort to address these crucial issues.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
