<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/EU/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in EU</title>
  <updated>2018-02-09T20:26:24+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-court-rules-against-facebook-class-action</id>
      <title>EU court rules against Facebook class action</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-court-rules-against-facebook-class-action" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:30:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Justice in Luxembourg on Thursday ruled that Austrian privacy campaigner Max Schrems cannot lodge a class action suit against Facebook Ireland. Schrems was seeking to stake the collective claim on the behalf of 25,000 people. The judges instead said he can file an individual case. Schrems maintains that Facebook violates the privacy of European-based users.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-votes-on-e-privacy</id>
      <title>MEPs votes on e-Privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-votes-on-e-privacy" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:20:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 19 October, the European Parliament Committee on Civil Liberties, Justice and Home Affairs (LIBE) voted on the proposed e-Privacy Regulation. With 31 votes the Committee voted in favour of measures defending privacy, security and competition for phone and internet services. The 31 MEPs in favour of the e-Privacy Regulation belong to the Alliance of Liberals and Democrats for Europe group (ALDE), the Europe of Freedom and Direct Democracy (EFDD), the European United Left-Nordic Green Left (GUE/NGL), the Non-Inscrits (NI), the Progressive Alliance of Socialists and Democrats (S&amp;amp;D) and the Greens–European Free Alliance (Verts/ALE).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-halts-retention-bulk-transfer-of-passenger-data</id>
      <title>European court halts retention, bulk transfer of passenger data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-halts-retention-bulk-transfer-of-passenger-data" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:35:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The top EU Court has &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/EU-Canada-PNR.pdf&quot;&gt;struck down&lt;/a&gt; an EU-Canada agreement on the processing of &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/international/eu_passenger_name_records.html&quot;&gt;airline passenger&lt;/a&gt; records. The Passenger Name Record agreement mandated data retention and permitted the bulk transfer of personal data provided by passengers booking a flight. The Court of Justice of the EU explained &quot;the PNR agreement may not be concluded in its current form because several of its provisions are incompatible with the fundamental rights recognised by the EU.&quot; The data can reveal &quot;a complete travel itinerary, travel habits, relationships existing between two or more individuals, and information on the financial situation of air passengers, their dietary habits or their state of health.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-mps-back-end-to-end-encryption-for-all-citizens-bbc-news</id>
      <title>MEPs back end-to-end encryption for all citizens</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-mps-back-end-to-end-encryption-for-all-citizens-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:13:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A European Parliament committee wants end-to-end encryption to be enforced on all forms of digital communication to protect European Union (EU) citizens. A ban on &quot;backdoors&quot; into encrypted messaging apps like WhatsApp and Telegram is also being considered.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-e-privacy-rules-need-improvements-to-help-build-trust-1</id>
      <title>New e-Privacy rules need improvements to help build trust</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-e-privacy-rules-need-improvements-to-help-build-trust-1" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T05:02:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 10 January 2017, the European Commission published its long-awaited proposal for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/news/proposal-regulation-privacy-and-electronic-communications&quot;&gt;e-Privacy Regulation&lt;/a&gt; (ePR) to replace the 2002 &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=URISERV:l24120&quot;&gt;e-Privacy Directive&lt;/a&gt; (ePD). This new regulation complements the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), adding more clarity and legal certainty for individuals and businesses – helping to protect our personal data by providing specific rules related to our freedoms in the online environment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recklessly-unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks</id>
      <title>Recklessly unclear Terrorism Directive creates significant risks for citizens’ security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/recklessly-unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:44:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 February, the European Parliament voted in favour of the EU Directive on combating terrorism. In EDRI&#039;s opinion, the weak, unclear, ambiguous wording in the Directive presents dangers for the rule of law, the right to privacy and freedom of opinion and expression of people in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/despite-large-opposition-ceta-limps-forward-in-the-european-parl</id>
      <title>Despite large opposition, CETA limps forward in the European Parliament</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/despite-large-opposition-ceta-limps-forward-in-the-european-parl" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:44:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 24 January 2017, the European Parliament Committee on International Trade voted in favour of the Comprehensive Economic Trade Agreement, despite the concerns about fundamental rights and the right to regulate. CETA is portrayed as a trade agreement, but it goes far beyond trade. It touches upon privacy and data protection, the right to access knowledge, as well as other fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-bulgarian-eu-council-presidency-the-latest-assault-on-epriva</id>
      <title>The Bulgarian EU Council presidency and the latest assault on ePrivacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-bulgarian-eu-council-presidency-the-latest-assault-on-epriva" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:26:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, the Bulgarian Presidency of the Council of the European Union picked up where the Estonian Presidency left off on the ePrivacy Regulation. It issued two examinations of the last Estonian “compromise” proposal and asked national delegations for guidance on some issues. Together, the documents cover most of the key points of the text. While the Bulgarian Presidency brings clarity on some points, its questions pave the way to undermine the text – and therefore threatens the protection of citizens’ privacy, confidentiality of communications of both citizens and businesses, as well as the positions of innovative EU companies and trust in the online economy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjue-decision-member-states-may-not-impose-a-general-data-retent</id>
      <title>CJUE decision: member states may not impose a general data retention obligation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjue-decision-member-states-may-not-impose-a-general-data-retent" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T05:06:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/documents.jsf?num=C-203/15&quot;&gt;Watson vs. Tele2 Sverige AB (C-203/15)&lt;/a&gt;, the court decides that EU law precludes national legislation that prescribes general and indiscriminate retention of data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The text of the decision is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/documents.jsf?num=C-203/15&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the press release &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statewatch.org/news/2016/dec/cjeu-watson-judgment-surveillance-blanket-retention-prel.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-fighting-terrorism-with-closed-door-secrecy</id>
      <title>European Parliament – fighting terrorism with closed-door secrecy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-fighting-terrorism-with-closed-door-secrecy" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T19:55:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament’s Special Committee on Terrorism (TERR) was established on 6 July 2017, for a renewable twelve-month mandate. The Committee was created with the ambitious aim of addressing ostensible practical and legislative deficiencies in the fight against terrorism across the European Union and with international actors.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-chiefs-wary-of-lagging-eu-states-on-new-data-rules</id>
      <title>Privacy chiefs wary of lagging EU states on new data rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-chiefs-wary-of-lagging-eu-states-on-new-data-rules" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:01:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU data protection chiefs are worried member states won&#039;t be ready when a new wide-sweeping general data protection regulation goes live on 25 May. National laws still need to be passed to ensure data authorities can enforce the regulation EU-wide.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-austria-privacy-chief-to-head-eu-data-protection-group</id>
      <title>Austria privacy chief to head EU data protection group</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-austria-privacy-chief-to-head-eu-data-protection-group" />
      <updated>2018-02-07T20:03:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The head of Austria&#039;s data protection authority Andrea Jelinek is replacing Isabelle Falque-Pierrotin as the chair of the body representing national data protection supervisors known as the Article 29 Working Party. Jelinek was elected for the post on Wednesday and is likely to also become the head of the upcoming European Data Protection Board, tasked to enforce the general data protection regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-proposal-undermined-by-eu-member-states</id>
      <title>e-Privacy proposal undermined by EU Member States</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-proposal-undermined-by-eu-member-states" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T17:29:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The discussions on the e-Privacy Regulation continue in the European Union legislative process. On 5 December 2017, the Estonian Presidency of the Council proposed new compromises on key articles. This latest proposal for amendments is related to Articles 6, 7 and 8 of the draft e-Privacy Regulation, which concern permitted processing (Art. 6), storage and erasure of communications data (Art. 7) and the protection of stored communications in users’ devices (Art. 8).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/end-of-the-privacy-debate-in-the-european-parliament-overview</id>
      <title>End of the privacy debate in the European Parliament: overview</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/end-of-the-privacy-debate-in-the-european-parliament-overview" />
      <updated>2018-01-13T16:38:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;On 26 October, the European Parliament as a whole decided to end it&#039;s debate about the future ePrivacy Regulation. It&#039;s position already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/eprivacy_failed&quot;&gt;adopted on 19 October&lt;/a&gt; by the leading Civil Liberties committee was thus confirmed. Now, governments of the Member States and representatives of the European Parliament will negotiate in order to find a compromise in form of a final text. La Quadrature du Net reviews the first step of legislation which has come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-member-states-plan-to-ignore-eu-court-data-retention-rulings</id>
      <title>EU Member States plan to ignore EU Court data retention rulings</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-member-states-plan-to-ignore-eu-court-data-retention-rulings" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:26:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Statewatch documents reveal that EU Member States are exploring all possible options to keep, and in fact expand, their current data retention regimes. The general plan is based on a new concept of ”restricted data retention”, which is really blanket data retention with a new name, along with amendments to the draft e-Privacy Regulation to facilitate blanket data retention. Member States are considering whether these new elements should be introduced through an EU instrument or through national law in each Member State.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/surveillance-laws-fall-far-short-of-fundamental-rights-standards</id>
      <title>Surveillance laws fall far short of fundamental rights standards</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/surveillance-laws-fall-far-short-of-fundamental-rights-standards" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:18:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 23 October, the European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights (FRA) published the second volume of its study on surveillance and its impact on fundamental rights. This study comes following the request of the European Parliament (EP) for information on the consequences of surveillance for fundamental rights. The Agency notes that “the mere existence of legislation allowing for surveillance constitutes an interference with the right to private life” even though it notes the role of surveillance measures in the fight against terrorism and new threats linked to new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-commission-struggles-to-find-a-position-on-encrypti</id>
      <title>The European Commission struggles to find a position on encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-commission-struggles-to-find-a-position-on-encrypti" />
      <updated>2017-11-05T16:39:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 18 October, the European Commission adopted some form of position on encryption, inexplicably embedded in its “anti-terrorism package”. Home affairs activity in relation to encryption is horizontal (covering all illegal activity) and not specifically related to terrorism. However, the Commission chose to include this topic in its anti-terrorism package.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-parliament-backs-e-privacy-talks</id>
      <title>EU Parliament backs e-privacy talks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-parliament-backs-e-privacy-talks" />
      <updated>2017-10-26T16:18:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament is ready to start talks on e-privacy reforms, following a plenary vote in Strasbourg on Thursday. The vote means the assembly has put forward its official position, aiming to keep online communications confidential, and is now ready to enter negotiations with the EU member states. The scope of the reforms covers digital services such as WhatsApp or Skype.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-adviser-says-local-regulators-can-enforce-privacy</id>
      <title>European Court Adviser Says Local Regulators Can Enforce Privacy Laws Against Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-adviser-says-local-regulators-can-enforce-privacy" />
      <updated>2017-10-26T16:36:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=195902&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=lst&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=705666&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; of a key adviser to the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://europa.eu/european-union/about-eu/institutions-bodies/court-justice_en&quot;&gt;European Court of Justice&lt;/a&gt; holds that local European data protection authorities can directly enforce privacy laws against Facebook. The case involves a German data protection authority&#039;s order to deactivate a local Facebook fan page for illegally tracking users. The opinion from Advocate General Bot said regional data protection authorities can intervene to stop unlawful data practices. The European Court of Justice typically adopts the opinions of the Advocate General. The Court of Justice will also &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/intl/schrems/DPC-v-Facebook-and-Schrems-Judgment-pt-1-20171003.pdf&quot;&gt;consider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/intl/schrems/#schrems2&quot;&gt;DPC v. Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, involving whether Facebook&#039;s data transfers from Ireland to the U.S. violate European Fundamental Rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-parliamentarians-say-a-clear-no-to-the-anti-privacy-lobby</id>
      <title>Euro-parliamentarians say a clear “no” to the anti-privacy lobby</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euro-parliamentarians-say-a-clear-no-to-the-anti-privacy-lobby" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:54:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 19 October, the European Parliament Committee on Civil Liberties, Justice and Home Affairs (LIBE) voted on the proposed e-Privacy Regulation. The Committee voted in favour of measures defending privacy, security and competition for phone and internet services. Despite a huge lobbying effort to water down the proposal, the Committee voted for clear, privacy-friendly rules.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/extending-the-use-of-eid-to-online-platforms-risks-to-privacy</id>
      <title>Extending the use of eID to online platforms – risks to privacy?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/extending-the-use-of-eid-to-online-platforms-risks-to-privacy" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T16:00:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 10 October 2017, the European Commission published the “draft principles and guidance on eID interoperability for online platforms” on the electronic Identification And Trust Services (eIDAS) observatory. Building on the eIDAS Regulation, the Commission would like to extend the scope of use for the eIDs to online platforms, in addition to public services.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cross-border-access-to-data-has-to-respect-human-rights-principl</id>
      <title>Cross-border access to data has to respect human rights principles</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cross-border-access-to-data-has-to-respect-human-rights-principl" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:14:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Council of Europe started preparing an additional protocol to the Cybercrime Convention – a new tool for law enforcement authorities to have access to data in the context of criminal investigations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cross-border-access-to-data-edri-delivers-international-ngo-posi</id>
      <title>Cross-border access to data: EDRi delivers international NGO position to Council of Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cross-border-access-to-data-edri-delivers-international-ngo-posi" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:18:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, 18 September 2017, a global coalition of civil society organisations, led by European Digital Rights (EDRi), submitted to the Council of Europe its comments on how protect human rights when developing new rules on cross-border access to electronic evidence (“e-evidence”). The Council of Europe is currently preparing an additional protocol to the Cybercrime Convention.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-the-gdpr-will-disrupt-google-and-facebook-pagefair</id>
      <title>How the GDPR will disrupt Google and Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/how-the-gdpr-will-disrupt-google-and-facebook-pagefair" />
      <updated>2017-09-01T13:32:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google and Facebook will be disrupted by the new European data protection rules that are due to apply in May 2018. The companies will be unable to use the personal data they hold for advertising purposes without user permission.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/antitrust-regulators-raise-the-issue-of-tech-giants-monopoly-ove</id>
      <title>Antitrust regulators raise the issue of tech giants&#039; monopoly over customer&#039;s online data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/antitrust-regulators-raise-the-issue-of-tech-giants-monopoly-ove" />
      <updated>2017-08-30T11:56:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tech companies earn billions of euros each year from the data they gather from people’s increasingly digital lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But to prove these companies have fallen afoul of Europe’s tough competition laws, regulators like Margrethe Vestager, Europe’s top antitrust enforcer, must show that their dominance over vast amounts of people’s data has hampered consumer choice by relegating potential rivals to the sidelines, according to competition lawyers and policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/norway-introduces-forced-biometric-authentication</id>
      <title>Norway introduces forced biometric authentication</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/norway-introduces-forced-biometric-authentication" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:40:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 5 April 2017, the Norwegian government proposed an amendment to the Norwegian code of criminal proceedings to allow the police to compel the use of biometric authentication. After two quick debates, the Norwegian Parliament passed the proposition into law on 21 June.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/pnr-eu-court-rules-that-draft-eucanada-air-passenger-data-deal-i</id>
      <title>PNR: EU Court rules that draft EU/Canada air passenger data deal is unacceptable</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/pnr-eu-court-rules-that-draft-eucanada-air-passenger-data-deal-i" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:26:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, on 26 July 2017, the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) confirmed that the EU/Canada deal on collection of air travellers’ data and sharing it breaches European law. This is the third time that the European Court has ruled against arrangements for mandatory storage of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-right-to-be-forgotten-spat-returns-to-europes-top-court</id>
      <title>Google right to be forgotten spat returns to Europe’s top court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-right-to-be-forgotten-spat-returns-to-europes-top-court" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:32:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google&#039;s dispute with France&#039;s privacy watchdog over a call to apply &quot;right to be forgotten&quot; rules globally to some Web links will be weighed by Europe&#039;s top court.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/turkey-court-backs-mp-over-intelligence-service-human-rights-com</id>
      <title>Turkey: Court backs MP over intelligence service human rights complaint</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/turkey-court-backs-mp-over-intelligence-service-human-rights-com" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:42:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Human rights judges have backed a Turkish MP, who complained that the six week interception and surveillance of all electronic communication in the country, amounted to a breach of human rights. The European Court of Human Rights’ 18 July decision in the case Mustafa Sezgin Tanrıkulu v. Turkey (no. 27473/06) declared a Violation of Article 8 and a Violation of Article 13.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decision is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudoc.echr.coe.int/eng#{%22itemid%22:[%22001-175464%22]}&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/total-information-awareness-for-law-enforcement-no-data-protecti</id>
      <title>Total information awareness for law enforcement, no data protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/total-information-awareness-for-law-enforcement-no-data-protecti" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:52:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Network of Law Enforcement Technology Services (ENLETS), an informal group funded by the European Commission, has produced a report&amp;nbsp;on best practices in mobile solutions for law enforcement practitioners. The report sees developments in mobile technologies, telecoms networks and cloud computing as a “game-changer” for total information awareness for law enforcement authorities. It foresees police smartphones, smartwatches or other devices having instant, 24/7 access to a complete profile on individuals from data gathered and stored locally, nationally or internationally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/are-we-on-the-right-track-for-a-strong-e-privacy-regulation</id>
      <title>Are we on the right track for a strong e-Privacy Regulation?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/are-we-on-the-right-track-for-a-strong-e-privacy-regulation" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:35:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union is revising its legislation on data protection, privacy and confidentiality of communications in the digital environment: the e-Privacy Directive. This piece of legislation contains specific rules related to your freedoms online and EDRi is analyzing the flaws and the positive aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-releases-draft-report-on-eprivacy-directive</id>
      <title>EU Parliament Releases Draft Report on ePrivacy Directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-releases-draft-report-on-eprivacy-directive" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:44:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament&#039;s Committee on Civil Liberties, Justice, and Home Affairs has released a draft &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//NONSGML+COMPARL+PE-606.011+01+DOC+PDF+V0//EN&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on regulations for privacy and electronic communications. The draft contains several proposals to strengthen online privacy, including end-to-end encryption in all electronic communications and a ban on encryption backdoors. Protecting the privacy of communications is &quot;an essential condition for the respect of other related fundamental rights and freedoms,&quot; according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-report-on-eprivacy</id>
      <title>Draft report on ePrivacy regulation proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/draft-report-on-eprivacy" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T18:21:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;DRAFT REPORT on the proposal for a regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council concerning the respect for private life and the protection of personal data in electronic communications and and repealing Directive 2002/58/EC.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-privacy-officials-push-for-answers-on-status-of-us-priv</id>
      <title>European privacy officials push for answers on status of U.S. privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-privacy-officials-push-for-answers-on-status-of-us-priv" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:47:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/just/item-detail.cfm?item_id=50083&quot;&gt;Article 29 Working Party&lt;/a&gt;, an expert group of European privacy officials, is pressing the European Commission to closely evaluate the EU-US &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/intl/privacy-shield/&quot;&gt;Privacy Shield&lt;/a&gt;, a framework permitting the flow of European consumers&#039; personal data to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-privacy-authorities-issue-opinion-on-the-eprivacy-regul</id>
      <title>European privacy authorities issue opinion on the ePrivacy regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-privacy-authorities-issue-opinion-on-the-eprivacy-regul" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:50:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Data Protection Authorities (DPA’s) of the Article 29 Working Party welcome the proposal for an ePrivacy Regulation. The Working Party welcomes the choice for a regulation as the regulatory instrument because this ensures that rules are uniform across the entire EU, and it provides clarity for supervisory authorities and organisations alike. The inclusion of Over-The-Top (OTT) providers is necessary, so that these services guarantee the same level of confidentiality of communications as traditional telecoms operators. The working party also welcomes the principled approach for broad prohibitions and narrow exceptions, as well as the attempt to modernize the rules applicable for tracking in the online world. However, the DPA’s note 4 points of concern in the opinion, adopted last week.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-judges-may-be-asked-to-rule-on-legality-of-uk-surveillance-po</id>
      <title>EU judges may be asked to rule on legality of UK surveillance powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-judges-may-be-asked-to-rule-on-legality-of-uk-surveillance-po" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T23:57:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU judges may be asked to decide whether the intelligence services’ bulk collection of email data in order to prevent terrorist attacks is legal. In a fresh challenge that could impact the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/nov/19/extreme-surveillance-becomes-uk-law-with-barely-a-whimper&quot;&gt;Investigatory Powers Act&lt;/a&gt;, the campaign group Privacy International argued in court on Monday that interception of social media that is not targeted and subject to sufficient safeguards is forbidden by a previous European judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-fines-facebook-110-million-euros-over-whatsapp-deal</id>
      <title>EU fines Facebook 110 million euros over WhatsApp deal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-fines-facebook-110-million-euros-over-whatsapp-deal" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T19:30:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European Union antitrust regulators fined Facebook 110 million euros ($122 million) on Thursday for giving misleading information during a vetting of its deal to acquire messaging service WhatsApp in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calling it a &quot;proportionate and deterrent fine&quot;, the European Commission, which acts as the EU&#039;s competition watchdog, said Facebook had said it could not automatically match user accounts on its namesake platform and WhatsApp but two years later launched a service that did exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-watchdogs-support-stronger-eprivacy-legislati</id>
      <title>EU data protection watchdogs support stronger ePrivacy legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-watchdogs-support-stronger-eprivacy-legislati" />
      <updated>2017-05-19T23:40:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 10 January 2017, the European Commission published its long-awaited proposal for an e-Privacy Regulation (ePR)&amp;nbsp;to replace the 2002 e-Privacy Directive (ePD). In April 2017, two Opinions were issued to provide comments and recommendations on how to better safeguard the right to privacy, confidentiality of communications, and the protection of personal data in the proposed ePR; one by the Article 29 Data Protection Working Party (WP29), and another one by the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eprivacy-regulation</id>
      <title>EDPS calls for strong and smart new rules to protect confidentiality of communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eprivacy-regulation" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:48:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edps.europa.eu/sites/edp/files/publication/17-04-24_eprivacy_en.pdf&quot;&gt;EDPS opinion&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edps.europa.eu/press-publications/press-news/press-releases/2017/edps-calls-strong-and-smart-new-rules-protect_en&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-eprivacy-regulation-must-level-the-playing-field-for-the</id>
      <title>Europe’s ePrivacy Regulation must level the playing field — for the users</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europes-eprivacy-regulation-must-level-the-playing-field-for-the" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:32:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Access Now testified in a hearing before the LIBE Committee in the European Parliament on the proposal for an e-Privacy Regulation that was presented by the EU Commission on 10 January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The e-Privacy proposal aims to set the rules for the respect for private life and the confidentiality of electronic communications in the EU. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/cms/assets/uploads/2017/04/Access-Now-testimony-f-on-ePrivacy-11-April-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Access Now&#039;s testimony&lt;/a&gt; clarifies that to protect Europeans’ fundamental rights, the rules should not only uphold the level of protection afforded by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), but should exceed it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-parliament-adopts-another-resolution-critical-of-th</id>
      <title>The European Parliament adopts another resolution critical of the Privacy Shield</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-european-parliament-adopts-another-resolution-critical-of-th" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:30:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 6 April 2017, the European Parliament (EP) voted a motion for a resolution on the adequacy of the protection afforded by the EU-US Privacy Shield. The scheme gives the United States a unique arrangement for the transfer of personal data from the European Union to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-adopts-resolution-on-big-data</id>
      <title>European Parliament Adopts Resolution on Big Data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-adopts-resolution-on-big-data" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:40:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament has adopted a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/oeil/popups/ficheprocedure.do?reference=2016/2225(INI)&amp;amp;l=en#documentGateway&quot;&gt;resolution on the fundamental rights implications of big data&lt;/a&gt;. The resolution stresses that &quot;the prospects and opportunities of big data&quot; can only be realized &quot;when public trust in these technologies is ensured by a strong enforcement of fundamental rights and compliance with current EU data protection law.&quot; The resolution discusses the importance of data protection, accountability, transparency, data security, and privacy by design.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks-for-citize</id>
      <title>Unclear Terrorism Directive creates significant risks for citizens’ security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unclear-terrorism-directive-creates-significant-risks-for-citize" />
      <updated>2017-03-01T08:40:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 February 2017, the European Parliament voted in favour of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/terrorism-directive-document-pool/&quot;&gt;EU Directive on combating terrorism&lt;/a&gt;. Weak, unclear, ambiguous wording in the Directive presents dangers for the rule of law, the right to privacy and freedom of opinion and expression of people in the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-rights-undermined-by-flawed-ceta-deal-1</id>
      <title>Citizens’ rights undermined by flawed CETA deal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-rights-undermined-by-flawed-ceta-deal-1" />
      <updated>2017-03-04T16:23:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 15 February 2017, the European Parliament voted in favour of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/ceta-signature-ignores-agreements-flaws/&quot;&gt;Comprehensive Economic Trade Agreement (CETA)&lt;/a&gt;. This concludes the process at the EU level. The EU Member States will now have to ratify the agreement, without having a right to make changes to the text. CETA creates significant risks for citizens’ fundamental rights, especially with regard to &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/ceta-puts-protection-privacy-and-personal-data-at-risk/&quot;&gt;privacy and data protection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-regulation-good-intentions-but-a-lot-of-work-to-do</id>
      <title>e-Privacy Regulation: Good intentions but a lot of work to do</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-regulation-good-intentions-but-a-lot-of-work-to-do" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:43:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 10 January 2017, the European Commission published its long-awaited proposal for an e-Privacy Regulation to replace the 2002 e-Privacy Directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposed draft Regulation contains a number of provisions which, if adopted and effectively implemented, should address some of the current gaps or lack of clarity in protection of the confidentiality of electronic communications and information stored on users devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the Commission has rightly identified and addressed most of the key issues and objectives in the proposal, strong forces seem to have watered down the text considerably, compared to the earlier version that was leaked in December 2016. For example, the reference to “privacy by design and by default” that was changed in Article 10 will need to be put back in order not to lower down the protections to the current “privacy by option”, options on the degree of online privacy that the browser would offer to the user.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-look-at-the-proposal-for-the-eprivacy-regulation</id>
      <title>A look at the proposal for the ePrivacy Regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-look-at-the-proposal-for-the-eprivacy-regulation" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T11:09:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On January 10 2017, the European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-17-16_en.htm&quot;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a proposal for a Regulation, in view of the economic and social importance of digital services, the development of Internet of Things and the rise of the so-called Over-the-Top communications services, all of which currently fall outside of Directive 2002/58/EC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article presents a commentary on the ePrivacy Regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eprivacy-commissions-weak-proposal-forecasts-harsh-debates</id>
      <title>ePrivacy: Commission&#039;s weak proposal forecasts harsh debates</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eprivacy-commissions-weak-proposal-forecasts-harsh-debates" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T12:38:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday 10 January, the European Commission put forward a series of new texts on personal data protection in the EU. It includes the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/files/eurobarometer-privacy-2016-EN.pdf&quot;&gt;upcoming ePrivacy Regulation&lt;/a&gt; which will frame the confidentiality and security of our electronic communications, as well as the famous internet cookies, among other things. Before the legislative process had even started, lobbies from the digital industry and telecom operators collaborated closely to water down as much as possible the reform that was supposed to not only provide better security and confidentiality to electronic communications, but also to give users control of their data back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-proposal-commission-leaves-the-european-parliament-wit</id>
      <title>e-Privacy proposal – Commission leaves the European Parliament with lots of work to do</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/e-privacy-proposal-commission-leaves-the-european-parliament-wit" />
      <updated>2017-01-11T08:52:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, on 10 January 2017, the European Commission published its proposal for an e-Privacy Regulation. This legislation is crucial to provide clear rules on tracking individuals as they surf the web, and on freedom of communication more generally.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-single-market-stronger-privacy-rules-for-electronic-comm-2</id>
      <title>Digital Single Market – Stronger privacy rules for electronic communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-single-market-stronger-privacy-rules-for-electronic-comm-2" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T12:39:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European Commission - Fact Sheet Brussels, 10 January 2017 Questions and Answers Why is the Commission modernising EU digital privacy rules? Since the last revision of the ePrivacy Directive in 2009, electronic communications services have evolved significantly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/commission-proposes-high-level-of-privacy-rules-for-all-electron-2</id>
      <title>Commission proposes high level of privacy rules for all electronic communications and updates data protection rules for EU institutions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/commission-proposes-high-level-of-privacy-rules-for-all-electron-2" />
      <updated>2017-01-23T12:41:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European - Press release Commission Brussels, 10 January 2017 The Commission is proposing new legislation to ensure stronger privacy in electronic communications, while opening up new business opportunities. The measures presented today aim to update current rules, extending their scope to all electronic communication providers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fitness-wristbands-violate-european-law</id>
      <title>Fitness wristbands violate European law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fitness-wristbands-violate-european-law" />
      <updated>2016-11-03T16:47:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several fitness wristbands violate Norwegian and European consumer and privacy legislation. The Norwegian Consumer Council is submitting a formal complaint against four companies to the Norwegian Data Protection Authoritiy and the Consumer Ombudsman.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-dynamic-ip-addresses-are-private-hands-off-snoops-sort</id>
      <title>CJEU says dynamic IP addresses are private</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-dynamic-ip-addresses-are-private-hands-off-snoops-sort" />
      <updated>2016-11-02T18:51:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Your dynamic IP address is private if it can be tied to other pieces of information you supply.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ceta-signature-ignores-agreements-flaws</id>
      <title>CETA signature ignores Agreement’s flaws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ceta-signature-ignores-agreements-flaws" />
      <updated>2016-10-31T09:29:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 30 October 2016, Comprehensive Economic Trade Agreement (CETA) will be signed between Canada and the European Union. The text includes special rights for corporations, new obligations on so-called “intellectual property rights” and measures which create significant risks for citizens’ fundamental rights, most notably with regard to privacy and data protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Civil society has repeatedly raised concerns about the lack of democracy and transparency of the negotiation process, problems related to the protection of the personal data of European citizens, the investment court system (ICS) introduced in the agreement to allow corporations to challenge government decisions, and the inclusion of intellectual property rights (IPR) to the agreement without debate, including measures that resemble very closely the text of Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement (ACTA) that was rejected by the European Parliament in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/assessing-the-impact-of-data-protection-dpo-edps-meeting-in-alic</id>
      <title>Assessing the impact of data protection: DPO-EDPS meeting in Alicante</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/assessing-the-impact-of-data-protection-dpo-edps-meeting-in-alic" />
      <updated>2016-11-02T19:05:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Assessing the impact of data protection: DPO-EDPS meeting in Alicante.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/from-personality-to-property-data-protection-needs-competition-c</id>
      <title>From personality to property: data protection needs competition and consumer protection law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/from-personality-to-property-data-protection-needs-competition-c" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:07:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Will personal data become a property right licensed to those who give you the best deal for it? Researchers at a conference convened by the Max-Planck Institute on Innovation and Competition in Munich delved into a future “holistic approach” of intellectual property, data and consumer protection, with additional assistance from competition law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-camp-2017-call-for-submissions</id>
      <title>Privacy Camp 2017: Call for submissions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-camp-2017-call-for-submissions" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:21:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Held every January just before the start of the CPDP conference, the camp brings together civil society, policy-makers and academia to discuss existing and looming problems for human rights in the digital environment. As every year, the event is co-organised by EDRi, Privacy Salon, USL-B and VUB-LSTS.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ai-predicts-outcome-of-human-rights-cases</id>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence predicts outcome of human rights cases</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ai-predicts-outcome-of-human-rights-cases" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T15:39:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A research project has found that an AI could accurately predict the outcome of legal cases nearly 80% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/corporate-sponsored-privacy-confusion-in-the-eu-on-trade-and-dat</id>
      <title>Corporate-sponsored privacy confusion in the EU on trade and data protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/corporate-sponsored-privacy-confusion-in-the-eu-on-trade-and-dat" />
      <updated>2016-10-20T15:07:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/privacy-shield-privacy-sham/&quot;&gt;Privacy shield&lt;/a&gt;” was adopted on 12 July 2016, the European Commission started internal discussions about whether or not to include “data flows” and “data localisation” clauses in &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/breaking-ttip-leaks-confirm-dangers-for-digital-rights/&quot;&gt;Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership&lt;/a&gt; and in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/tisa-leaks-set-alarm-bells-ringing/&quot;&gt;Trade in Services Agreement&lt;/a&gt;. It appears that the European Commission Directorate-General for Justice and Consumers (DG Justice) initially accepted the inclusion of clauses on forced, unjustified “data localisation”, but not on transfers of data. However, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.euractiv.com/section/trade-society/news/european-commission-paralysed-over-data-flows-in-tisa-trade-deal/&quot;&gt;EurActiv&lt;/a&gt;, DG Justice has backed down and accepted a weakening of its position on data protection and privacy in order to placate industry, after a campaign based on dubious assertions and backed up by the US government.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-endorse-new-surveillance-powers-bbc-news</id>
      <title>Swiss endorse new surveillance powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/swiss-endorse-new-surveillance-powers-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2016-10-01T01:54:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Swiss voters have given a strong approval to a law on new surveillance powers for the intelligence agencies. The new law would allow the authorities to tap phones, snoop on email and deploy hidden cameras and bugs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-weaken-security-says-uks-new-european-commi</id>
      <title>Encryption backdoors weaken security says UK’s new European Commissioner</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-weaken-security-says-uks-new-european-commi" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T15:16:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julian King, the UK’s new European Commissioner said that he believed encryption backdoors would weaken the online ecosystem as a whole. Regarding data protection questions he would “respect purpose limitations,” citing recent court rulings in the Digital Rights Ireland and the Max Schrems cases. Moreover, despite the ongoing controversy over PNR, King said he wanted to implement existing instruments “to the full.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-opinion-canada-pnr-deal-cannot-be-signed</id>
      <title>European Court Opinion: Canada PNR deal cannot be signed</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-opinion-canada-pnr-deal-cannot-be-signed" />
      <updated>2016-09-08T13:10:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 8 September 2016, the Advocate General of the Court of Justice of the European Union gave his Opinion confirming that the agreement between EU and Canada to share Passenger Name Records data is not fully in compliance with European law. The EU-Canada agreement is the least restrictive PNR agreement that the EU has so far adopted.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/enditorial-when-crypto-is-outlawed-only-outlaws-will-have-crypto</id>
      <title>France and Germany ask EC to draft a backdoor law for encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/enditorial-when-crypto-is-outlawed-only-outlaws-will-have-crypto" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:26:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French and German Ministers of Interior asked the European Commission on 23 August to draft a new law that would require services such as Telegram to cooperate with the decryption of encrypted communications.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In their joint press statement, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.interieur.gouv.fr/Le-ministre/Interventions-du-ministre/Initiative-franco-allemande-sur-la-securite-interieure-en-Europe&quot;&gt;French Minister of Interior Bernard Cazeneuve stated&lt;/a&gt; that for law enforcement purposes, the conversations people have via apps such as Telegram have to be accessible to the police and secret services.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-europols-plans-to-increase-surveillance-1</id>
      <title>New documents reveal Europol’s plans to increase surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-europols-plans-to-increase-surveillance-1" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T19:20:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Europol work programme until the end of the year 2016 reveals that the agency’s goals are to gradually expand its surveillance capacities, to facilitate cross-border access to data, and increase the use of biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-europols-plans-to-increase-surveillance</id>
      <title>New documents reveal Europol’s plans to increase surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-documents-reveal-europols-plans-to-increase-surveillance" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:35:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Europol work programme until the end of the year 2016 reveals that the agency’s goals are to gradually expand its surveillance capacities, to facilitate cross-border access to data, and increase the use of biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In August 2016, the German news site Netzpolitik.org &lt;a href=&quot;https://netzpolitik.org//wp-upload/2016/08/europol_information_exchange_interoperability.pdf&quot;&gt;leaked a document&lt;/a&gt; which provides an overview of Europol’s planned activities.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-and-germany-fighting-terrorism-by-weakening-encryption</id>
      <title>France and Germany: Fighting terrorism by weakening encryption</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-and-germany-fighting-terrorism-by-weakening-encryption" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:29:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 23 August, the French and German Ministers of Interior met in Paris to discuss an initiative that would extend surveillance in Europe and weaken encryption, in the name of the fight against terrorism. Speaking at a joint press conference, French Minister of Interior Bernard Cazeneuve and his German counterpart Thomas de Maizière called for legislation that would force intermediaries to weaken encryption standards.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/massive-lobby-against-personal-communications-security-has-start</id>
      <title>Massive lobby against personal communications security has started</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/massive-lobby-against-personal-communications-security-has-start" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:41:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since 2002, European citizens’ freedom of communication, the security of our communications devices, and the protection of our personal data in the online world have been safeguarded by the so-called e-Privacy Directive. This Directive is now up for renewal.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-privacy-watchdogs-vow-to-thoroughly-frisk-privacy-shield-next</id>
      <title>Privacy Shield still presents a number of concerns, DPAs say</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-privacy-watchdogs-vow-to-thoroughly-frisk-privacy-shield-next" />
      <updated>2016-08-08T13:46:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Article 29 Working Party (WP29) agreed that while Privacy Shield is an improvement on Safe Harbour, it&#039;s still potted with shortcomings. In its &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.co.uk/tech-policy/2016/04/privacy-shield-us-surveillance-eu-article-29-working-party/&quot;&gt;first opinion&lt;/a&gt; on the draft text in April, the WP29 was highly critical of the proposed deal. Following its meeting on Monday, the group admitted that the final version has addressed some of its issues, but by no means all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-appear-on-eu-data-chiefs-ban-wishlist</id>
      <title>Encryption backdoors appear on EU data chief’s ban wishlist</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/encryption-backdoors-appear-on-eu-data-chiefs-ban-wishlist" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:52:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Revised ePrivacy laws should guarantee confidentiality of communications and encourage encryption, the European Union’s data watchdog has said. European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) Giovanni Buttarelli published his &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2016/16-07-22_Opinion_ePrivacy_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;official opinion&lt;/a&gt; on the review of the ePrivacy Directive on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An overhaul to the so-called Cookie Law is currently be worked on by officials at the European Commission, with the completion date expected before the end of the year to bring it into line with the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-confirms-strict-safeguards-essential-for-data-ret</id>
      <title>European Court confirms: Strict safeguards essential for data retention</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-confirms-strict-safeguards-essential-for-data-ret" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:44:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, on 19 July 2016, the Advocate General Henrik Saugmandsgaard Øe of the Court of Justice of the European Union issued an Opinion on a case Tele2 Sverige AB v Post- och telestyrelsen (C-203/15) that deals with data retention obligations that were imposed by law on a Swedish telecom provider.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Court was asked a set of questions related to the respect of European Union law, in the context of the data retention laws in Sweden and the UK. In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2016-07/cp160079en.pdf&quot;&gt;Opinion&lt;/a&gt; issued today, the AG re-stated principles that were previously established in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?docid=150642&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;pageIndex=1&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;cid=334440&quot;&gt;Digital Rights Ireland case&lt;/a&gt;. He also provided extensive further analysis of the legal context that national courts need to consider when they “rigorously verify that no other measure or combination of measures” can be as effective as the national data retention regime being proposed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-shield-more-robust-and-sustainable-solution-needed</id>
      <title>Privacy Shield: more robust and sustainable solution needed</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-shield-more-robust-and-sustainable-solution-needed" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:53:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EDPS statement regarding the Privacy Shield: &quot;as it stands is not robust enough to withstand future legal scrutiny before the Court. Significant improvements are needed should&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; European&amp;nbsp; Commission&amp;nbsp; wish&amp;nbsp; to&amp;nbsp; adopt&amp;nbsp; an&amp;nbsp; adequacy&amp;nbsp; decision,&amp;nbsp; to&amp;nbsp; respect&amp;nbsp; the essence of key data protection principles with particular regard to necessity, proportionality and redress mechanisms. Moreover, it’s time to develop a longer term solution in the transatlantic dialogue.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDPS &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2016/16-05-30_Privacy_Shield_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/PressNews/Press/2016/EDPS-2016-11-PrivacyShield_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-just-published</id>
      <title>General Data Protection Regulation just published</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-just-published" />
      <updated>2016-06-15T00:55:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The text of the General Data Protection Regulation has been published and it is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=OJ%3AL%3A2016%3A119%3ATOC&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ad-blocker-blocking-websites-face-legal-peril-at-hands-of-privac</id>
      <title>Ad-blocker blocking websites must ask for permission before probing your browser</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ad-blocker-blocking-websites-face-legal-peril-at-hands-of-privac" />
      <updated>2016-05-03T18:04:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Under EU law in force since May 2011, people must give their consent before an anti-ad-blocker script can run and hide content on a page.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-reform-parliament-approves-new-rules-fit-for-the</id>
      <title>Data protection reform - Parliament approves new rules fit for the digital era</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-reform-parliament-approves-new-rules-fit-for-the" />
      <updated>2016-05-30T14:03:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New EU data protection rules which aim to give citizens back control of their personal data and create a high, uniform level of data protection across the EU fit for the digital era was given their final approval by MEPs on Thursday. The reform also sets minimum standards on use of data for policing and judicial purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-internet-freedom-programme-endangered-by-commission</id>
      <title>EU internet freedom programme endangered by Commission</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-internet-freedom-programme-endangered-by-commission" />
      <updated>2016-02-16T23:58:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission appears to have shelved a landmark programme that gave out aid money to help human rights workers, protestors and journalists access the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-open-letter-on-eu-us-data-transfer</id>
      <title>Civil society open letter on EU-US data transfer</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-open-letter-on-eu-us-data-transfer" />
      <updated>2016-10-24T16:06:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 6 October 2015, the European Court of Justice (ECJ) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/safe-harbor-repealed-cjue&quot;&gt;invalidated the Safe Harbor&lt;/a&gt;, the agreement concluded in 2000 with the USA in order to give a legal framework to data transfers between the European Union and the USA. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;W29&lt;/a&gt;, a working group bringing together all Member States&#039; national data protection authorities, waited until the end of January for the European Commission to draft a new agreement taking into account the requirements of the ECJ. This agreement called &quot;Privacy Shield&quot; was announced on &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-16-216_en.htm&quot;&gt;2 February&lt;/a&gt; but only contains vague promises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-co-hosts-the-privacy-camp-26-january-2016</id>
      <title>EDRi co-hosts the Privacy Camp</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-co-hosts-the-privacy-camp-26-january-2016" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:23:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the run up to CPDP conference in Brussels, civil society groups met at the fifth annual Privacy Camp to exchange views and develop new strategies. This year’s conference took place under the title “The Multiple Ways of (De/Self)-Regulation: What is at stake for Human Rights?” and included various panels and speakers from around the EU and the US involved in privacy activism.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-transfers-will-not-be-blocked-by-dpas</id>
      <title>EU-US data transfers will not be blocked by DPAs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-transfers-will-not-be-blocked-by-dpas" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:42:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Article 29 Working Party, the body made up of representatives of individual European Member States’ data protection authorities (DPAs), has said today that it will not be taking enforcement action against companies that are using alternative transfer mechanisms in the wake of last year’s Safe Harbor strikedown.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/whats-behind-the-privacy-shield</id>
      <title>What’s behind the Privacy Shield?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/whats-behind-the-privacy-shield" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:46:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An agreement on data transfers has been reached, but the document has not been published.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-cybersecurity-directive-finalised-the-knights-who-say-nis</id>
      <title>EU Cybersecurity Directive finalised</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-cybersecurity-directive-finalised-the-knights-who-say-nis" />
      <updated>2016-04-01T15:51:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union has finalised its first pan-European cybersecurity rules. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2015/12/pdf/st15229-re02_en15_pdf/&quot;&gt;Directive on the Security of Network and Information Systems&lt;/a&gt; (NIS) is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security&quot;&gt;EU cybersecurity strategy&lt;/a&gt; launched in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NIS Directive requires EU member states to develop and implement strict security and notification requirements for “operators of essential services” such as internet exchange points, and more flexible rules for so-called digital service providers, meaning companies that provide cloud computing services, online search engines, and online marketplaces. As we discuss below, there are potential risks for privacy in this approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/at-what-age-should-teenagers-pass-the-digital-age-of-consent</id>
      <title>At what age should teenagers pass the &#039;digital age of consent&#039;?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/at-what-age-should-teenagers-pass-the-digital-age-of-consent" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:29:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union’s new data protection rules have finally been agreed by the European Council and await the approval of the European Parliament. But a last-minute addition has sparked a debate about responsibility and consent, by proposing to raise to 16 the “age of consent” under which it is illegal for organisations to handle the individual’s data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-final-version</id>
      <title>General Data Protection Regulation final version</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-final-version" />
      <updated>2016-10-19T22:53:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Civil Liberties Committee of the European Parliament and the EU member states agreed on a final version of the long-awaited &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statewatch.org/news/2015/dec/eu-council-dp-reg-draft-final-compromise-15039-15.pdf&quot;&gt;General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt; (GDPR), which is aimed at updating EU data protection rules for the digital age. This regulation will replace the 1995 Data Protection Directive and harmonise data protection — its terms and conditions — across EU member states.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new rules will ensure individuals are in control of their own data, providing for a long list of users’ rights and a clear set of obligations for companies. At first glance, “obligations” might seem like a headache for businesses that have difficulty meeting their responsibility to respect human rights. However, having harmonised rules across the EU will provide legal certainty and lower the administrative burden.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/will-the-european-parliament-ask-court-whether-isds-is-legal</id>
      <title>Will the European Parliament ask Court whether ISDS is legal?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/will-the-european-parliament-ask-court-whether-isds-is-legal" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:57:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a letter to the European Parliament, Dutch EDRi member Vrijschrift suggests the Parliament ask the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) whether the investor-to-state dispute settlement (ISDS) is compatible with the EU treaties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vrijschrift points out that the ISDS in the trade agreement with Singapore would expose our privacy to interference, expose the EU to claims for damages, compromise the independence of our data protection authorities, and compromise the effectiveness of the Court of Justice of the EU. In essence, the ISDS places investment tribunals above democracies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-agrees-draft-text-of-pan-european-data-privacy-rules</id>
      <title>EU agrees draft text of pan-European data privacy rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-agrees-draft-text-of-pan-european-data-privacy-rules" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:01:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new data privacy laws comprise of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which governs the use and privacy of EU citizens’ data, and the Data Protection Directive, which governs the use of EU citizens’ data by law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new privacy regulations aim to create strong data protection law for Europe’s 500 million citizens, streamline legislation between the 28 member states pushing a digital single market and boost police and security cooperation. It is set to replace the outdated patchwork of national rules that have only allowed for small fines in cases of violation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-adopts-surveillance-resolution-aimed-at-mass</id>
      <title>European Parliament adopts surveillance resolution aimed at mass surveillance and prompting progress on Safe Harbor 2.0</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-adopts-surveillance-resolution-aimed-at-mass" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:03:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On October 29, 2015, the European Parliament adopted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://datamatters.sidley.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/getDoc.pdf&quot;&gt;resolution&lt;/a&gt; on the electronic mass surveillance of EU citizens. Positioned as a follow-up to its &lt;a href=&quot;http://datamatters.sidley.com/european-parliament-votes-to-approve-new-eu-data-protection-regulation-and-immediate-suspension-of-safe-harbor-2/&quot;&gt;resolution of 12 March 2014&lt;/a&gt; in which the Parliament called for the immediate suspension of Safe Harbor and put forward a number of recommendations to limit access to personal data of European citizens as part of mass surveillance, the Resolution calls on the European Commission to “reflect immediately on alternatives to Safe Harbor and on the impact of the judgment [from the Court of Justice of the European Union in the Schrems case] on any other instruments for the transfer of personal data to the U.S.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-guidelines-after-safe-harbor-invalidation</id>
      <title>European Commission guidelines after Safe Harbor invalidation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-guidelines-after-safe-harbor-invalidation" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T12:02:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Commission&#039;s explanatory communication analyses the consequences of the judgement and sets out the alternative mechanisms for transfers of personal data to the US. The Commission will also continue to work closely with the independent data protection authorities to ensure a uniform application of the ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines available &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/files/eu-us_data_flows_communication_final.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and FAQ available &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_MEMO-15-6014_en.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/prior-notice-of-personal-data-sharing-between-public-authorities</id>
      <title>Prior notice of personal data sharing between public authorities is required</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/prior-notice-of-personal-data-sharing-between-public-authorities" />
      <updated>2015-11-04T20:22:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Court of Justice of the European Union recently held that personal data cannot be transferred between two public bodies, and subject to further processing, without the data subjects concerned having been informed in advance (&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/celex.jsf?celex=62014CJ0201&amp;amp;lang1=en&amp;amp;type=TXT&amp;amp;ancre&quot;&gt;Smaranda Bara and Others v Președintele Casei Naționale de Asigurări de Sănătate, Casa Națională de Asigurări de Sănătate, Agenția Națională de Administrare Fiscală (ANAF), Case C-201/14&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-legislation-of-a-member-state-may-be-applied-to</id>
      <title>Data protection legislation of a Member State may be applied to a foreign company</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-legislation-of-a-member-state-may-be-applied-to" />
      <updated>2015-11-04T20:18:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The recent European Court of Justice decision in &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2015-10/cp150111en.pdf&quot;&gt;Weltimmo sro v Nemzeti Adatvédelmi és Információszabadság Hatóság C-230/14&lt;/a&gt; provides important guidelines on the competence of, and co-operation between, national data protection authorities. The ECJ has clarified how data protection law applies in cross-border situations within the EU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-resolution-to-award-asylum-protection-for-sn</id>
      <title>European Parliament resolution to award asylum protection for Snowden</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-resolution-to-award-asylum-protection-for-sn" />
      <updated>2015-10-29T20:00:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By 285 votes to 281, MEPs decided to call on EU member states to “drop any criminal charges against Edward Snowden, grant him protection and consequently prevent extradition or rendition by third parties, in recognition of his status as whistle-blower and international human rights defender”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commissioner-announces-further-guidance-on-the-impact-of-the</id>
      <title>EU Commissioner announces further guidance on the impact of the Safe Harbor ruling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commissioner-announces-further-guidance-on-the-impact-of-the" />
      <updated>2015-11-04T19:13:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Monday, October 26, 2015, EU Commissioner for Justice, Consumers and Gender Equality, Věra Jourová, gave a &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_SPEECH-15-5916_en.htm?locale=EN&quot;&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt; before the European Parliament’s Committee on Civil Liberties, Justice and Home Affairs on the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=169195&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=en&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=84927&quot;&gt;ruling&lt;/a&gt; by the Court of Justice of the European Union that invalidated the European Commission’s Safe Harbor Decision. The EU Commissioner welcomed the Article 29 Working Party’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/press-material/press-release/art29_press_material/2015/20151016_wp29_statement_on_schrems_judgement.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; and, in particular, its support for a new Safe Harbor framework by January 31, 2016. However, the EU Commissioner called for more clarity in the meantime. Accordingly, she announced that the European Commission will soon issue an explanatory document on the consequences of the CJEU’s ruling to provide guidance for businesses on international data transfers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/28-october-2015-a-further-step-towards-comprehensive-eu-data-pro</id>
      <title>EDPS recommendations for the police and justice sectors</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/28-october-2015-a-further-step-towards-comprehensive-eu-data-pro" />
      <updated>2017-08-28T20:38:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Data Protection Supervisor issued an &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2015/15-10-28_Directive_Recommendations_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; containing recommendations for the police and justice sectors. EDPS recalls that data protection in the police and justice sectors should be fully consistent with the general rules contained in the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and should only contain specifications and adjustments where necessary in view of the specific nature of these sectors. The scope of the Directive should be limited to the areas where specific rules are really necessary, namely the activities of criminal law enforcement by police and judicial authorities, as was the&amp;nbsp; case&amp;nbsp; in&amp;nbsp; the&amp;nbsp; original&amp;nbsp; proposal&amp;nbsp; of&amp;nbsp; the Commission. Moreover, the performance of law enforcement tasks by non-public entities and organisations should be subject to the GDRP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links to the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/PressNews/Press/2015/EDPS-2015-10-Directive_Police_Justice_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2015/15-10-28_Directive_Recommendations_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-leaders-call-for-robust-legal-framework</id>
      <title>Civil society leaders call for robust legal framework</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-leaders-call-for-robust-legal-framework" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:22:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A group of U.S. and EU digital rights organizations and consumer NGOs have issued a &lt;a href=&quot;http://thepublicvoice.org/NGO-FRF-Statement-ICDPPC37.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; calling for a “meaningful legal framework” to protect fundamental privacy rights in the digital era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The statement comes as a critical response to the publication earlier this month of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://privacybridges.mit.edu/&quot;&gt;Bridges report&lt;/a&gt;: a joint project between U.S. and EU academics — and including the involvement of the Dutch data protection agency — advocating for continued reliance on existing laws coupled with industry self-regulation as a middle-of-the-road approach to safeguarding privacy rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-agree-in-principle-on-new-safe-harbor-framework</id>
      <title>EU-US agree &quot;in principle&quot; on new Safe Harbor framework</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-agree-in-principle-on-new-safe-harbor-framework" />
      <updated>2015-11-04T20:42:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union on Monday said it had agreed in principle with the US on a new trans-Atlantic data-transfer agreement. The negotiations between the EU and U.S. became more urgent after the court’s ruling, which raises questions about how much legal certainty a new version could bring businesses because it enshrines the power for national data protection authorities to independently review, and potentially suspend, data transfers to the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/after-foi-request-epic-obtains-secret-umbrella-agreement-from-th</id>
      <title>After FOI request, EPIC obtains secret &quot;Umbrella Agreement&quot; from the EU Commission</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/after-foi-request-epic-obtains-secret-umbrella-agreement-from-th" />
      <updated>2015-11-01T22:28:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU Commission, in response to a freedom of information request, has released to EPIC the text of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/files/dp-umbrella-agreement_en.pdf&quot;&gt;EU-US data transfer agreement&lt;/a&gt;. US and EU officials &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/2015/09/eu-and-us-reach-agreement-on-d.html&quot;&gt;finalized&lt;/a&gt; the so-called &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/intl/data-agreement/&quot;&gt;&quot;Umbrella Agreement&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in September, but had kept the final document secret. EPIC &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/2015/09/epic-pursues-public-release-of-1.html&quot;&gt;has filed&lt;/a&gt; multiple &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/foia/eu-us-data-transfer/&quot;&gt;FOIA requests&lt;/a&gt; with US federal agencies and the European Commission to obtain public release of the document. The Agreement, alongside the &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/2015/09/epic-recommends-changes-to-jud.html&quot;&gt;Judicial Redress Act&lt;/a&gt;, is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://free-group.eu/2015/10/14/eu-us-umbrella-data-protection-agreement-detailed-analysis-by-douwe-korff/&quot;&gt;key document&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europe-v-facebook.org/EN/en.html&quot;&gt;aftermath&lt;/a&gt; of the European court decision &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/2015/10/european-court-strikes-down-sa.html&quot;&gt;striking down&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;http://epic.org/privacy/intl/schrems/&quot;&gt;Safe Harbor&lt;/a&gt; arrangement. Legal scholars who have reviewed the agreement have &lt;a href=&quot;http://free-group.eu/2015/10/14/eu-us-umbrella-data-protection-agreement-detailed-analysis-by-douwe-korff/&quot;&gt;concluded it is deeply flawed.&lt;/a&gt; EPIC continues to pursue the public release of the Agreement from US federal agencies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/19-october-2015-statement-of-the-article-29-working-party</id>
      <title>Article 29 Working Party statement on the Safe Harbor case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/19-october-2015-statement-of-the-article-29-working-party" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:19:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/press-material/press-release/art29_press_material/2015/20151006_wp29_press_release_on_safe_harbor.pdf&quot;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; on the 6th October, the Article 29 Working Party issued a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/press-material/press-release/art29_press_material/2015/20151016_wp29_statement_on_schrems_judgement.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; regarding the Safe Harbor Decision (&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf;jsessionid=9ea7d0f130d5661d59b92e4e49b28ee58537625f6296.e34KaxiLc3eQc40LaxqMbN4Oc30Pe0?text=&amp;amp;docid=169195&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=en&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=856568&quot;&gt;Schrems v. Data Protection Commissioner&lt;/a&gt; (C-362- 14). Article 29 Working Party calls for a robust, collective and common position on the implementation of the judgment urging Member States and the European institutions to open discussions with US authorities in order to find political, legal and&amp;nbsp; technical solutions enabling data transfers to the territory of the United States that respect fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/press-material/press-release/art29_press_material/2015/20151016_wp29_statement_on_schrems_judgement.pdf&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; from the Article 29 Working Party.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-ministers-reach-agreement-on-data-protection-directive-for-th</id>
      <title>EU ministers reach agreement on Data Protection Directive for the police and criminal justice sector</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-ministers-reach-agreement-on-data-protection-directive-for-th" />
      <updated>2015-11-02T17:23:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, Ministers in the Justice Council have sealed an overall &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.consilium.europa.eu/press-releases-pdf/2015/10/40802203348_en_635799853200000000.pdf&quot;&gt;agreement&lt;/a&gt; on the EU&#039;s Data Protection Directive for the police and criminal justice sector.&amp;nbsp;Trilogues between the Commission, the European Parliament and the Council of the EU on the Directive will begin later this month.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/safe-harbor-abusive-data-collection-and-mass-surveillance-repeal</id>
      <title>Safe Harbor annulled by the European Court of Justice</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/safe-harbor-abusive-data-collection-and-mass-surveillance-repeal" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:20:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By a decision &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net//files/schrems_CJUE.pdf&quot;&gt;published this morning&lt;/a&gt;, the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU), the highest European jurisdiction, repealed the Safe Harbor agreement. This agreement in effect since 2000, allows data transfers between Europe and the United States under different versions, authorised the processing of European citizens&#039; data by US companies, with fewer guarantees than those existing in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Max Schrems, an Austrian citizen, has put Facebook on trial since the monitoring by the NSA of his data hosted by Facebook had an impact on his freedom and privacy. The CJEU today confirmed his viewpoint by invalidating the Safe Harbor and held that the European Commission abused its power by approving it. The CJEU also affirmed that a local data protection authority may dissent a European agreement if guarantees granted to citizens were modified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-asks-public-opinion-on-geo-blocking</id>
      <title>EU asks public opinion on geo-blocking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-eu-asks-public-opinion-on-geo-blocking" />
      <updated>2015-09-24T15:32:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission started two public consultations Thursday, as part of its Digital Single Market strategy. One is about the role of &lt;a href=&quot;https://euobserver.com/news/128806&quot;&gt;online platforms&lt;/a&gt; such as Google and Amazon, and asks whether they should be more transparent. The other asks citizens about their opinion and experience with &lt;a href=&quot;https://euobserver.com/connected/128143&quot;&gt;geo-blocking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Commission wants to hear from citizens, manufacturers, retailers (especially SMEs), right holders, data and cloud service providers and users, as well as all those involved in the collaborative economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please see the press release &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-15-5704_en.htm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/advocate-general-bot-opinion-on-max-schrems-case</id>
      <title>Advocate General Bot opinion on Max Schrems case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/advocate-general-bot-opinion-on-max-schrems-case" />
      <updated>2015-11-01T22:22:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, in case&amp;nbsp;Case C-362/14 Maximillian Schrems v Data Protection Commissioner, Advocate General Yves Bot takes the view that the existence of a Commission decision finding that a third country ensures an adequate level of protection of the personal data transferred cannot eliminate or even reduce the national supervisory authorities’ powers under the directive on the processing of personal data. He considers furthermore that the Commission decision is invalid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2015-09/cp150106en.pdf&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; and the full opinion &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=168421&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=en&amp;amp;mode=lst&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=326249&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-sharing-agreement-to-be-analyzed-by-eu-court</id>
      <title>EU-US data-sharing agreement to be analyzed by EU court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-data-sharing-agreement-to-be-analyzed-by-eu-court" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T12:07:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The case stems from a complaint filed by 27-year-old Austrian law student Max Schrems against Facebook with the Irish data protection commissioner, who monitors compliance with privacy laws. Schrems argued the company helped the NSA harvest email and other private data from European citizens by forwarding data to servers in the United States and asked the Irish watchdog to investigate whether the United States was providing adequate data protection. The Irish regulator rejected the request on the grounds that it was bound by the EU Safe Harbour agreement of 2000 which allows companies to transfer EU citizens&#039; data to the United States because it is held to have sufficient privacy safeguards in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Justice Advocate General Yves Bot will deliver his opinion in Luxembourg on Wednesday at around 9:30 CET. While the court&#039;s judges are not bound by the opinion, they follow it in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-edps-ethics-board</id>
      <title>The new EDPS Ethics Board</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-new-edps-ethics-board" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T18:15:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Giovanni Buttarelli, the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS), recently announced the formation of a new external Ethics Board that will do a deep dive into the complex ethical issues that surround the use of&amp;nbsp; personal data in the “big data” economy. The EDPS is particularly concerned about the rise of artificial intelligence and its implications for personal data protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/PressNews/Press/2015/EDPS-2015-07-EDPS_Data_Ethics_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2014/14-03-26_competitition_law_big_data_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;full opinion&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-umbrella-agreement-could-open-us-courts-to-eu-litigants</id>
      <title>EU-US Umbrella agreement could open US courts to EU litigants</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-umbrella-agreement-could-open-us-courts-to-eu-litigants" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T18:24:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Sept. 8, 2015, the US and EU announced that they finalized an “Umbrella Agreement” establishing a data protection framework for EU-US law enforcement cooperation. The Umbrella Agreement is subject to approval of US Congress as well as the European Parliament and Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Agreement allows data to be transferred between EU and US law enforcement authorities for the purpose of preventing, investigating, detecting or prosecuting criminal offences, including terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the agreement includes the obligation to extend equal treatment to the citizens of the other jurisdiction. That means, for example, that EU citizens will have the right to enforce data protection rights in US courts even if they are not residing in the US. Until now, EU citizens have had little luck enforcing EU law in US courts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-meps-adopt-report-to-help-boost-europes-drones-industry</id>
      <title>MEPs adopt report to help boost Europe&#039;s drones industry</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-meps-adopt-report-to-help-boost-europes-drones-industry" />
      <updated>2015-09-19T23:46:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New rules are needed to ensure safe use of drones, the European Parliament&#039;s transport committee has recommended in a new report. No-fly zones are considered, while no new privacy legislation needed, according to UK conservative MEP Jacqueline Foster, steering the new rules through a Parliament plenary vote end of October.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-statement-on-national-data-retention-laws-2</id>
      <title>European Commission statement on national data retention laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-statement-on-national-data-retention-laws-2" />
      <updated>2015-09-23T18:27:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On September 16, the European Commission has reiterated in a statement that the decision of whether or not to introduce national data retention laws is a national decision and that it is not going to start a court action against the German draft data retention law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission is neither opposing, nor advocating the introduction of national data retention laws. Therefore, the Commission is not coming forward with any new initiatives on Data Retention. In the absence of EU rules, Member States are free to maintain their current data retention systems or set up new ones, providing of course they comply with basic principles under EU law, such as those contained in the ePrivacy Directive.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/11-september-2015-towards-a-new-digital-ethics</id>
      <title>EDPS opinion on Towards a new digital ethics</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/11-september-2015-towards-a-new-digital-ethics" />
      <updated>2015-09-11T17:09:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Data Protection Supervisor published an opinion highlighting some of the major technology trends which may involve unacceptable processing of&amp;nbsp; personal information or may interfere with the right to privacy. It outlines a four-tier ‘big data protection ecosystem’ to respond to the digital challenge. The EDPS has also announced the establishment of an external Ethics Board, that will help to better assess the ethical implications of how personal information is defined and used in the big data and artificial intelligence driven world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Opinion follows on from the previous &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2015/15-07-27_GDPR_Recommendations_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;Opinion on the General Data Protection Regulation&lt;/a&gt; which aimed to assist the main institutions of the EU in reaching the right&amp;nbsp; consensus on workable, future-oriented set of rules which enable and promote the rights and freedoms of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/Consultation/Opinions/2015/15-09-11_Data_Ethics_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;Opinion &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/PressNews/Press/2015/EDPS-2015-07-EDPS_Data_Ethics_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-tools</id>
      <title>Data Protection Tool</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-tools" />
      <updated>2015-09-11T16:33:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Signatu is a free cloud service (SaaS) which makes it easy and safe for your company to author, integrate and track privacy terms for your users, in compliance with the upcoming EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tool is complex and offers the possibility&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to create privacy terms and policies based on a questionnaire, track user’s consent and withdrawal of consent or rack user’s requests to exercise their data protection rights. At the same time it offers demonstration and verification of GDRP-compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please note that &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://signatu.com&quot;&gt;signatu&lt;/a&gt; is still in beta v1 for testing. Signatu is established in Norway and co-founded by the data engineer, Torgeir Hovden (formerly at Microsoft and technology director at Telenor) and the data protection law expert, Georg Philip Krog (former scholar at the Faculty of law in Oslo, Max Planck Institut in Hamburg, Fulbright Scholar at Stanford Law School and Fulbright Scholar at Harvard Law School).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/parliament-calls-for-stricter-controls-over-surveillance-tech-ex</id>
      <title>Parliament calls for stricter controls over surveillance tech exports</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/parliament-calls-for-stricter-controls-over-surveillance-tech-ex" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T23:28:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament gave the green light on Tuesday&amp;nbsp;(8 September) to a non-binding resolution calling for safeguards to ensure technology isn’t implicated in human rights abuse, especially when it’s exported outside of Europe for surveillance or censorship purposes. A European Commission proposal is expected next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dutch MEP Marietje Schaake drafted at her own initiative a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?type=REPORT&amp;amp;mode=XML&amp;amp;reference=A8-2015-0178&amp;amp;language=EN&quot;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on ‘Human rights and technology: the impact of intrusion and surveillance systems on human rights in third countries’. The surveillance report faced the first plenary session after the summer break and was approved with 371 votes in favour, 293 against and 43 abstentions yesterday afternoon in Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-clinch-data-sharing-deal-for-security-terrorism-cases-docu</id>
      <title>EU-US Umbrella agreement</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-clinch-data-sharing-deal-for-security-terrorism-cases-docu" />
      <updated>2015-11-11T21:29:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union and the United States have clinched a deal protecting personal data shared for law enforcement purposes such as terrorism investigations, according to a document seen by Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two sides have been negotiating for four years over the so-called &quot;umbrella agreement&quot; that would protect personal data exchanged between police and judicial authorities in the course of investigations, as well as between companies and law enforcement authorities.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statement-by-eu-commissioner-vera-jourova-on-the-finalisation-of</id>
      <title>Statement by EU Commissioner Věra Jourová on the finalisation of the EU-US negotiations on the data protection &quot;Umbrella Agreement&quot;</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statement-by-eu-commissioner-vera-jourova-on-the-finalisation-of" />
      <updated>2015-09-09T20:34:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU Commissioner Věra Jourová: &quot;I am very pleased that today we have finalised negotiations with the US on high data protection standards for transatlantic law enforcement cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robust cooperation between the EU and the US to fight crime and terrorism is crucial to keep Europeans safe. But all exchanges of personal data, such as criminal records, names or addresses, need to be governed by strong data protection rules. This is what the Umbrella Agreement will ensure.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/report-on-human-rights-and-technology-the-impact-of-intrusion-an</id>
      <title>Report on ‘Human rights and technology: the impact of intrusion and surveillance systems on human rights in third countries’</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/report-on-human-rights-and-technology-the-impact-of-intrusion-an" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T13:56:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On September 8th, the European Parliament will vote in the plenary meeting on Marietje Schaake’s Report on ‘Human rights and technology: the impact of intrusion and surveillance systems on human rights in third countries’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In February, Marietje Schaake (ALDE/D66) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marietjeschaake.eu/2015/02/call-for-input-on-report-human-rights-and-technologies/&quot;&gt;called for input&lt;/a&gt; for her draft report. By sharing the draft, Schaake invited anyone from hackers to journalists, activists and lawyers, to share their comments. The draft report also built on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marietjeschaake.eu/2015/01/video-hearing-on-human-rights-and-technologies/&quot;&gt;public hearing&lt;/a&gt; which took place on 21 January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To read the report please click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marietjeschaake.eu/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/REPORT-on-Human-rights-and-technology-the-impact-of-intrusion-and-surveillance-systems-on-human-rights-in-third-countries-20142232INI.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-challenges-french-order-on-the-right-to-be-forgotten</id>
      <title>Google challenges French order on the right to be forgotten</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-challenges-french-order-on-the-right-to-be-forgotten" />
      <updated>2015-08-19T14:35:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google disagrees with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnil.fr/english/news-and-events/news/article/cnil-orders-google-to-apply-delisting-on-all-domain-names-of-the-search-engine&quot;&gt;order&lt;/a&gt; from the French Data Protection Authority to apply the right to be forgotten to all its search results around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, CNIL ordered Google to remove search results meeting “right to be forgotten” criteria from any regional version of Google’s search engine. However, granting CNIL’s request could have a “serious chilling effect on the web,” Google said Thursday in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlepolicyeurope.blogspot.co.uk/2015/07/implementing-european-not-global-right.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/status-update-of-data-retention-in-the-eu-following-the-cjeu-rul</id>
      <title>Status update on data retention in the EU following the CJEU ruling (April 2015)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/status-update-of-data-retention-in-the-eu-following-the-cjeu-rul" />
      <updated>2015-08-20T02:32:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In December 2014 ORG prepared a table showing the status of data retention in the EU, following the CJEU&#039;s decision in the Digital Rights Ireland case. We have now updated the table to show the position in April 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The table can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openrightsgroup.org/assets/files/legal/Data_Retention_status_table_updated_April_2015_uploaded_finalwithadditions.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-tells-its-publisher-partners-to-comply-with-eu-cookie-dir</id>
      <title>Google tells its publisher partners to comply with EU cookie directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/google-tells-its-publisher-partners-to-comply-with-eu-cookie-dir" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T15:01:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google is now requiring that publishers that carry its ads comply with a European Union directive and ask their site visitors’ for permission before setting cookies on their computers. Google spelled out the requirement in its new &lt;a href=&quot;http://adsense.blogspot.ie/2015/07/introducing-new-user-consent-policy.html&quot;&gt;EU User Consent Policy&lt;/a&gt; for publishers that participate in services including AdSense, DoubleClick Ad Exchange and DoubleClick for Publishers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If your websites are getting visitors from any of the countries in the European Union, you must comply with the EU user consent policy. We recommend you start working on a policy-compliant user consent mechanism today,” said Jason Woloz, Google’s security and privacy program manager for display and video ads, in a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-criticises-air-passenger-bill</id>
      <title>EDPS criticises air passenger bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-criticises-air-passenger-bill" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T19:11:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Giovanni Buttarelli criticizes the Passenger Names Records (PNR) law saying it makes more sense to target specific categories of flights, passengers, and countries and declaring it as too invasive and unlikely to stop terrorism. “I’m still waiting for the relevant evidence to demonstrate, even in terms on the amount of money, and years to implement this system, how much it is essential,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His comments come after MEPs in the civil liberties committee on 15 July agreed a legislative proposal that will allow the collection of detailed information – such as credit card details and addresses – of all people flying in and out of the EU. Buttarelli is due to give a formal opinion on it in September.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-adopts-proposal-on-airline-passengers-data-sharing</id>
      <title>EU Parliament adopts proposal on airline passengers data sharing</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-adopts-proposal-on-airline-passengers-data-sharing" />
      <updated>2015-08-21T20:53:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, the European Parliament’s Committee on Civil Liberties (LIBE) adopted the EU Passenger Name Records (EU-PNR) directive proposal, presented by Rapporteur Timothy Kirkhope, a conservative MEP from the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU-PNR directive would establish the systematic collection, retention, and analysis of passenger data for everyone flying into or leaving the EU. Passenger data contains a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/jan/28/european-commission-blanket-collection-passenger-data&quot;&gt;plethora of personal information&lt;/a&gt;, such as passengers’ personal and contact details, itinerary, payment methods, and sometimes even car and hotel bookings.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-annual-report-2014</id>
      <title>EDPS annual report 2014</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-annual-report-2014" />
      <updated>2015-07-03T01:56:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The press release commenting on the data protection reform is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/PressNews/Press/2015/EDPS-2015-05-EDPS_AR2014_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please read EDPS Annual Report 2014 &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/Publications/Annualreport/2014/EDPS_Annual_Report_2014_Web_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-asks-the-european-commission-to-investigate-illegal-data-re</id>
      <title>EDRi asks the European Commission to investigate illegal data retention laws in the EU</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-asks-the-european-commission-to-investigate-illegal-data-re" />
      <updated>2015-07-03T01:59:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;European Digital Rights (EDRi) sent &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://edri.org/files/DR_EDRi_letter_CJEU_Timmermans_20150702.pdf&quot;&gt;a letter to European Commission First Vice-President Frans Timmermans&lt;/a&gt;, asking the European Commission to investigate the data retention laws in EU Member States which appear to be illegal in light of the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) ruling on this issue from 8 April last year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/afet-committee-adopts-its-report-on-human-rights-and-technology</id>
      <title>AFET Committee adopts its Report on Human rights and technology</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/afet-committee-adopts-its-report-on-human-rights-and-technology" />
      <updated>2015-07-01T22:09:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament Committee on Foreign Affairs (AFET) adopted its Report on “Human rights and technology: the impact of intrusion and surveillance systems on human rights in third countries” on 26 May 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Report aimed at providing input in order to help create smart European legislation which deals adequately with all the concerns, but at the same time takes into account new technological solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-document-pool</id>
      <title>EDRi&#039;s document pool on the General Data Protection Regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/general-data-protection-regulation-document-pool" />
      <updated>2015-06-25T12:51:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January 2012, the European Commission, following extensive consultations, published a draft Regulation. After 3 years of discussion following the first proposal being made by the European Commission (and a first reading by the European Parliament that was finalised in 2014), the Council has decided to agree on a new text (a “&lt;b&gt;general approach&lt;/b&gt;“) that will be the object of current trialogues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The trilogue discussions between the three institutions officially started on 24 June 2015 with the first meeting in Brussels. In order to explain the process, EDRi will be publishing information and analysis in a document pool which will be updated as the negotiations advance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-reform-on-track-for-adoption-in-2015</id>
      <title>Data protection reform on track for adoption in 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-reform-on-track-for-adoption-in-2015" />
      <updated>2015-06-25T12:38:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read Commissioner &#039;s Jourová remarks after the launch of the Data protection regulation trilogue: We are on track to adopt the data protection reform in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-eurobarometer-2015</id>
      <title>Data protection Eurobarometer 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-eurobarometer-2015" />
      <updated>2015-06-25T12:41:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The protection of personal data remains an important concern for citizens, according to a new Eurobarometer published by the European Commission today (24 June 2015) on data protection. The central finding of the survey shows that trust in digital environments remains low. Two-thirds of the respondents (67%) say that they are worried about having no control over the information they provide online, while only 15% feel they have complete control.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-groups-attack-latest-eu-data-protection-proposals-it-pro</id>
      <title>Privacy groups criticize latest EU data protection proposals</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/privacy-groups-attack-latest-eu-data-protection-proposals-it-pro" />
      <updated>2015-06-21T11:38:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU&#039;s Justice Council &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-15-5176_en.htm?locale=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;yesterday agreed&lt;/a&gt; on a definitive proposal for a General Data Protection Regulation that would replace the old 1995 Data Protection Directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Privacy campaigners have dismissed the latest proposal for new pan-European data protection laws as “meaningless”, saying the rules will not strengthen individuals&#039; rights over their personal information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-and-digital-rights-the-booklet</id>
      <title>TTIP and Digital Rights: the Booklet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-and-digital-rights-the-booklet" />
      <updated>2015-06-08T23:16:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, European Digital Rights (EDRi) is publishing its latest booklet, “TTIP and digital rights”: The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) is a trade agreement that is currently being negotiated between the United States and the European Union. TTIP has already raised many concerns among civil society, trade unions, consumer groups, some businesses, and European and national institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-reform-enters-final-discussion-stage</id>
      <title>EU Data Protection reform enters final discussion stage</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-reform-enters-final-discussion-stage" />
      <updated>2015-05-25T17:14:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First proposed at the start of 2012, the data protection reform has already gone through the European Parliament, which adopted its version in March last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five chapters remain to be wrapped up at the EU Presidency level in the next few weeks. They include issues on data subject rights, sanctions, definitions, final provisions, and the complex legal interpretations of implemented and delegated acts (secondary legislation).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/second-internet-privacy-engineering-network-ipen-workshop</id>
      <title>Second Internet Privacy Engineering Network (IPEN) Workshop</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/second-internet-privacy-engineering-network-ipen-workshop" />
      <updated>2015-05-25T17:56:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;The second edition of the Internet Privacy Engineering Network (IPEN) workshop will take place on 5 June 2015 at KU Leuven. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/edps/pid/612&quot;&gt;draft programme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/eusurvey/runner/IPEN-2nd-Workshop-Leuven&quot;&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;IPEN is an initiative launched by the European Data Protection Supervisor (EDPS) aiming to bring together developers and data protection experts with a technical background from different areas in order to launch and support projects that build privacy into everyday tools and develop new tools which can effectively protect and enhance our privacy. More information is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/edps/EDPS/IPEN&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The report of the first IPEN workshop is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/IPEN/15-01-22_IPEN_Report_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/la-quadrature-du-net-warns-that-the-european-commission-must-pro</id>
      <title>La Quadrature du Net warns that the European Commission must protect fundamental rights in the digital age</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/la-quadrature-du-net-warns-that-the-european-commission-must-pro" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T22:53:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/news/2015/05/20150506_en.htm&quot;&gt;published on 6 May&lt;/a&gt; its strategy for 2020 and the setting up of the Digital Single Market. Several important digital issues are concerned by this agenda: from copyright to crime, from telecommunications to VAT harmonisation. While La Quadrature du Net welcomes the Commission&#039;s engagement with these issues, it does this only with caution as previous attempts were harmful to the protection of fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Commission&#039;s strategy already started with the proposal on personal data protection and the proposal on telecommunications. These two currently negotiated regulations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laquadrature.net/en/council-of-the-european-union-to-kill-net-neutrality-we-must-act&quot;&gt;raise&lt;/a&gt; serious concerns on the risks they represent to a number of fundamental principles of the Internet and the right of personal data protection.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-keynote-speech-on-recent-developments-in-data-protection</id>
      <title>EDPS keynote speech on recent developments in data protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edps-keynote-speech-on-recent-developments-in-data-protection" />
      <updated>2015-05-12T12:05:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&quot;Big data, big data protection: challenges and innovative solutions&quot;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edps.europa.eu/EDPSWEB/webdav/site/mySite/shared/Documents/EDPS/Publications/Speeches/2015/15-05-11_ERA_speech_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;keynote speech&lt;/a&gt; given by Giovanni Buttarelli at ERA Conference on Recent Developments in Data Protection Law.&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-close-to-complete-negociation-in-data-protection</id>
      <title>EU &amp; US close to complete negociation in data protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-us-close-to-complete-negociation-in-data-protection" />
      <updated>2015-05-11T12:02:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;The two sides have been negotiating since 2011 over the so-called &quot;umbrella agreement&quot; that would protect personal data exchanged between police and judicial authorities in the course of investigations, as well as between companies and law enforcement authorities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;The European Commission, which leads the negotiations on behalf of the EU, has said that it aims to complete those negotiations before the summer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-under-siege-slams-european-privacy-regulators</id>
      <title>Facebook criticizes European privacy regulators</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebook-under-siege-slams-european-privacy-regulators" />
      <updated>2015-04-29T21:53:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook has warned that overlapping national probes into its privacy policy could severely endanger the European Union’s economy if such a fragmented strategy is continued and applied to other businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data protection authorities from Belgium, the Netherlands and Germany &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pcworld.com/article/2879872/eu-data-protection-authorities-get-serious-about-facebooks-privacy-policy.html&quot;&gt;in February formed a task force to deal with Facebook’s new privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;, introduced late January. They suspect that the new policy violates EU privacy laws. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/facebook-confronts-european-probes-1427975994&quot;&gt;French, Spanish and Italian authorities later joined the group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/emergency-call-system-mandatory-for-new-cars-in-eu</id>
      <title>Emergency call system mandatory for new cars in EU</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/emergency-call-system-mandatory-for-new-cars-in-eu" />
      <updated>2015-04-29T22:10:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament on Tuesday voted to adopt mandatory installation of an EU emergency call system called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/ecall-time-saved-lives-saved&quot;&gt;eCall&lt;/a&gt; in new cars from 31 March 2018. When a car with eCall is involved in a crash, the system automatically makes contact with the nearest emergency centre.&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/45d709ff/sc/21/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-proposal-on-airline-passenger-data-sharing-no-still-means-no</id>
      <title>Access comments the EU revised proposal on airline passenger data sharing</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-proposal-on-airline-passenger-data-sharing-no-still-means-no" />
      <updated>2015-04-21T15:09:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 26 February 2015, MEP Timothy Kirkhope presented to the European Parliament’s Committee on Civil Liberties (LIBE) a revised draft of the European Union Passenger Name Records proposal (see revisions &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/news-room/content/20150223IPR24702/html/Changes-to-planned-European-Passenger-Name-Record-%28PNR%29-system-discussed-by-MEPs&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this latest revision to the PNR proposal doesn’t make many improvements when it comes to protecting private information. To make matters worse, &lt;a href=&quot;http://audiovisual.europarl.europa.eu/Assetdetail.aspx?id=d9149905-6653-4c38-a296-a44b00a8fadd&quot;&gt;several MEPs&lt;/a&gt; have proposed extending this type of data collection to other means of transport. This reinforces our concern that adoption of the PNR proposal could lead to the normalisation of mass surveillance, spreading to other areas of EU citizens’ personal life.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-groups-from-around-the-world-call-on-ec-to-defend-priva</id>
      <title>Citizens’ groups from around the world call on EC to defend privacy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-groups-from-around-the-world-call-on-ec-to-defend-priva" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T09:22:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The institutions of the European Union are completing a reform of Europe’s Data Protection framework. Recognising the huge significance of the reform, the European Commission made an unequivocal promise when it launched the process. As an “absolute red line”, the level of protection of individuals’ data would not fall below existing levels. However, leaks show that this promise is not being kept.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sixty-six NGOs from the European Union, North, Central and South America, Africa, Asia and Australia have joined forces to ask for a confirmation from European Commission President Jean-Claude Juncker that the promise will be respected.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo</id>
      <title>Leaked Digital Single Market strategy addresses copyright and geo-blocking, e-privacy and the role of ISPs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T11:17:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leaked copies of the upcoming Digital Single Market Strategy and its supporting Evidence file show the European Commission is ready to propose vast regulatory reforms that could affect everything from sales taxes and e-privacy to Internet searches and big data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-and-privacy-must-be-excluded-from-ttip</id>
      <title>Data protection and privacy must be excluded from TTIP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/data-protection-and-privacy-must-be-excluded-from-ttip" />
      <updated>2015-04-09T00:58:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data protection is a contentious issue in the discussions about the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) and other trade or investment agreements, such as the Trade in Services Agreement (TiSA). Now that the European Parliament is preparing to issue a non-legislative resolution on TTIP, various parliamentary committees are giving their input to the committee in charge, the Committee on International Trade (INTA).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-does-not-plan-a-new-data-retention-law</id>
      <title>EU does not plan a new data retention law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-does-not-plan-a-new-data-retention-law" />
      <updated>2015-03-21T13:15:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;articleText&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;focusParagraph&quot;&gt;The European Commission will not introduce a new law requiring telecom companies to store the communications data of European Union citizens for security purposes, the EU home affairs commissioner said on Thursday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-documents-reveal-governments-efforts-to-weaken-eu-data-pr</id>
      <title>Leaked documents reveal governments&#039; efforts to weaken EU data protection proposed regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-documents-reveal-governments-efforts-to-weaken-eu-data-pr" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:58:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;German diplomatic cables and thousands of pages of leaked classified EU documents reveal behind-the-scenes efforts by governments to weaken the EU’s data protection bill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LobbyPlag.eu, which obtained the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lobbyplag.eu/governments/documents&quot;&gt;cables and documents&lt;/a&gt;, on Tuesday (10 March), found that 132 of 151 (87%) changes by member states lowered privacy protections.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/revelations-on-safe-harbour-violations-go-to-hearing-at-eu-court</id>
      <title>Revelations on Safe Harbour violations go to hearing at EU Court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/revelations-on-safe-harbour-violations-go-to-hearing-at-eu-court" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T09:29:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In late 2012, Max Schrems, a privacy advocate and member of the Europe v Facebook group requested that the Irish Data Protection Commissioner investigate the alleged sharing of European Facebook users’ information with the United States National Security Agency (NSA), in the light of the Snowden revelations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These revelations suggest that Facebook and the US government had violated the Safe Harbour arrangement, which aimed at guaranteeing the privacy of EU citizens and regulates the transfer of personal data from the European Union to the United States. When the Irish Data Protection Commissioner refused to investigate the case, Schrems appealed to the Irish High Court. The Court’s decision centred around whether the European Commission’s decision on Safe Harbour in 2000 was binding and therefore not subject to investigation by the Irish Data Protection Commissioner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Schrems case, to which EDRi-member Digital Rights Ireland is attached as an amicus curiae, will have a hearing at the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) on 24 March.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-documents-show-european-data-protection-reform-is-badly-b-1</id>
      <title>Leaked documents show European data protection reform is badly broken</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-documents-show-european-data-protection-reform-is-badly-b-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:39:06+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, leading digital rights organizations — including Access, EDRi, Privacy International, and Panoptykon — published new leaked documents showing that European Union member states are working to undermine the right to personal data protection for citizens.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-governments-punch-holes-in-eu-data-protection-bill</id>
      <title>National governments punch holes in EU data protection bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-governments-punch-holes-in-eu-data-protection-bill" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T20:11:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;National governments are unraveling a EU data protection bill for the benefit of big business, according to leaked documents published by pro-privacy campaigners.&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/43fffd83/sc/7/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raegan MacDonald, European policy manager at Access, accused the member states of “carving out so many loopholes there’ll soon be nothing left.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-intra-eu-flights-to-be-included-in-passenger-data-checks</id>
      <title>Intra-EU flights to be included in passenger data checks</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-intra-eu-flights-to-be-included-in-passenger-data-checks" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:08:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new EU system for the use of Passenger Name Record (PNR) data would include intra-EU flights and require sensitive data be kept for minimum 30 days, according to the draft text discussed in the civil liberties committee on Thursday. The committee rejected a 2011 draft directive in April 2013.&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/43d230ee/sc/24/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/222166600113/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43d230ee/sc/24/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/scottish-plans-for-central-identity-database-spark-privacy-criti</id>
      <title>Scottish plans for central identity database spark privacy criticism</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/scottish-plans-for-central-identity-database-spark-privacy-criti" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T16:19:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/a&gt; and civil rights campaigners have urged the Scottish government to drop plans for a new identity database which could allow public bodies, including tax authorities, to share every adult’s private data. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gov.scot/Publications/2014/12/5990/0&quot;&gt;Public consultation&lt;/a&gt; on the proposal, which has faced intense opposition in the Scottish parliament after the scale and reach of the project came to light, ended on 25 February.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-hidden-cameras-legitimate-journalism-tool-court-says</id>
      <title>Hidden cameras legitimate journalism tool, court says</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ticker-hidden-cameras-legitimate-journalism-tool-court-says" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:27:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Human Rights on Tuesday ruled that journalists should be able to use hidden cameras when reporting on issues of public interest. The case was brought by four Swiss journalists convicted for invasion of privacy following their use of a hidden camera to report on insurance scams.&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/43c545de/sc/24/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;zxiuvrcpdbtjfikvrabb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/222166543922/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/43c545de/sc/24/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebooks-privacy-policy-breaches-european-law-report-finds-1</id>
      <title>Facebook’s privacy policy breaches European law, report finds</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/facebooks-privacy-policy-breaches-european-law-report-finds-1" />
      <updated>2015-02-23T20:26:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A report commissioned by the Belgian privacy commission has found that Facebook is acting in violation of European law, despite updating its privacy policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conducted by the Centre of Interdisciplinary Law and ICT at the University of Leuven in Belgium, &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.law.kuleuven.be/icri/en/news/item/icri-cir-advises-belgian-privacy-commission-in-facebook-investigation&quot;&gt;the report&lt;/a&gt; claimed that Facebook’s privacy policy update in January had only expanded older policy and practices, and found that it still violates European consumer protection law.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the report, Facebook’s policies around profiling for third-party advertising do not “meet the requirements for legally valid consent”, while the social network “fails to offer adequate control mechanisms” with regard to the use of user-generated content for commercial purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/parliament-votes-to-push-forward-its-agenda-eu-pnr</id>
      <title>Parliament votes to push forward its agenda EU-PNR</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/parliament-votes-to-push-forward-its-agenda-eu-pnr" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:41:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 11th, the European Parliament has adopted a resolution in which it commits to work toward finalising, by the end of 2015, a directive on EU Passenger Name Records (PNR). This proposal aims at the systematic data collection, retention and analysis by national authorities of passengers taking flights entering or leaving the EU. This data, originally collected by airline companies, contains &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/jan/28/european-commission-blanket-collection-passenger-data&quot;&gt;plethora of personal data&lt;/a&gt;, from passengers’ personal and contact details, itinerary, payment methods, to sometimes even food preferences.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/isds-one-month-after-the-results-of-the-public-consultation</id>
      <title>ISDS – one month after the results of the public consultation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/isds-one-month-after-the-results-of-the-public-consultation" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:26:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;National sovereignty of the EU Member States and the rule of law would be endangered if Investor-State Dispute Settlement (ISDS) was part of the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP). Respondents to the public consultation conducted by the European Commission (EC) between March and July 2014 made it clear that they oppose ISDS, but the Commission doesn’t seem to be taking their opinion into account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 13 January 2015 the EC presented the results of the public consultation on ISDS. A month later, the Commission’s strategy seems to be a quiet but strong defence of ISDS.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-vote-a-resolution-on-airline-passenger-bill</id>
      <title>MEPs vote a resolution on airline passenger bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meps-vote-a-resolution-on-airline-passenger-bill" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T18:27:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Police are a step closer to gaining broad access to the personal details of anyone flying in or out of Europe after EU lawmakers on Wednesday (11 February) agreed to break a deadlock on a stalled EU bill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Euro-deputies in Strasbourg voted on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-%2f%2fEP%2f%2fTEXT%2bMOTION%2bP8-RC-2015-0122%2b0%2bDOC%2bXML%2bV0%2f%2fEN&amp;amp;language=EN&quot;&gt;resolution&lt;/a&gt; with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//NONSGML+AMD+P8-RC-2015-0122+004-004+DOC+PDF+V0//EN&quot;&gt;amendment&lt;/a&gt; to reach an agreement on the EU’s passenger name (EU PNR) record bill by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-a-peek-into-the-negotiations</id>
      <title>TTIP: a peek into the negotiations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ttip-a-peek-into-the-negotiations" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:05:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the 8th round of the TTIP negotiations just ended in Brussels, Access reflects on the state of play of this major transatlantic trade deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-authorities-investigate-facebooks-new-privacy</id>
      <title>EU data protection authorities investigate Facebook&#039;s new privacy policy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-data-protection-authorities-investigate-facebooks-new-privacy" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:59:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Union’s data protection authorities are getting serious about issues with Facebook’s new privacy policy. They have formed a task force which will deal with part of the policy that could very well violate EU privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The task force was formed on Tuesday during a meeting of European data protection authorities and will be led by Belgium, the Netherlands, Germany and perhaps Italy, said the spokeswoman for Bart Tommelein, Belgium’s state secretary for privacy. The data protection authorities (DPAs) for instance take issue with Facebook’s practice of following its users off site, collecting information when they use third-party websites and apps that use a Facebook “like” button, a Facebook log-in or Facebook’s measurement and advertising services. What’s more, the authorities don’t like Facebook claiming the right to use information and photos from user profiles for commercial purposes and take issue with Facebook sharing personal user data with third parties, she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/passenger-tracking-in-the-eu-will-be-as-invasive-as-it-is-in-the</id>
      <title>Passenger tracking in the EU will be as invasive as it is in the US</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/passenger-tracking-in-the-eu-will-be-as-invasive-as-it-is-in-the" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:14:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the debate over an EU-wide scheme continues, the same scheme has been operating for all flights between EU member states and the US since 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blanket mass surveillance was instigated by the US in the wake of the 9/11 terrorist attacks, but put airlines in a bind: the US Department of Homeland Security demands the information from them, but European data protection law bars the transfer of data outside the EU.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-calls-for-swift-passage-of-law-to-collect-flight-passenge</id>
      <title>Europe calls for swift passage of law to collect flight passengers’ data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/europe-calls-for-swift-passage-of-law-to-collect-flight-passenge" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:00:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European executive on Wednesday called for the prompt passage of legislation to collect and retain information on anyone flying into or out of the EU, as part of a package of counter-terror policies following the jihadi attacks in Paris and alleged foiled terrorist murders in Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/european-commission&quot;&gt;European commission&lt;/a&gt; note seen by the Guardian calls for the swift adoption of the collection of passenger name records, including bank details, mobile numbers and meal preferences, for those flying in and out of the EU and their retention for up to five years for access by the police and security services.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/vice-president-ansip-and-commissioner-jourova-concluding-the-eu</id>
      <title>Vice-President Ansip and Commissioner Jourová: Concluding the EU Data Protection Reform is essential for the Digital Single Market</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/vice-president-ansip-and-commissioner-jourova-concluding-the-eu" />
      <updated>2015-03-25T14:12:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vice-President Ansip and Commissioner Jourová released an announcement on the EU Data Protection Reform. In their note, the commissioners urge for quick adoption of newly prepared reform which is a necessary part allowing creation of European Digital Single Market.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-internet-firms-to-hand-over-encryption-keys</id>
      <title>EU wants internet firms to hand over encryption keys</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-internet-firms-to-hand-over-encryption-keys" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:37:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A top EU official wants internet and telecommunication companies to hand over encryption keys to police and spy agencies as part of a wider crackdown on terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The EU’s counter-terrorism co-ordinator Gilles de Kerchove, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statewatch.org/news/2015/jan/eu-council-ct-ds-1035-15.pdf&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; leaked by London-based civil liberties group Statewatch, says the European Commission should come up with rules that require the firms to help national governments snoop on possible suspects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/calls-for-isps-to-filter-content-could-be-illegal-eu-council-doc</id>
      <title>Calls for ISPs to filter content could be illegal, EU council documents suggest</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/calls-for-isps-to-filter-content-could-be-illegal-eu-council-doc" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:45:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week justice ministers from across the European Union called on ISPs to conduct voluntary censorship of online content—but documents in preparation for a meeting of telecoms ministers suggest such a move could be illegal. The documents, prepared by the Latvian presidency of the Council of the EU, note that calls to allow Internet service providers to block or filter content in the “public interest” as part of a proposed net neutrality law could violate privacy laws that protect the confidentiality of communication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-latest-proposals-from-council-undermines-protection-from-pro</id>
      <title>The latest proposals from Council undermines protection from profiling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-latest-proposals-from-council-undermines-protection-from-pro" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:48:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest proposals from the Council seek to further undermine protection from profiling. The draft text from the Council not only re-inserts profiling into the (absurdly long) list of measures in the Regulation that Member States can choose not to impose, it also increases the range of justifications for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-comments-on-the-legal-service-opinion-on-cjeu-data-retentio</id>
      <title>EDRi comments on the legal service opinion on CJEU data retention ruling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/edri-comments-on-the-legal-service-opinion-on-cjeu-data-retentio" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:47:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament (EP) legal services last week presented an opinion on the Court of Justice of the EU’s (CJEU) ruling on the Data Retention Directive (DRD) and its implications. The opinion, after restating the principles that are essential to permit any interference on fundamental rights (proportionality, justification and necessity), answered specific questions raised by the Civil Liberties, Justice and Home Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/paris-attack-prompts-calls-for-greater-security-powers</id>
      <title>Paris attack prompts calls for greater security powers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/paris-attack-prompts-calls-for-greater-security-powers" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:49:54+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A number of officials and ministers are calling for expanded surveillance and security powers in the wake of the Charlie Hebdo attack in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The head of the UK’s domestic intelligence service MI5, Andrew Parker, on Thursday (8 January) said it needs greater snooping powers to stop Islamist militants from carrying out attacks in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parker said some privacy rules need to be roll backed in order for the agency to properly conduct its operations, warning more attacks are “highly likely”, reports the Guardian newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-european-parliament-legal-study-on-data-retention</id>
      <title>Leaked European Parliament legal study on data retention</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-european-parliament-legal-study-on-data-retention" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:39:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament legal services will release its long-awaited study on the Court of Justice of the EU’s ruling on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2014/04/11/a-closer-look-at-eu-courts-ruling-and-what-it-means-for-the-future-of-data-&quot;&gt;Data Retention Directive&lt;/a&gt;. Access obtained a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/page/-/eu_data_retention.pdf&quot;&gt;copy of the document&lt;/a&gt;, which concludes that the EU’s powers to legislate on data retention matters are now limited.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-negotiating-texts-in-ttip</id>
      <title>EU negotiating texts in TTIP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-negotiating-texts-in-ttip" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:52:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) between Europe and the United States have been published by the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-proposed-trade-secrets-directive-risks-eu-free-speec</id>
      <title>Open Letter: Proposed trade secrets directive risks EU free speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-proposed-trade-secrets-directive-risks-eu-free-speec" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:35:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Quadrature du Net signs an open letter written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://haieurope.org/&quot;&gt;Health Action International Europe&lt;/a&gt; against the directive&#039;s project on trade secrets. Initiated by the business community, put forward by the Member States and the European Commission, it gives the possibility for private companies to sue any person that &quot;unlawfully acquires, uses or discloses&quot; the &quot;trade secrets&quot;. Whistleblowers are poorly protected in this text, the directive creates a judiciary insecurity as it will dissuade from leaking from private companies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-joint-statement-on-european-values</id>
      <title>Article 29 joint statement on European values</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-joint-statement-on-european-values" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:57:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The National Law Review announced that on November 26, the Article 29 Working Party released a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/documentation/opinion-recommendation/files/2014/wp227_en.pdf&quot;&gt;short joint statement&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;containing a series of declarations on: &amp;nbsp;(i) “European values”; (ii) “surveillance for security purposes”; and (iii) the “European influence”. The joint statement emphasizes the balance to be struck between protecting data protection rights and allowing national intelligence agencies to perform their duties, and the fundamental importance of European data protection rights more generally. These affirmations are particularly significant in the context of both the Snowden revelations and the ongoing Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/households-who-use-cctv-cameras-violate-data-protection-law</id>
      <title>Households who use CCTV cameras violate data protection law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/households-who-use-cctv-cameras-violate-data-protection-law" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:20:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EU judges have said private households who use CCTV cameras to film people in public spaces outside their house violate data protection law. The case stems from a Czech man who filmed vandals attacking his house and gave the recordings to Czech police.&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://feeds.euobserver.com/c/748/f/9610/s/415ef1fd/sc/1/mf.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br clear=&quot;all&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951246872/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/415ef1fd/sc/1/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;display: none !important; &quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/215951246872/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/415ef1fd/sc/1/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/215951246872/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/415ef1fd/sc/1/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/two-meps-votes-againts-closed-sessions-on-safe-harbour</id>
      <title>Two MEPs voted againts closed sessions on Safe Harbour</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/two-meps-votes-againts-closed-sessions-on-safe-harbour" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:18:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eu Observer reports that MEP German Cornelia Ernst along with Dutch liberal Sophie In&#039;t Veld voted to suspend the so-called in-camera session on Safe Harbour. In-camera sessions are not open to the public. It also means MEPs are under threat of sanctions should they discuss the issue outside the room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Safe Harbour is enforced by the US Federal Trade Commission and is supposed to ensure US firms follow EU data protection laws when processing the personal data of EU citizens. Last November, the former EU justice commissioner Viviane Reding published 13 recommendations that the Americans needed to implement in order to keep the agreement viable. The commission official, invited to update the MEPs on the negotiations, revealed that Washington has an issue with three of the 13 recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;ycthyoxtvxvllycihfdb&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;display: none !important; &quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612663822/u/197/f/9610/c/748/s/41589874/sc/7/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-working-document-on-surveillance-electronic-communica</id>
      <title>Article 29 working document on surveillance, electronic communications and national security</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-working-document-on-surveillance-electronic-communica" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:36:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On December 5, the Article 29 Working Party published a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/documentation/opinion-recommendation/files/2014/wp228_en.pdf&quot;&gt;Working Document&lt;/a&gt; on surveillance, electronic communications and national security. The Working Document is specifically intended to address data protection issues arising out of the Snowden revelations that began in 2013 and the bulk data collection activities of various intelligence and security agencies. The Working Document examines the boundaries between the concepts of privacy and national security, and emphasizes the importance of privacy as a fundamental right in the EU. The Working Document concludes that the activities of intelligence and security agencies should not always fall within the scope of the national security exemption under EU data protection law, and that where the meaning of the term “national security” is unclear, the exemption should be construed narrowly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-wants-an-agreement-on-pnr</id>
      <title>European commissioner wants an agreement on PNR</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissioner-wants-an-agreement-on-pnr" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:40:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament recently&amp;nbsp;voted in favour of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/news-room/content/20141121IPR79818/html/MEPs-refer-EU-Canada-air-passenger-data-deal-to-the-EU-Court-of-Justice&quot;&gt; resolution&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to refer the EU-Canada agreement on PNR to the Court of Justice to deliver an opinion of its compliance with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:C:2010:083:0389:0403:en:PDF&quot;&gt; Charter of Fundamental Rights&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;After this vote, members of the European Parliament and digital rights activists expected the legislative debate on the EU PNR directive to be postponed until the CJEU’s assessment was released. Unfortunately, Commissioner Avramopoulos decided not to wait for the opinion and signaled his desire to quickly reach an agreement on the 2011 directive. To the surprise of many Parliamentarians at the hearing,&amp;nbsp;the Home Affairs Commissioner said the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accessnow.org/blog/2014/04/11/a-closer-look-at-eu-courts-ruling-and-what-it-means-for-the-future-of-data-&quot;&gt; landmark CJEU&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;ruling on data retention was “&lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_SPEECH-14-2351_en.htm&quot;&gt;a different scheme than the PNR&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-guidelines-on-google-vs-spain-case</id>
      <title>Article 29 guidelines on Google vs Spain case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-guidelines-on-google-vs-spain-case" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:40:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November Article 29 Working Party published &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/documentation/opinion-recommendation/files/2014/wp225_en.pdf&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on the implementation of the Google vs Spain case.&amp;nbsp;In May, the European Court of Justice ruled that private individuals in Europe have the right to request search engines to de-index specific URLs containing their name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-proposal-for-automated-car-emergency-calls-addresses-privacy</id>
      <title>EU proposal for automated car emergency calls addresses privacy concerns</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-proposal-for-automated-car-emergency-calls-addresses-privacy" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T19:54:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;A law that would &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/news-room/content/20141201IPR81901/html/MEPs-back-deal-with-Council-on-automatic-emergency-call-system-for-cars&quot;&gt;require all new car models and light commercial vehicles to be equipped with the technology from March 2018&lt;/a&gt; was backed by a committee of Members of the European Parliament (MEPs) on Thursday. Parliament had in 2012 called for the system to be implemented by next year, but the proposal was delayed for various reasons, including privacy concerns.&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-canada-agreement-on-pnr-referred-to-the-cjeu</id>
      <title>EU-Canada agreement on PNR referred to the CJEU</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-canada-agreement-on-pnr-referred-to-the-cjeu" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T13:37:30+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 25 November the European Parliament voted, by 383 votes to 271, in favour of a resolution to refer the EU-Canada agreement on Passenger Name Records (PNR) to the European Court of Justice (CJEU). The CJEU will now decide on the compliance of the agreement with EU law, in particular the Charter of Fundamental Rights. As explained in previous EDRi-gram articles, PNR data has become an attractive and invasive source for governments to obtain personal data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-working-document-on-contractual-clauses</id>
      <title>Article 29 working document on contractual clauses</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/article-29-working-document-on-contractual-clauses" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:58:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SCL -&amp;nbsp;The IT Law Community wrote about Article 29 Working Party&#039;s Working Document Setting Forth a Co-Operation Procedure for Issuing Common Opinions on &quot;Contractual clauses&quot; Considered as compliant with the EC Model Clauses&#039; which was&amp;nbsp;adopted on 26 November. The Working Document sets out in its introduction the need for a new procedure and recognises some of the current difficulties faced by lawyers in seeking approval.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meet-the-eus-new-privacy-watchdogs</id>
      <title>Meet the EU’s new privacy watchdogs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/meet-the-eus-new-privacy-watchdogs" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:01:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, the conference of presidents of the &lt;span class=&quot;c0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c6&quot; href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/aboutparliament/en/00766d87cc/Political-bodies.html&quot;&gt; European Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;gave its &lt;span class=&quot;c0&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;c6&quot; href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/news-room/content/20141127IPR81016/html/Giovanni-Buttarelli-named-new-data-protection-watchdog&quot;&gt; final&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; approval to the appointments of Giovanni Buttarelli and Wojciech Rafał Wiewiórowski to become the new heads of the European Union Data Protection Authority.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/guidelines-on-the-implementation-of-google-vs-spain-decision</id>
      <title>Guidelines on the implementation of Google vs Spain decision</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/guidelines-on-the-implementation-of-google-vs-spain-decision" />
      <updated>2014-11-28T17:19:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The judgment of the Court of Justice of European Union (CJEU) of 13 May 2014 Google Spain SL and Google Inc. v Agencia Española de Protección de Datos (AEPD) and Mario Costeja González (C-131/12) sets a milestone for EU data protection in respect of search engines and, more generally, in the online world.&lt;br /&gt;It grants the possibility to data subjects to request to search engines, under certain conditions, the delisting of links appearing in the search results based on a person’s name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday 26 November, the European data protection authorities assembled in the Article 29 Working Party (WP29) have adopted guidelines on the implementation of the CJEU’s judgment. These guidelines contain the common interpretation of the ruling as well as the common criteria to be used by the data&lt;br /&gt;protection authorities when addressing complaints.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-approves-facebooks-takeover-of-whatsapp</id>
      <title>EU approves Facebook&#039;s takeover of WhatsApp</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-approves-facebooks-takeover-of-whatsapp" />
      <updated>2014-10-08T11:58:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU&#039;s competition authorities on Friday gave social media site Facebook the green light to complete its €15bn takeover of mobile messaging startup WhatsApp.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/giving-european-citizens-the-data-protection-rules-they-deserve</id>
      <title>Giving European citizens the data protection rules they deserve</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/giving-european-citizens-the-data-protection-rules-they-deserve" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T11:51:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p class=&quot;A_Standard__35__20_Normal&quot;&gt;The Court decision highlights the urgency of reform. The ruling on the right to be forgotten is a milestone in the enforcement of European&amp;nbsp;citizens&#039; fundamental right to data protection. The Court had to step in and take a stance because Europe lacks modern data protection rules that are fit for the internet age.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-right-to-be-forgotten-and-the-eu-data-protection-reform-why</id>
      <title>The right to be forgotten and the EU data protection reform: Why we must see through a distorted debate and adopt strong new rules soon</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-right-to-be-forgotten-and-the-eu-data-protection-reform-why" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T11:56:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The recent ruling by the European Court of Justice on the right to be forgotten does not give the all-clear for people or organisations to have content removed from the web simply because they find it inconvenient. Far from it. It calls for a balance between the legitimate interests of internet users and citizens&#039; fundamental rights. A balance that will have to be found in each case.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fnf-2014-brussels-privacy-advocates-summit-to-tackle-surveillanc</id>
      <title>FNF 2014: Brussels privacy advocates summit to tackle surveillance, censorship, net discrimination</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/fnf-2014-brussels-privacy-advocates-summit-to-tackle-surveillanc" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T13:42:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Between 26 and 29 September, the annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedomnotfear.org/&quot;&gt;Freedom not Fear (FNF)&lt;/a&gt; conference and barcamp will take place in Brussels. Privacy advocates will tackle surveillance, censorship, net discrimination. Simon Davies,&amp;nbsp;publisher of the Privacy Surgeon and co-founder of Privacy International, will present the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.privacysurgeon.org/blog/incision/global-security-analysis-reveals-widespread-government-apathy-following-snowden-disclosures/&quot;&gt;first &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.privacysurgeon.org/blog/incision/global-security-analysis-reveals-widespread-government-apathy-following-snowden-disclosures/&quot;&gt;global analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the impact of the Snowden revelations and Paul Nemitz, Director at DG Justice of the European Commission, will discuss the data protection reform and the future of the EU-US umbrella and Safe Harbor agreements.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-to-googles-advisory-council-on-the-right-to-be-forgo</id>
      <title>Open letter to Google’s Advisory Council on the “right to be forgotten”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-to-googles-advisory-council-on-the-right-to-be-forgo" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T15:26:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 9 September, European and international civil rights organisations submitted an open letter (&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://edri.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Open-Letter-to-Google-Advisory-Council.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;) to Google’s Advisory Council on their assessment of the so-called “right to be forgotten”. The groups urge the Council’s members to avoid inadvertently delaying the adoption of the data protection reform package.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
