<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/Privacy/RO/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for Privacy in RO</title>
  <updated>2017-09-22T23:04:01+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/human-rights-court-sets-limits-on-right-to-monitor-employees</id>
      <title>Human Rights Court sets limits on right to monitor employees</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/human-rights-court-sets-limits-on-right-to-monitor-employees" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:04:01+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 5 September 2017, the Grand Chamber of the European Court for Human Rights (ECtHR) ruled on the Bărbulescu v. Romania case. It found that there was a breach of the right to family life and correspondence (Article 8 of the European Convention on Human Rights), as claimed by Mr Bărbulescu.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-draft-law-on-national-e-identity-cards-in-romania</id>
      <title>New draft law on national e-identity cards in Romania</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-draft-law-on-national-e-identity-cards-in-romania" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:26:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new proposal does not bring improvements from the law adopted in 2012 and lacks an impact assessment. The proposed law is under public consultation until 29 March 2017 and Romanian digital rights NGO ApTI submitted a written opinion to the Ministry of Internal Affairs regarding the implications the new provisions might have on the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The opinion is available in Romanian &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apti.ro/sites/default/files/Opinie-ApTI-carte-identitate-electronica.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-mass-surveillance-project-disguised-as-egovernment-1</id>
      <title>Romania: Mass surveillance project disguised as eGovernment</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-mass-surveillance-project-disguised-as-egovernment-1" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:52:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Romanian Intelligence Services (SRI) has been recently granted EU funds for the project “SII Analytics” to acquire software and hardware for “consolidating and assuring eGovernment interoperability between public information systems”. The project seems to aim at gathering all major state owned databases (e.g. citizens and company registry, health card data, fiscal data) in SRI’s playground. The data would be joined into one large system, through which other public institutions would potentially have unlimited and unwarranted access to the personal data collected.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-secret-services-uses-european-funding-for-mass-surveill</id>
      <title>Romanian Secret Services uses European funding for mass surveillance project disguised as eGovernment services</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-secret-services-uses-european-funding-for-mass-surveill" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T19:56:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Romanian Secret Service (SRI) is granted European funding in order to acquire software and hardware for “increasing eGovernment system usage”. However, as the technical specifications of the project show, one of its declared purposes is to design a Big Brother system that will, among others, intercept Internet traffic from instant messaging apps or other similar electronic communications programmes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entitled SII Analytics, the project aims at aggregating data sets from all major public institutions and at allowing advanced search in order to permit inquiring any type of information about any citizen or resident. Moreover, the project includes a chapter on behaviour analysis, which will allow to correlate information from databases as well as other public information (such as Facebook account information) and create individual profiles. Additionally, the system will have facial recognition features and it will include a database of approximately 50-60 million images (passport or identity card photos) to which SRI will have unlimited access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the project flagrantly violates Articles 7 and 8 of the Charter of Fundamental Rights of the European Union, namely the rights to privacy and to personal data protection, several NGOs sent a letter to Romanian and European officials urging for the public procurement to be annulled.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-for-sound-cybersecurity-regulation</id>
      <title>Romania: Open letter for sound cybersecurity regulation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-for-sound-cybersecurity-regulation" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:56:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.mcsi.ro/Transparenta-decizionala/Proiecte-2016/Securitatea-cibernetica/lege-securitate-cibernetica&quot;&gt;new cybersecurity law proposal&lt;/a&gt; has been published and ApTI - the Association for Technology and Internet launched an open letter describing 5 sound principles which should be taken into consideration by the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This proposal follows last year&#039;s Constitutional Court&#039;s decision against the cybersecurity law. Unfortunately, the new version does not bring sufficient changes. More information is available in English on &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/romanian-cybersecurity-law-reloaded/&quot;&gt;EDRI&#039;s website&lt;/a&gt; and in Romanian on &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/2016/02/09/scrisoare-deschisa-pentru-o-securitate-informatica-sanatoasa-5-principii-pentru-un-act-normativ-coerent/&quot;&gt;privacy.apti.ro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/private-messages-at-work-can-be-read-by-european-employers-bbc-n</id>
      <title>Private messages at work can be read by European employers</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/private-messages-at-work-can-be-read-by-european-employers-bbc-n" />
      <updated>2016-02-02T21:59:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Employers can read workers&#039; private messages sent via chat software and webmail accounts during working hours, the European Court of Human Rights ruled in Barbulescu vs. Romania.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, as &lt;a href=&quot;https://privacy.apti.ro/2016/01/13/viata-privata-la-locul-de-munca-exista-sau-mai-pe-larg-despre-ce-a-decis-cedo-in-cazul-barbulescu-vs-romania/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (available only in Romanian) analyses this does not mean that there is no privacy at the working space and that the employer is able to monitor the employees without discretion.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/camera-deputailor-din-postura-de-camer-decizonal-adopt-in-goana</id>
      <title>Fast track adoption for ePrivacy law ammendments</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/camera-deputailor-din-postura-de-camer-decizonal-adopt-in-goana" />
      <updated>2015-10-09T09:47:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/2015/09/22/societatea-civila-deranjeaza-coreografia-democratiei-dambovitene-sau-postmortem-opinie-pe-modificarea-legii-5062004-privind-prelucrarea-datelor-cu-caracter-personal/&quot;&gt;simulating a debate in the Legal Commission&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdep.ro/pls/proiecte/upl_pck2015.proiect?idp=15116&quot;&gt;proposal for amending the ePrivacy law&lt;/a&gt; was rapidly adopted by the Deputy Chamber with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdep.ro/pls/steno/evot2015.data?dat=20150923&quot;&gt;majority of votes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Association for Technology and Internet (ApTI) wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/2015/09/21/opinie-pe-modificarea-legii-5062004-privind-prelucrarea-datelor-cu-caracter-personal/&quot;&gt;opinion&lt;/a&gt; indicating several issues, however despite &lt;a href=&quot;http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/opinie-pe-modificarea-legii-5062004-privind-prelucrarea-datelor&quot;&gt;being invited&lt;/a&gt; to participate in a debate organized by the Legal Commission, none of the points raised were given any attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/opinie-pe-modificarea-legii-5062004-privind-prelucrarea-datelor</id>
      <title>New provisions amending the ePrivacy law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/opinie-pe-modificarea-legii-5062004-privind-prelucrarea-datelor" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T10:21:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 7th of September, the Romanian Senate swiftly adopted a modification proposal for Law 506/2004 on privacy and data protection in the electronic communications sector. The proposal is now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdep.ro/pls/proiecte/upl_pck2015.proiect?idp=15116&quot;&gt;under review in the Chamber of Deputies&lt;/a&gt; with very tight deadlines for debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Association for Technology and Internet (ApTI) has received an invitation from the IT&amp;amp;C Committee to take part in a joint meeting with the Legal Committee on Tuesday, the 22nd of September at 11:00. In reply to the invitation, ApTI prepared a written opinion with several remarks regarding the new amendments. The document is available in Romanian &lt;a href=&quot;http://apti.ro/sites/default/files/Opinie-ApTI-proiect-modif-506.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-mass-surveillance-provisions-the-national-database-with-tour</id>
      <title>New mass surveillance provisions: the national database with tourists</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-mass-surveillance-provisions-the-national-database-with-tour" />
      <updated>2015-09-22T10:43:53+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 5th of August 2015, the Romanian Ministry of Economy, Commerce and Tourism announced that it will adopt a Governmental Decision for implementing a new integrated system with tourists. The system will be operated by the Special Telecommunications Service (STS) and the Ministry of Administration and Interior (MAI) will have access to the database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposal has deep implications for the right to privacy and the Association for Technology and Internet (ApTI) has sent on the 14th of August an opinion underlining the excessive, disproportionate and illegitimate nature of the new law which allows for new surveillance measures to be put in place. The document is available in Romanian &lt;a href=&quot;http://apti.ro/sites/default/files/opinie-siet-apti.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to our comments, the Ministry of Economy will organize on the 26th of August a public debate. The announcement is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://apti.ro/sites/default/files/Anunt%20intalnire%20publica.docx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-president-asks-for-review-of-big-brother-laws</id>
      <title>Romanian President asks for review of Big Brother laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-president-asks-for-review-of-big-brother-laws" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:24:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Romania’s Operative Council for Cyber Security (COSC) will start this week a review&amp;nbsp;of legislative provisions on access to traffic data and cyber security, also known as the ‘Big Brother’ laws. Romanian President Klaus Iohannis has requested the review, according to a statement of the Presidential Administration. The aim is&amp;nbsp; to overcome the current deadlock by acknowledging the Constitutional Court’s decisions and by providing better public information on legislative measures and their effects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-romanian-cybersecurity-law-is-declared-unconstitutional</id>
      <title>The Romanian cybersecurity law is declared unconstitutional</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-romanian-cybersecurity-law-is-declared-unconstitutional" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:23:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;With majority of votes, the Romanian Constitutional Court decided that the cybersecurity law is unconstitutional. This represents the 4th attempt to pass laws violating human rights under the pretext of fighting terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Association for Technology and Internet (ApTI) together with 14 other NGOs filed an &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/2015/01/19/interventie-ccr-pentru-sustinerea-neconstitutionalitatii-legii-securitatii-cibernetice/&quot;&gt;amicus curiae to support the unconstitutionality claims&lt;/a&gt; (in Romanian). In its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ccr.ro/noutati/COMUNICAT-DE-PRES-141&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt; (in Romanian), the Constitutional Court mentioned not only the articles which were brought into attention by the civil society groups, but also showed that putting the National Security Agency (SRI) in charge of cybersecurity is also unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Background information about the cybersecurity law is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/romanian-cybersecurity-law-sent-to-the-constitutional-court/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-cybersecurity-law-sent-to-the-constitutional-court</id>
      <title>Romanian cybersecurity law sent to the Constitutional Court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanian-cybersecurity-law-sent-to-the-constitutional-court" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:47:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new law on cybersecurity, previously reported in the EDRi-gram, was adopted by the Romanian Parliament at the end of 2014. The law gives the Romanian Intelligence Agency (SRI) access to any computer data owned by private companies, without a court order. The law was sent to the Constitutional Court for analysis and it will be judged on 21 January 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover,&amp;nbsp; the situation regarding surveillance practices in Romania seems to have recently become even blurrier. Even as the events in France were unfolding, a special inter-institutional group formed by several ministries and SRI had already met a couple of times to decide about a revival of the surveillance laws declared unconstitutional in 2014 – the data retention law and the mandatory registration of telephony prepaid cards.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-terrorist-attack-used-as-pretext-for-big-brother-laws</id>
      <title>Romanian authorities are using the French terrorist attack as a pretext to urgently adopt Big Birother laws</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-terrorist-attack-used-as-pretext-for-big-brother-laws" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:04:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, 8 January 2015, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcsi.ro/Minister/Comunicate-de-presa-2014/Grup-interinstitutional-convocat-in-regim-de-urgen&quot;&gt;Ministry for Information Society called&lt;/a&gt; an inter-institutional working group to urgently analyze CJUE data retention decision’s impact on national law. Using the terrorist attacks in France as pretext, Romanian authorities are pushing for the urgent adoption of a package of mass surveillance measures which violate fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This comes in the context of the Parliament&#039;s unanimous vote on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdep.ro/proiecte/2014/200/60/3/pl263.pdf&quot;&gt;Law on cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; which states that &#039;owners of a&amp;nbsp;cyber infrastructure&#039; (basically every legal person with a computer) needs to allow access to data at the simple demand of 9 different Romanian security and intelligence agencies. The cybersecurity law was sent to the Constitutional Court on the 23rd of December 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, the Romanian Constitutional Court declared the data retention law unconstitutional two times. The last decision was on the 8th of July 2015 (see some remarks in English &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/romania-aftermath-of-second-ccr-data-retention-ruling/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in Romanian &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/2014/11/13/3-idei-importante-despre-retentia-datelor-din-decizia-ccr/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). At the same time, the Court also declared unconstitutional the law for registering pre-pay SIM cards and Wi-Fi users by Decision no. 461 of 16 September 2014 (available &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacy.apti.ro/decizie-curtea-constitutionala-prepay-461-2014/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in Romanian). This was the 4th attempt to introduce this kind of law in the last 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Civil society and private parties are left out of any discussion.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanias-ministry-of-finance-wants-a-database-with-all-bank-acco</id>
      <title>Romania&#039;s Ministry of Finance wants a database with all bank accounts</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romanias-ministry-of-finance-wants-a-database-with-all-bank-acco" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:59:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A draft legislative project wants to automatically collect all financial data from all opened bank accounts as a way to combat fraud. The Association for Technology and Internet (ApTI) together with 6 other Romanian NGOs argued against such measures of mass surveillance and commented that they are disproportionate and violate the right to privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ministry&#039;s draft law and ApTI&#039;s opinion are available only in Romanian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-the-aftermath-of-the-second-ccr-data-retention-ruling</id>
      <title>Romania: The aftermath of the second CCR data retention ruling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-the-aftermath-of-the-second-ccr-data-retention-ruling" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T17:20:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As previously reported in the EDRi-gram, the Romanian Constitutional Court (CCR) ruled in its decision no. 440 on 8 July 2014 that the second Romanian data retention law (no. 82/2012) was not constitutional. The full reasoning for this was published in the Official Journal on 4 September 2014 in Romanian. EDRi-member ApTI is working on the translation of the text, and an English version will follow soon.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-mandatory-prepaid-sim-registration-ruled-unconstitutiona</id>
      <title>Romania: Mandatory prepaid SIM registration ruled unconstitutional</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/romania-mandatory-prepaid-sim-registration-ruled-unconstitutiona" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T17:20:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Romanian Constitutional Court (CCR) ruled on 16 September 2014 that a law that required the mandatory registration of all prepaid SIM cards and free WiFi users, is unconstitutional, as a whole. The Court reviewed the law as a result of the Romanian Ombudsman’s objection concerning its possible unconstitutionality. Several human rights NGOs asked the Ombudsman in July 2014 to notify the CCR regarding the law which had been recently adopted, and to ask the Court to rule on the law’s constitutionality before its promulgation by the President.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/law-on-registering-prepay-sim-card-users-is-unconstitutional</id>
      <title>Romanian Constitutional Court declared unconstituional the law on registering prepay sim card users and public Wi-Fi users</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/law-on-registering-prepay-sim-card-users-is-unconstitutional" />
      <updated>2014-09-19T17:55:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 September 2014, the Romanian Constitutional Court declared the law on registering prepay sim card users and public Wi-Fi users unconstitutional. After being adopted in an emergency procedure, several NGOs put pressure on decision makers (including in a letter addressed to the President) to declare this law unconstitutional signaling the serious infringements on private life. The law was brought to the Constitutional Court by the Ombudsman and ApTI together with AADOR-CH intervened via an amicus curiae. in the last 3 years, this law is the 4th attempt to adopt such legislation in Romania.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-legea-reteniei-datelor-a-fost-declarat-neconstitutional</id>
      <title>Romanian data retention law declared unconstitutional</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-legea-reteniei-datelor-a-fost-declarat-neconstitutional" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T13:24:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Romanian Constitutional Court has declared the second data retention law to be unconstitutional on 7 July 2014. The decision will be published in the Official Monitor soon. This is the second data retention law to be declared that it breaches the right to privacy, as stipulated in the Romanian Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/i-totui-colaboreaz-romania-cu-nsa-pentru-interceptrile-internetu</id>
      <title>Is Romania in cooperation with the NSA?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/i-totui-colaboreaz-romania-cu-nsa-pentru-interceptrile-internetu" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T13:13:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Romanian intelligence agency (SRI) declared that it is not cooperating with NSA. Yet, an article from The Intercept....&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
