<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/FR/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in FR</title>
  <updated>2018-02-09T20:07:14+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-tables-new-fake-news-law</id>
      <title>France tables new &#039;fake news&#039; law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-tables-new-fake-news-law" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:07:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;France has tabled new legislation to quickly take down fake news at election time, its culture minister, Francoise Nyssen, has said. The new &quot;judicial procedure&quot; would &quot;permit us to act very quickly when a fake news story goes viral, particularly during an election period,&quot; she told the Journal de Dimanche newspaper. The bill comes after Russian hackers and trolls tried to stop president Emmanuel Macron from getting elected last year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-plans-internet-ombudsman-to-safeguard-free-speech</id>
      <title>France plans internet ombudsman to safeguard free speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-plans-internet-ombudsman-to-safeguard-free-speech" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T23:41:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;France is considering appointing an official internet ombudsman to regulate complaints about online material in order to prevent excessive censorship and preserve free speech. A bill establishing a “content qualification assessment procedure” has been tabled in the French Senate and the initiative was debated last week at a high level meeting attended by senators and judges as well as policy officers from Google and Twitter. The aim is to provide a simple procedure that will support firms operating online who are uncertain of their legal liabilities and to prevent over-zealous removal or censorship of material merely because it is the subject of a complaint. It could be copied by other European jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-data-mandatory-for-local-authorities-data</id>
      <title>Open data: mandatory for local authorities’ data</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-data-mandatory-for-local-authorities-data" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:20:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the Digital Republic Bill makes open data mandatory for local communities beyond 3500 inhabitants, an appraisal mission has been assigned&amp;nbsp; to the association, Open Data France. The aim of this mission is to prepare the local authorities to put in place the default mechanism for open of data as foreseen by article 4 of the Digital Republic Bill.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-french-digital-council-welcomes-the-adoption-of-the-digital</id>
      <title>The French Digital Council welcomes the adoption of the Digital Republic Bill and the important clauses it contains</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-french-digital-council-welcomes-the-adoption-of-the-digital" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:23:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French Digital Council expressed its satisfaction with the adoption of the Digital Bill by the joint committee composed of senators and deputies. An intense debate preceded the bill’s adoption, as over 2500 amendments were put forward. The Digital Council highlighted the great quality of these discussions which confirms the increasing importance for the national representatives of the debated matters.&amp;nbsp; The Digital Council welcomes many elements of the bill such as open data; a balanced right to portability; the measures promoting accessibility and inclusion; the exception to copyright in order to enable scientific text and data mining, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-digital-republic-bill-highlights</id>
      <title>The Digital Republic Bill highlights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-digital-republic-bill-highlights" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:30:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Based on the compromised version of the Digital Republic Bill agreed by senators and deputies on 29 June 2016, some of the bill highlights are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a provision enabling text and data mining which opposed the scientific community and editors, with the exception of the audiovisual data in respect of copyright;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;net neutrality;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;open data becomes the rule;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;websites will not be obliged to collect taxes;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;no obligation to store data in France;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;digital death for which same rules apply as in the physical world, that is online documents belonging to a deceased person shall be transmitted to designated heirs unless otherwise agreed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-leader-of-censorship-on-facebook-in-2015</id>
      <title>France leader of censorship on Facebook in 2015</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-leader-of-censorship-on-facebook-in-2015" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:38:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following French government’s requests, Facebook had to delete a total 37 990 pages during the past related to terrorism. The requests targeted pages supporting terrorist activity.&amp;nbsp; The second country with the highest number of censorship requests is India with a total of 30 126 deletion requests.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-digital-republic-bill-adopted-by-the-senate</id>
      <title>The Digital Republic Bill adopted by the Senate</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-digital-republic-bill-adopted-by-the-senate" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:33:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although the draft digital bill was adopted by the Senate, special attention is drawn to the number of amendments adopted, despite the government’s opinion. In total 13 government amendments were rejected during the debate, which is not surprising given that the Socialist party does not have a majority in the Senate. Certain legal provisions risk posing problems vis-à-vis the European regulation, i.e. the interdiction to process French data stored outside of Europe or the amendment obliging platforms like e-Bay to automatically declare the earned income of its users. The next step is for the Joint Committee composed of deputies and senators to agree upon a compromised version of the bill.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-says-gafa-in-charge-of-internet-governance</id>
      <title>France says GAFA in charge of Internet Governance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-says-gafa-in-charge-of-internet-governance" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T14:36:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following the reform of Internet Governance from US to ICANN based on a multi-stakeholder concept, France expressed its disappointment with the fact that the new organization hands over the control of Internet to private actors. Paris denounces the heavy lobbying and influence of “GAFA (Google, Apple, Facebook, Amazon)” during the summits held during the past months and deplores the further diminishing weight of individual countries within ICANN.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-digital-council-issues-opinion-on-the-draft-digital-bil</id>
      <title>National Digital Council issues opinion on the draft Digital Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/national-digital-council-issues-opinion-on-the-draft-digital-bil" />
      <updated>2016-01-10T20:09:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to the National Digital Council (NDC), the draft Digital Bill is one of the phases of the digital strategy of the government. It was developed following wide and innovative public consultation launched in October 2014 by the Prime Minister and conducted by the NDC. This bill represents a way for the government to relaunch national growth and development for businesses, citizens and for the country itself. The NDC considers that the bill aims to have everyone take advantage of the benefits offered by the digital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-change-of-the-french-surveillance-bill-undermines-ci</id>
      <title>Last minute change of the French Surveillance Bill undermines civil liberties</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-minute-change-of-the-french-surveillance-bill-undermines-ci" />
      <updated>2015-06-19T23:10:41+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;La Quadrature du Net reports on a last minute change of the French Surveillance Bill and it calls to French representatives to reject this text during the final vote on the 23rd and 24th June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The change is a defeat for civil liberties and the procedure for the modification itself is characterised as anti-democratic. The new amendment states that any person transiting in France or not being identified as habitually resident is deprived from all the guarantees offered by the preliminary notice and can be directly put under surveillance following authorisation by the French Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/future-digital-bill-pending-report-from-the-national-digital-cou</id>
      <title>Future digital bill - pending report from the National Digital Council</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/future-digital-bill-pending-report-from-the-national-digital-cou" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:09:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;National Digital Council’s report on the draft digital bill is not ready yet although the bill should be presented to the Council of Ministers in June 2015.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-reviews-internet-content-control-measures</id>
      <title>CNIL reviews Internet content control measures</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cnil-reviews-internet-content-control-measures" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T12:13:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since February 2015, CNIL has a person in charge of reviewing the websites which are blocked on grounds of online propaganda, terrorism or child pornography content.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/bbc-news-french-government-orders-website-block</id>
      <title>French government orders website block</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/bbc-news-french-government-orders-website-block" />
      <updated>2015-03-21T13:10:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The French authorities have used new powers to block five websites, which they claim condone terrorism, without a court order. Internet service providers have 24 hours to comply. The chairman of European Internet Service Provider OVH &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/olesovhcom/status/577401572235296768&quot;&gt;tweeted &lt;/a&gt;that his firm had not been given any warning. The new powers apply to sites suspected of commissioning or advocating terrorism or distributing indecent images of children.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-implements-internet-censorship-without-judicial-oversight</id>
      <title>France implements Internet censorship without judicial oversight</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-implements-internet-censorship-without-judicial-oversight" />
      <updated>2015-03-12T09:14:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The recent terrorist attacks in Europe have led to many statements implying the necessity of limiting citizens’ fundamental rights to ensure public safety. At the European level we are faced with the alarming prospect of air passenger data (Passenger Name Records, PNR) collection&amp;nbsp;and long-term storage, while in France the legislative mills are turning even faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, the French government enacted a decree that enables the de-listing of websites from search engines without any judicial oversight. The decree targets websites that distribute child abuse content as well as sites that incite or endorse terrorism. This comes only a month after another decree that enabled the administrative blocking of websites.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-court-rules-it-can-hear-cases-brought-against-facebook-1</id>
      <title>French court rules it can hear cases brought against Facebook</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-court-rules-it-can-hear-cases-brought-against-facebook-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T16:51:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Paris court has ruled that it has the legal authority to judge a case against &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, which blocked the account of a French teacher who posted an image of a vulva.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court ruled that the case came under its jurisdiction and Facebook’s clause forcing all users to agree that any litigation must be based in California, where the site is based, was “abusive”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Facebook is being sued by a French man whose account was blocked after he posted a 19th-century picture by &lt;a data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/jonathanjonesblog/2013/feb/08/gustave-courbet-origin-world-art&quot;&gt;Gustave Courbet, The Origin of the World&lt;/a&gt;, depicting a vulva.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-seeks-to-sanction-web-companies-for-hate-speech</id>
      <title>France seeks to sanction web companies for hate speech</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-seeks-to-sanction-web-companies-for-hate-speech" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:18:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;President Francois Hollande said Tuesday in Paris the government will present a draft law next month that makes Internet operators “accomplices” of hate-speech offenses if they host extremist messages. Interior Minister Bernard Cazeneuve said he will travel to the U.S. to seek help from the heads of Twitter Inc. and Microsoft Corp. as well as Google and Facebook. Spokesmen for the companies did not immediately return requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-law-blocking-terrorist-and-child-abuse-sites-comes-into-e-1</id>
      <title>French law blocking terrorist and child abuse sites comes into effect</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-law-blocking-terrorist-and-child-abuse-sites-comes-into-e-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:18:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/france&quot;&gt;France&lt;/a&gt; has introduced a new law that allows government agencies to order the blocking of websites that advocate acts of terrorism or contain images of child abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation was brought in by revisions to 2011’s Loppsi Act, and an anti-terror bill passed by the French senate in October, but can now be used by the general directorate of the police’s cybercrime unit to force French internet service providers to block sites within 24 hours, without a court order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sites that are blocked will redirect to a page from the interior ministry describing why the action was taken. The sites will be checked quarterly to make sure they continue to display the proscribed content and that the block is still appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-digital-council-publishes-report-on-platform-neutrality</id>
      <title>French Digital Council publishes report on platform neutrality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/french-digital-council-publishes-report-on-platform-neutrality" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T15:52:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The concept of platform neutrality implies that web platforms such as YouTube, Spotify and the Apple Store do not abuse their position to the detriment of other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report aims at the application of the neutrality principle and the regulation of dGoata systems. It is structured in three main parts: the opinion of the CNNum, thematic fact sheets that clarify that opinion and an in-depth economic analysis of platform neutrality. The full report is available in French and the two main parts also in English, German, Spanish and Italian.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
