<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/ES/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in ES</title>
  <updated>2017-10-21T15:02:09+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-constitutional-court-kills-the-catalonian-digital-tax</id>
      <title>Spanish Constitutional Court kills the Catalonian digital tax</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-constitutional-court-kills-the-catalonian-digital-tax" />
      <updated>2017-07-30T00:04:49+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Spanish Constitutional Court has sided with the Government and declared unconstitutional the Catalonian digital canon, a tax that the local Government (Generalitat) was charging to the Internet Service Providers operating in Catalonia.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/catalonian-website-on-independence-referendum-shut-down-after-ju</id>
      <title>Catalonian website on independence referendum shut down after judge ruling</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/catalonian-website-on-independence-referendum-shut-down-after-ju" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T15:02:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Referendum.cat, the oficcial website created by the Catalonian Government to inform about the independence referendum for October, 1st was closed on September 14th, after ruling from the judge of Barcelona&#039;s Court number 13.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-police-raid-cat-domain-name-registry-offices-domain-name</id>
      <title>Spanish police raid .Cat domain name registry offices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-police-raid-cat-domain-name-registry-offices-domain-name" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T22:59:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spanish police has raided the offices of Fundació puntCAT, the registry operator for the .cat domain name, just days after a court ruled to shut down domains referring to the independence referendum.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spains-freedom-of-speech-repression-is-no-joke</id>
      <title>Spain&#039;s freedom of speech repression is no joke</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spains-freedom-of-speech-repression-is-no-joke" />
      <updated>2017-06-05T14:07:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cassandra Vera, a 21-year-old student from the city of Murcia in the south-east of Spain, has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/mar/30/spanish-woman-given-jail-term-for-tweeting-jokes-about-franco-era-assassination&quot;&gt;sentenced to a year in prison&lt;/a&gt;, and disqualified from public functions for seven years, after making jokes on Twitter that “glorified terrorism”. Ruling on her crime, judges in the National Audience, Spain’s top criminal court, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-39442213&quot;&gt;stated that Vera’s tweets&lt;/a&gt; “constitute contempt, dishonour, disrepute, mockery and affront to the people who have suffered the blow of terrorism”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The judges were &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:52014SC0270&quot;&gt;following the law&lt;/a&gt; but their interpretation is questionable. The European parliament has &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32017L0541&amp;amp;from=ES&quot;&gt;made it crystal clear&lt;/a&gt; that for there to be an offence of glorification or justification of terrorism, it has to be understood “as a way to gather support for terrorist causes or to seriously intimidate the population”. It should, according to the parliament, only be punished “when it causes a danger that terrorist acts may be committed”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-bill-threatens-whisleblowers-protection</id>
      <title>Spanish bill threatens whisleblowers&#039; protection</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-bill-threatens-whisleblowers-protection" />
      <updated>2017-04-21T21:33:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A very flawed whistleblowers protection law has been proposed in Spain. The law would not only insufficiently protect whistleblowers but also undermine citizens’ rights. Its apparently attractive name (“Ley Integral de Lucha contra la Corrupción y Protección de los Denunciantes” - Comprehensive Law on the Struggle against Corruption and Protection of Whistleblowers) hides serious dangers. Yet, the draft law has been supported by all the parties except PNV (Basque Nationalist Party).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-national-library-finalizes-the-first-massive-retrieving-of</id>
      <title>Spain National Library finalizes the first massive retrieving of .es domains</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spain-national-library-finalizes-the-first-massive-retrieving-of" />
      <updated>2016-09-05T13:31:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For three months, the Spanish National Library automatic collection software has crawled 1.800.000 “.es” domains and downloaded 460 million files, resulting in a collection of 20 TB, an estimated 87% of all active domains. The purpose of this web archive is the preservation and dissemination of these &quot;digital born&quot; resources so they can serve as knowledge tools for present and future generations.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-and-the-spanish-position</id>
      <title>Net neutrality and the Spanish position</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/net-neutrality-and-the-spanish-position" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T22:33:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This article presents a closer look at the ramifications of the European Parliament’s legislation on net neutrality, which is now unlikely to be subjected to any further amendments. It also contains a specific comment on Spain&#039;s position.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-law-there-is-still-some-hope</id>
      <title>Spanish Citizens’ Security law: There is still some hope</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizens-security-law-there-is-still-some-hope" />
      <updated>2015-04-09T00:49:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite considerable global criticism, the Spanish Citizens’ Security law was passed on 26 March 2015, together with the reforms of the Criminal Code, which include punishment of badly-defined “terrorist crimes” online. The Citizens’ Security law was greatly opposed by political parties, but that was not enough against the majority in the Parliament of the Popular Party in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-juez-ordena-el-bloqueo-de-the-pirate-bay-en-espana-cultura-el</id>
      <title>Spanish court decides to block The Pirate Bay</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-juez-ordena-el-bloqueo-de-the-pirate-bay-en-espana-cultura-el" />
      <updated>2015-03-28T15:08:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Pirate Bay, the Swedish site access torrents, has been locked in Spain since Friday, according to a court ruling. Internet Service Providers have 72 hours to comply. The popular service was unavailable last December after a police raid, but was revived earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-political-parties-agree-on-draft-law-proposal-broadening</id>
      <title>Spanish political parties agree on draft law broadening the concept of terrorism</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-political-parties-agree-on-draft-law-proposal-broadening" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:24:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the context of the undergoing Spanish Criminal Code reform, PSOE and PE, two major political parties in Spain, agreed on a law proposal on terrorism which include provisions about the Internet. This happened despite critics saying that the section on terrorism should be left out of the Criminal Code reform.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizen-security-law-implications-for-the-internet</id>
      <title>Spanish Citizen Security Law implications for the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/spanish-citizen-security-law-implications-for-the-internet" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:21:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Among the new aspects included in the new Citizen Security Law is the possibility of holding someone responsible for a street rally if he or she makes a public statement or a call for participation, like a simple Tweet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-security-bill-demands-to-keep-id-records</id>
      <title>Citizens’ Security Bill demands to keep ID records</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/citizens-security-bill-demands-to-keep-id-records" />
      <updated>2014-12-14T08:58:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 11 July 2014, the Spanish Council of Ministers adopted the Bill on the Protection of Citizens’ Security. The Government’s proposal has been strongly criticised. Restrictions to the freedoms of assembly and expression in protests received a lot of attention in the media, but EDRi says some provisions of the bill have barely been discussed. Measures which have been overlooked in the media include Article 25, which would oblige cybercafés and similar establishments to keep records of their clients’ IDs because these establishments “exercise activities which are relevant for citizens’ security”.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
