<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IG/UK/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IG in UK</title>
  <updated>2017-07-17T14:11:40+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-plans-age-verification-for-porn-websites-from-2018-bbc-news</id>
      <title>UK plans age verification for porn websites from 2018</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-plans-age-verification-for-porn-websites-from-2018-bbc-news" />
      <updated>2017-07-17T14:11:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;People in the UK will have to prove they are 18 before being allowed to access pornography websites from next year (2018), the government is to announce.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-economy-act-2017-uk-parliament</id>
      <title>Digital Economy Act 2017 — UK Parliament</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/digital-economy-act-2017-uk-parliament" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:50:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Digital Economy Act 2017 includes a provision to allow providers of internet access services to engage in filtering of their service for child protection purposes, where this is in accordance with the terms of service. In light of net neutrality, this supports the position of the existing popular parental control filters offered by UK ISPs to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/bsg-publishes-new-open-internet-code-of-practice-broadband-stake</id>
      <title>BSG Publishes New Open Internet Code of Practice</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/bsg-publishes-new-open-internet-code-of-practice-broadband-stake" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:47:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In June 2016 the Broadband Stakeholder Group (a multi-stakeholder industry advisory group to Government) published its new Open Internet Code. This is signed up to by all major UK ISPs and MNOs, and is a self-regulatory set of commitments on open internet that complement the EU Regulation. It forms an update and merger of the previous existing two self-regulatory codes on open internet and traffic management.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-open-internet-access-eu-regulation-regulations-2016</id>
      <title>The Open Internet Access (EU Regulation) Regulations 2016</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-open-internet-access-eu-regulation-regulations-2016" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:45:21+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UK is subject to EU Regulation 2015/2120 laying down measures concerning open internet access, the net neutrality aspects of which came into force in April 2016. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UK has introduced the Open Internet Access (EU Regulation) Regulations 2016, which came into force in June 2016&amp;nbsp;to allow Ofcom, as the UK National Regulatory Authority, the powers to monitor compliance with the EU regulation, to enforce its provisions and to impose penalties for non-compliance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-reveals-uk-plans-for-wider-internet-surveillance</id>
      <title>Leaked document reveals UK plans for wider internet surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-reveals-uk-plans-for-wider-internet-surveillance" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T22:54:12+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government is planning to push greater surveillance powers that would force internet providers to monitor communications in near-realtime and install backdoor equipment to break encryption, according to a leaked document.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-open-rights-group-crowdfunds-mass-surveillance-explainer</id>
      <title>UK Open Rights Group crowdfunds mass surveillance explainer</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-open-rights-group-crowdfunds-mass-surveillance-explainer" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:51:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Civil rights campaign organisation, the Open Rights Group, is running a crowdfunding campaign to try to raise £20,000 to fund a challenge to the U.K. government’s own massive PR machine which is in the midst of driving the draft Investigatory Powers bill through Parliament and onto the statute books this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The draft IP bill, presented to parliamentary in November — and now being interrogated by a &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/11/27/ipbill-committee-rubberstamp/&quot;&gt;joint select committee of MPs and Peers&lt;/a&gt;, due to report next month — is the U.K. government’s attempt to update and crystalize the law on surveillance powers in the post-Snowden era.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-statement-against-uk-surveillance-bill</id>
      <title>Apple statement against UK surveillance bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/apple-statement-against-uk-surveillance-bill" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T21:24:13+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Guardian reports that Apple has submitted a formal statement to the bill committee working on a new complex and controversial surveillance law in the U.K. The submission was just released, and Apple is staying on course when it comes to privacy, saying that government backdoors could be used by anyone and weaken the security of hundreds of millions of devices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dont-spy-on-us-condemns-the-fast-tracking-of-uk-new-surveillance</id>
      <title>Don&#039;t Spy on Us condemns the fast-tracking of UK new surveillance legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/dont-spy-on-us-condemns-the-fast-tracking-of-uk-new-surveillance" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:25:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The decision by the UK government to reduce parliamentary scrutiny of the Investigatory Powers Bill has been condemned by civil liberties groups and technology experts. The draft Bill and explanatory notes, which run to 299 pages, will now only receive three weeks scrutiny in order to drive the legislation through parliament in the New Year.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-response-to-uk-draft-investigatory-powers-bill</id>
      <title>Open Rights Group response to UK draft Investigatory Powers Bill</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-rights-group-response-to-uk-draft-investigatory-powers-bill" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:31:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Rights Group has responded to the publication of the UK&#039;s proposed new surveillance law, the draft Investigatory Powers Bill.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-investigatory-powers-bill-now-published</id>
      <title>UK Investigatory Powers Bill now published</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-investigatory-powers-bill-now-published" />
      <updated>2016-01-09T20:28:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government has published the draft Investigatory Powers Bill which will decide the surveillance powers that the police and intelligence have for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-uk-law-would-give-government-access-to-encrypted-internet-me</id>
      <title>New UK law would give government access to encrypted Internet messaging apps</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-uk-law-would-give-government-access-to-encrypted-internet-me" />
      <updated>2015-07-01T22:14:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new Investigatory Powers Bill, announced in yesterday&#039;s Queen&#039;s Speech, will include legislation to force Internet companies to give access to encrypted conversations of suspected terrorists and criminals. According to The Telegraph: &quot;New laws will require WhatsApp, which is owned by Facebook, Snapchat and other popular apps to hand messages sent by their users to MI5, MI6 and GCHQ about suspects under investigation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-magna-carta-vote-launched</id>
      <title>UK vote on Internet &#039;Magna Carta&#039; was launched</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/internet-magna-carta-vote-launched" />
      <updated>2015-06-08T18:59:08+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thousands of young people take part in a UK debate about what should be included in a &quot;Magna Carta&quot; for the digital age. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bl.uk/my-digital-rights/vote-now&quot; class=&quot;story-body__link-external&quot;&gt;The public can now vote online for the clauses they suggested&lt;/a&gt;, in a project organised by the British Library.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-cybersecurity-legislation</id>
      <title>UK government quietly rewrites cybersecurity legislation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-quietly-rewrites-cybersecurity-legislation" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T11:01:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK government has passed new legislation that exempts GCHQ, police, and other intelligence officers from prosecution for hacking into computers and mobile phones. The changes to the Computer Misuse Act were introduced over a year ago without a real public debate and entered into force on May 3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Privacy International&#039;s legal experts, the amended Computer Misuse Act &quot;grants UK law enforcement new leeway to potentially conduct cyber attacks within the UK.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-martha-lane-fox-calls-for-new-body-granting-deeper-understand</id>
      <title>UK: Martha Lane Fox calls for new body granting &#039;deeper understanding&#039; of the Internet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-martha-lane-fox-calls-for-new-body-granting-deeper-understand" />
      <updated>2015-03-24T11:22:51+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media/martha-lane-fox&quot;&gt;Martha Lane Fox&lt;/a&gt; is calling for the creation of an institution to examine the ethical and moral issues posed by the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Britain should lead the way in setting up the body, to counter the rise of huge commercial concerns that dominate our relationship with the internet, she will argue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-political-parties-approach-to-digital-issues</id>
      <title>UK political parties&#039; approach to digital issues</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-political-parties-approach-to-digital-issues" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:09:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ed Vaizey, the minister for culture and the digital economy, called for technology firms to “meet politicians halfway” on sensitive issues around privacy and internet safety, rather than react furiously with accusations that politicians do not understand the technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“So the prime minister, I think, is entitled to say: ‘We have a very sophisticated technology industry and encryption and so on… on the one hand I want to promote those industries and I want a successful technology economy, but I also have a duty as prime minister to keep our citizens as safe as possible. And we need to meet somewhere in the middle and talk about this’.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaizey was speaking at a Big Digital Debate event in London organised by techUK, Computer Weekly and BCS – The Chartered Institute for IT, which aimed to give the three major parties a platform to set out their approach to digital issues.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/hate-crime-on-social-media-should-be-punished</id>
      <title>Hate crime on social media should be punished</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/hate-crime-on-social-media-should-be-punished" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:06:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-link-name=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; data-component=&quot;auto-linked-tag&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/media/social-media&quot;&gt;Social media&lt;/a&gt; users who persistently spread racial hatred online should be given “internet asbos” blocking them from sites such as Facebook and Twitter, according to an MPs’ report that examines the rising levels of antisemitism in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Crown Prosecution Service has been asked by the all-party parliamentary inquiry into antisemitism to examine whether prevention orders, similar to those used to restrict sex offenders’ online access, could be applied to hate crimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MPs suggested the orders could be imposed to bar determined perpetrators from social media.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-issues-first-definition-of-computer-hacking-by-spi</id>
      <title>UK government issues first definition of computer hacking by spies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-government-issues-first-definition-of-computer-hacking-by-spi" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:25:25+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The British government has for the first time offered an official definition of computer hacking by the security services. The definition can be found in the Home Office &lt;a title=&quot;&quot; data-link-name=&quot;in body link&quot; data-component=&quot;in-body-link&quot; class=&quot;u-underline&quot; href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2015/feb/06/uk-security-services-capable-bypassing-encryption-draft-code&quot;&gt;“draft equipment interference code of practice”&lt;/a&gt; released on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-snoopers-charter-blocked</id>
      <title>UK snoopers charter blocked</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-snoopers-charter-blocked" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:13:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A former Conservative cabinet minister who chaired the parliamentary inquiry into the snooper’s charter has told four senior peers not to go ahead on Monday with their last-minute attempt to sneak it into law before the general election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lord Blencathra, a former Home Office minister, has written to the former Tory defence secretary Lord King, voicing strong concerns over his attempt to “insert the whole of the discredited draft communications data bill” into the counter-terror legislation being fast-tracked through the House of Lords.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-and-uk-to-step-up-cyber-defense-efforts</id>
      <title>US and UK to step up cyber defense efforts</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/us-and-uk-to-step-up-cyber-defense-efforts" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:56:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The U.S. and the U.K. have been working together to prevent cyber attacks for some time, but are going to increase the collaboration. They will combine their expertise to set up “cyber cells” on both sides of the Atlantic to increase sharing information about threats and to work out how to best protect themselves and create a system that lets hostile states and organization know they shouldn’t attack, said U.K. prime minister David Cameron &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-politics-30842669&quot;&gt;in an interview published by the BBC on Friday.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-prime-minister-wants-intelligence-agencies-to-be-able-to-trac</id>
      <title>UK Prime Minister wants intelligence agencies to be able to track all communications</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-prime-minister-wants-intelligence-agencies-to-be-able-to-trac" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T19:02:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mr. Cameron said that a Tory Government would pass a new law to ensure that the intelligence agencies would be able to track phone calls and internet messages. He said that this power to track “who made which call, to which person, and when” was “absolutely crucial not just in terrorism but finding missing people, murder investigations, almost every single serious crime. &quot;What matters is that we can access this communications data whether people are using fixed phones, mobile phones or more modern ways of communicating via the internet.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-specialist-for-catching-dark-net-pedophiles</id>
      <title>UK specialist for catching dark net pedophiles</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/uk-specialist-for-catching-dark-net-pedophiles" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:19:46+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;article&gt;&lt;section&gt;&lt;p&gt;IT Worlds brings to attention the fact that the U.K. will set up a specialist unit that will use high-tech capabilities to hunt down pedophiles on the Tor anonymity network and other dark corners of the Web. The unit will combine the investigatory expertise of the U.K.’s National Crime Agency (NCA) with those of the Government Communications Headquarters (GCHQ), the U.K’s intelligence service, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-announces-new-global-action-to-deal-with-online-child-abuse&quot;&gt;tackle the worst cases of child sexual exploitation online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/article&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ofcom-in-denial-over-uk-ipv6-failure</id>
      <title>Ofcom in denial over UK IPv6 failure</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ofcom-in-denial-over-uk-ipv6-failure" />
      <updated>2017-05-18T15:08:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experts say the UK has been more negative about the adoption of IPv6 than almost any other nation. The big ISPs convey a lack of urgency and Ofcom, rather than pushing industry to adopt, seems more focused on thinking of work-arounds. This article asks why the UK regulator fails to show leadership in IPv6 implementation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/six-britons-arrested-over-silk-road-20-amid-dark-web-takedown-1</id>
      <title>Six Britons arrested over Silk Road 2.0 amid dark-web takedown</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/six-britons-arrested-over-silk-road-20-amid-dark-web-takedown-1" />
      <updated>2014-11-10T12:56:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The arrests were part of a joint European and US operation stretching across 17 countries and culminating in the shutdown of over 400 other illicit web sites and services not usually accessible through normal search engines or by typing out standard web addresses. UK police revealed that more British nationals involved in the “dark web” global trade of illegal drugs, forged documents and firearms will be arrested as part of the National Crime Agency’s (NCA) “project protein”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/1/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;incngmfnmqdkqlpwczbg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/1/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/2/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;incngmfnmqdkqlpwczbg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/2/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/3/rc.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;incngmfnmqdkqlpwczbg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/rc/3/rc.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/a2.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;incngmfnmqdkqlpwczbg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://da.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/a2.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/211597298193/u/197/f/663871/c/34708/s/4042c12c/sc/24/a2t.img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
