<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.euoverview/IPR/EU/feed.xml</id>
  <title>Policy Observatory for IPR in EU</title>
  <updated>2018-04-13T19:08:22+02:00</updated>
  <author><name>Policy Observatory</name></author>

      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-legal-services-unclear-about-censorship-filters</id>
      <title>EU Council legal services unclear about censorship filters</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-legal-services-unclear-about-censorship-filters" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T16:02:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 16 October 2017, Politico leaked the response from the Legal Services of the Council of the European Union (CLS) to the questions raised by six member states about the legality of the upload filter proposal in the Article 13 of the Copyright Directive proposal. As the censorship filter is about restricting fundamental rights, it is regrettable that the questions did not mention the rules under which restrictions can be imposed, namely Article 52.1 of the Charter of Fundamental Rights of the European Union. This means that key issues were not addressed in the CLS response.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-calls-for-the-deletion-of-the-censorshipmachine</id>
      <title>Civil society calls for the deletion of the #censorshipmachine</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/civil-society-calls-for-the-deletion-of-the-censorshipmachine" />
      <updated>2017-10-22T13:37:42+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, 16 October, European Digital Rights (EDRi), together with 56 other civil society organisations, sent an open letter to EU decision makers. The letter calls for the deletion of the Article 13 of the Copyright Directive proposal, pointing out that monitoring and filtering of internet content that it proposes breach citizens’ fundamental rights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-eu-presidency-calls-for-massive-internet-filteri</id>
      <title>Leaked document: EU Presidency calls for massive internet filtering</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-document-eu-presidency-calls-for-massive-internet-filteri" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:23:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Council of the European Union document leaked by Statewatch on 30 August reveals that during the summer months, that Estonia (current EU Presidency) has been pushing the other Member States to strengthen indiscriminate internet surveillance, and to follow in the footsteps of China regarding online censorship. Standing firmly behind its belief that filtering the uploads is the way to go, the Presidency has worked hard in order to make the proposal for the new copyright Directive even more harmful than the Commission’s original proposal, and pushing it further into the realms of illegality.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-research-committee-wants-to-gift-publishers-new-rights-to-res</id>
      <title>Latest copyright votes: Filtering, blocking &amp; half-baked compromises</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-research-committee-wants-to-gift-publishers-new-rights-to-res" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:32:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 11 July, two Committees in the European Parliament voted on their Opinions on European Commission’s proposal for a Copyright Directive: the Committee on Culture and Education (CULT) and the Committee on Industry, Research and Energy (ITRE).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-moves-one-step-closer-to-the-worlds-worst-internet-filtering</id>
      <title>EU moves one step closer to the world’s worst internet filtering law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-moves-one-step-closer-to-the-worlds-worst-internet-filtering" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:45:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September 2016, the European Commission proposed legislation that would require the constant monitoring and filtering of virtually everything that is uploaded to the internet in Europe. Under the extreme rules proposed by the Commission in the Copyright Directive, uploads to the internet would need to be scanned to assess if any photo, video or text that is being uploaded can be “identified” based on information provided by copyright holders. This would block, for example, memes that include copyrighted images or videos, parody, quotation and other perfectly harmless activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to encourage internet companies to monitor and delete information as thoroughly as possible, it is also proposed that their legal liability for uploads would be increased.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-positive-step-forward-against-the-censorship-machine-in-the-co</id>
      <title>A positive step forward against the “censorship machine” in the Copyright Directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-positive-step-forward-against-the-censorship-machine-in-the-co" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:45:32+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 24 February 2017 the Rapporteur of the European Parliament (EP) Committee on Internal Market and Consumer Protection (IMCO), Catherine Stihler MEP, published her draft Opinion on the Copyright Directive. The Opinion sends a strong message against the most extremist parts of the European Commission’s proposal: the “censorship machine” (aka upload filter).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-overdue-report-on-copyright-consultations</id>
      <title>European Commission’s overdue report on copyright consultations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commissions-overdue-report-on-copyright-consultations" />
      <updated>2016-10-20T18:11:27+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week the European Commission released its bombshell Directive on Copyright in the Digital Single Market. And while analyzing this proposal has occupied most of our time, there were several other documents released simultaneously by the Commission that also deserve the public’s attention. Of particular interest was the long-awaited report on the results of the public consultation on 1) the panorama exception, and 2) the role of publishers in the copyright value chain (aka ancillary copyright proposal).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-allows-copyright-owners-to-demand-open-wifi-netwo</id>
      <title>European Court allows copyright owners to demand open WiFi networks be password protected</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-court-allows-copyright-owners-to-demand-open-wifi-netwo" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T14:50:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Court of Justice (ECJ) recently announced its decision in Sony v McFadden with important consequences for open wireless in the European Union. The court held that providers of open wifi are not liable for copyright violations committed by others, but can be ordered to prevent further infringements by restricting access to registered users with passwords. EFF reported on the legal aspects of the case last year and collaborated on an open letter to the ECJ on the costs to economic growth, safety and innovation of a password lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyfails-bonus-track-copyright-levies-1</id>
      <title>Copyfails bonus track: Copyright levies</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyfails-bonus-track-copyright-levies-1" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T19:50:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU is reforming its copyright rules. EDRi wants to introduce you to the main failures of the current copyright system, with suggestions on how to fix them. You can find all the Copyfails &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/copyfails/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is an additional one – a “bonus track” – to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/copyfails/&quot;&gt;series presenting Copyfails&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-to-require-platforms-to-filter-uploaded-content-includi</id>
      <title>EU wants to require platforms to filter uploaded content (including code)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-wants-to-require-platforms-to-filter-uploaded-content-includi" />
      <updated>2018-04-13T19:08:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU is considering a copyright proposal that would require code-sharing platforms to monitor all content that users upload for potential copyright infringement (see the EU Commission’s proposed Article 13 of the Copyright Directive). The proposal is aimed at music and videos on streaming platforms, based on a theory of a “value gap” between the profits those platforms make from uploaded works and what copyright holders of some uploaded works receive. However, the way it’s written captures many other types of content, including code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/no-the-eu-did-not-abolish-geoblocking-today-1</id>
      <title>No, the EU did not abolish geoblocking today</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/no-the-eu-did-not-abolish-geoblocking-today-1" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T20:04:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zdnet.com/article/eu-agrees-to-end-geoblocking-to-boost-single-digital-market/&quot;&gt;did not agree to end geoblocking&lt;/a&gt; last November, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2017/05/29/eu_axes_geo_blocking_upsets_studios_delights_consumers/&quot;&gt;axe geoblocking&lt;/a&gt; last May or put an end to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eppgroup.eu/news/Geo-blocking%3A-end-to-geographic-discrimination&quot;&gt;geographic discrimination&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-extra-copyright-for-news-in-germany-was-a-failure-yet-the-bu</id>
      <title>The extra copyright for news in Germany was a failure – yet the Bulgarian EU presidency now presents it as a good compromise for all of Europe</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-extra-copyright-for-news-in-germany-was-a-failure-yet-the-bu" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T19:51:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Should the EU introduce an&amp;nbsp;extra copyright for news sites, restricting how we can share news online? The controversy around this plan continues to brew – this time in the Council, where the member state governments are trying to find a consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mercosur-eu-free-trade-agreement-a-bad-deal-for-the-public-domai-1</id>
      <title>Mercosur-EU Free Trade Agreement: a bad deal for the public domain</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/mercosur-eu-free-trade-agreement-a-bad-deal-for-the-public-domai-1" />
      <updated>2018-01-06T12:13:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like many other multilateral agreements that have been negotiated in recent years (TPP, TTIP, etc.), the Mercosur-EU FTA covers a large number of areas (not all strictly related to trade) ranging from the exchange of goods to capital movements, phytosanitary measures, electronic commerce and intellectual property (IP). The area of ​​negotiation related to IP is extremely broad, including patents, trademarks, geographical indications and copyright, among other topics.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-may-lead-newspapers-to-become-their-own-cens</id>
      <title>Copyright Directive may lead newspapers to become their own censors</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-may-lead-newspapers-to-become-their-own-cens" />
      <updated>2018-02-09T19:57:36+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Copyright discussions continue in the European institutions. On one hand, Axel Voss, the German conservative (EPP/CDU) Parliamentarian in charge of the dossier in the European Parliament Committee on Legal Affairs is on some sort of a stand-by while the German government forms. On the other hand, the EU Council, composed of the relevant ministers in charge of the copyright Directive proposal, is speeding up. The two worst proposals in it are the upload filter (“&lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/contact-ep-juri/&quot;&gt;censorship machine&lt;/a&gt;”) in Article 13 and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/copyfail-6/&quot;&gt;ancillary copyright&lt;/a&gt; in Article 11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.parlament.gv.at/PAKT/EU/XXVI/EU/00/11/EU_01173/imfname_10763193.pdf&quot;&gt;documents leaked from the Council meetings&lt;/a&gt; there is a new definition of a type of online service, “online content sharing service provider” which would be the one affected by the censorship machine proposal (Article 13).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/whats-wrong-with-the-eus-filtering-solutions</id>
      <title>What’s wrong with the EU’s filtering solutions?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/whats-wrong-with-the-eus-filtering-solutions" />
      <updated>2017-11-11T19:13:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union’s answer to protecting children from harmful content on the internet and combating copyright infringement is to require internet companies to filter the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament is about to vote on two pieces of legislation in the near future. One is the Directive on copyright in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/news/proposal-directive-european-parliament-and-council-copyright-digital-single-market&quot;&gt;Digital Single Market&lt;/a&gt;, the other is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://Audiovisual Media Services Directive&quot;&gt;Audiovisual Media Services Directive&lt;/a&gt;. These Directives would forever change the internet for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-leaked-these-3-eu-governments-want-to-give-record-lab</id>
      <title>These 3 EU governments want to give record labels control over what we can and can’t post online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-leaked-these-3-eu-governments-want-to-give-record-lab" />
      <updated>2017-11-05T16:36:26+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The governments of France, Spain and Portugal want to double down on a law proposed by the European Commission that would&amp;nbsp;force all kinds of internet platforms to install a “censorship machine”&amp;nbsp;to surveil all uploads and try to prevent copyright infringement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-these-3-eu-governments-want-to-give-record-labels-control</id>
      <title>Leaked: These 3 EU governments want to give record labels control over what we can and can’t post online</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/leaked-these-3-eu-governments-want-to-give-record-labels-control" />
      <updated>2017-10-26T16:32:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet is our greatest and most egalitarian public sphere: Never before was it possible for everyone to publish their creative works worldwide, at no cost, without seeking anyone’s approval. But some want to change that.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/did-the-eu-commission-hide-a-study-that-did-not-suit-their-agend</id>
      <title>Did the EU Commission hide a study that did not suit their agenda?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/did-the-eu-commission-hide-a-study-that-did-not-suit-their-agend" />
      <updated>2017-09-22T23:05:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the European Commission announced a launch of a study on copyright – and never published its results. Julia Reda, a Member of the European Parliament, tabled a freedom of information request on this issue and was eventually granted access to the study. Even though the independent study was finalised in 2015 and financed by public funds, the European Commission failed to publish the research.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/six-states-raise-concerns-about-legality-of-copyright-directive</id>
      <title>Six states raise concerns about legality of Copyright Directive</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/six-states-raise-concerns-about-legality-of-copyright-directive" />
      <updated>2017-10-21T16:06:52+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;According to a new leak, a number of EU Member States share our serious concerns about the proposal for mass surveillance and censorship of uploads to the internet in Europe, included in the European Commission’s proposal for a new copyright Directive. Those Member States seem unwilling to build a censorship machine forcing EU countries to build a censorship machine forcing EU countries to adopt Google’s current practices. They highlight that such practices should not be implemented without making sure of the consequences for fundamental rights and for the rule of law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cult-committee-wants-educators-to-pay-for-content-that-they-now</id>
      <title>CULT Committee wants educators to pay for content that they now use for free</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cult-committee-wants-educators-to-pay-for-content-that-they-now" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:23:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, the Committee on Culture and Education (CULT) of the European Parliament voted on its final opinion concerning the Commission’s Directive on Copyright in the Digital Single Market.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/no-you-cant-enjoy-the-music-you-paid-for-says-eu-parliament-comm</id>
      <title>No, you can’t enjoy the music you paid for, says EU Parliament Committee</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/no-you-cant-enjoy-the-music-you-paid-for-says-eu-parliament-comm" />
      <updated>2017-07-31T22:49:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A leaked European Parliament document exposes some of the most bizarre suggestions yet in the debates around the proposed new copyright rules in Europe. The proposal for the Copyright Directive is currently being debated in various European Parliament Committees. The leaked document shows that conservative, socialist and Green Members of the European Parliament (MEPs) in the Committee on Culture and Education (CULT) have agreed to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/files/copyright/CULT_COMPArt_13-V3.pdf&quot;&gt;compromise amendment&lt;/a&gt;”* that would ban legal uses of legally acquired copyrighted material. They would also require the implementation of upload filter, which would remove uploads identified as copyrighted material – memes for example. The vote takes place on 11 July.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-of-europe-report-on-copyright-exceptions-and-limitations</id>
      <title>Council of Europe report on copyright exceptions and limitations</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/council-of-europe-report-on-copyright-exceptions-and-limitations" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:04:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The intergovernmental Council of Europe, based in Strasbourg, France, has published a freely available report on exceptions and limitations to copyright. The report comes as a contribution to the ongoing process of reforming European copyright rules.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-copyright-directive-commissioner-confirms-it-is-illegal</id>
      <title>Proposed Copyright Directive – Commissioner confirms it is illegal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/proposed-copyright-directive-commissioner-confirms-it-is-illegal" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T19:02:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At a meeting of the European Parliament Committee on Legal Affairs (JURI) on 19 June, European Commission Vice-President Andrus Ansip made a statement that was both shocking and shockingly honest. He advertised the content filtering product of the US company Audible Magic as an affordable alternative to Google’s Content ID filtering technology for filtering European citizens’ uploads to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-cjeu-says-that-site-like-the-pirate-bay-makes-acts-of-c</id>
      <title>CJEU says that site like The Pirate Bay makes acts of communication to the public</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-cjeu-says-that-site-like-the-pirate-bay-makes-acts-of-c" />
      <updated>2017-08-01T00:15:23+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Is there a communication to the public within the meaning of Article&amp;nbsp;3(1) of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2001:167:0010:0019:EN:PDF&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;InfoSoc Directive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by the operator of a website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, if no protected works are available on that website, but there is a system therein by means of which metadata on protected works is indexed and categorised for users, so that these can trace and upload and download the protected works?&amp;nbsp;Does Article&amp;nbsp;8(3) of the InfoSoc Directive allow the issuing of an injunction against an ISP ordering it to block access for its users to an indexing site like The Pirate Bay?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;These were the important questions that the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;Dutch Supreme Court (Hoge Raad der Nederlanden)&amp;nbsp;had referred to the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) in&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=174196&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=en&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=621150&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Stichting Brein v Ziggo&lt;/i&gt;, C-610/15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;(also known as&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Pirate Bay&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;case).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; In his&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=187646&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=634431&quot;&gt;Opinion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;in February last&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Advocate General (AG) Szpunar answered both questions in the affirmative.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/consumer-committee-rejects-upload-filter-but-fails-on-link-tax</id>
      <title>Consumer Committee rejects upload filter but fails on “link tax”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/consumer-committee-rejects-upload-filter-but-fails-on-link-tax" />
      <updated>2017-06-28T20:10:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 8 June, the European Parliament Committee on the Internal Market and Consumer Protection (IMCO) voted on the European Commission’s proposal for a Copyright Directive. The IMCO Committee failed to adopt any amendments to Article 11, basically giving up its opportunity to have an influence on the process of fixing the Commission’s absurd proposal.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/just-9-days-left-to-reject-the-worst-version-of-eu-copyright-exp</id>
      <title>Just 9 days left to reject the worst version of EU copyright expansion plans yet</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/just-9-days-left-to-reject-the-worst-version-of-eu-copyright-exp" />
      <updated>2017-06-12T18:52:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 8, the Internal Market and Consumer Protection (IMCO) Committee will decide its standpoint. The IMCO committee is jointly responsible for the Parliament position on one of the most controversial parts of the reform: the introduction of mandatory censorship filters on online services such as social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today it was revealed that MEP Pascal Arimont from the European People’s Party (EPP) is trying to sabotage the Parliamentary process, going behind the negotiators of the political groups and pushing a text that would make the Commission’s original bad proposal look tame in comparison. If he succeeds again, the result would once more do the opposite of what the Committee is tasked to do: Protecting European consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-ep-committee-opinion-on-copyright-reform-balances-civil-lib</id>
      <title>Last EP Committee opinion on copyright reform balances civil liberties with political reality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/last-ep-committee-opinion-on-copyright-reform-balances-civil-lib" />
      <updated>2017-06-01T19:02:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This articles reflects whether the LIBE amendments would meet the goal of respecting fundamental rights of users while also regulating agreements between platforms and rightholders.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-to-the-european-commission-on-encrypted-media-extens</id>
      <title>Open letter to the European Commission on encrypted media extensions</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/open-letter-to-the-european-commission-on-encrypted-media-extens" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T05:01:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) is considering to standardize a highly controversial proposal on Encrypted Media Extensions for the use of DRM technology (copyright restrictions) in modern web browsers. Julia Reda wrote an open letter to raise a number of concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-citizens-and-intellectual-property-perception-awareness</id>
      <title>European Citizens and Intellectual Property: Perception, Awareness and Behaviour</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-citizens-and-intellectual-property-perception-awareness" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:10:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Report comissioned to Deloitte by the European Union Intellectual Property Office that &quot;provides evidence of how IP rights (IPR) are perceived by EU citizens at a time when encouraging innovation and creativity is increasingly the focus of economic policy&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report shows for instance that General subjective understanding of IP increases, although it decreases among the younger generation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-lead-mep-partly-deletes-the-censorship-machi</id>
      <title>Copyright Directive: Lead MEP party deletes the “censorship machine”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-directive-lead-mep-partly-deletes-the-censorship-machi" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:29:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Member of the European Parliament (MEP) Therese Comodini Cachia, the Rapporteur for JURI on this file, has proposed a number of changes to the original &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/press-release-new-copyright-directive-fails-every-level/&quot;&gt;broken and extreme proposal&lt;/a&gt; of the European Commission (EC). Ms Comodini has taken a reasonable approach and has amended the worst sections of the proposal: the “censorship machine” (aka upload filter) proposal in Article 13, and the suggestion to expand the “ancillary copyright” (aka “link tax”) that failed in Germany and Spain and was planned to be expanded to the entire EU.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-proposal-for-increasing-online-copyright-enforcement</id>
      <title>New proposal for increasing online copyright enforcement</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-proposal-for-increasing-online-copyright-enforcement" />
      <updated>2017-06-13T00:34:19+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A working group established by the Swiss government has reached a compromise in regard to copyright enforcement, in which (contrary to a previous proposal) no Internet blocking would be used against copyright-infringing foreign websites, but the legal protection for the privacy of IP addresses would be reduced, in order to allow persecution of illegal peer-to-peer filesharing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-copyright-study-shows-fundamental-flaws-in-eu-commission-pla</id>
      <title>New copyright study shows fundamental flaws in EU Commission plans for upload surveillance</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-copyright-study-shows-fundamental-flaws-in-eu-commission-pla" />
      <updated>2017-05-09T23:49:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission wants to obligate internet platforms to monitor all content their users upload for copyright infringements. This is laid out in Article 13 of Günther Oettinger’s copyright overhaul plans. Julia Reda detailed the harmful effects such upload surveillance would have.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/lead-parliamentarian-for-culture-committee-defends-upload-filter-1</id>
      <title>Lead Parliamentarian for Culture Committee defends upload filtering</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/lead-parliamentarian-for-culture-committee-defends-upload-filter-1" />
      <updated>2017-03-04T16:24:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 6 February 2017, the Parliamentarian in charge of the Copyright Directive for the European Parliament (EP) Committee for Culture and Education (CULT), Marc Joulaud, published his draft Opinion on the proposal for the Directive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As EDRi described in previous blogposts the European Commission’s proposal has not fulfilled hopes for a reform that could deliver a modern, harmonised European copyright framework. The proposal has been disappointing both for not introducing the much needed changes and scary for what it proposes, namely an upload filter for all types of content and the ancillary copyright that failed in two European countries already.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-should-protect-users-rights-and-prevent-content-fil</id>
      <title>EU copyright should protect users’ rights and prevent content filtering</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-should-protect-users-rights-and-prevent-content-fil" />
      <updated>2017-04-18T04:42:40+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This paper deals with article 13 of the Commission’s proposal which introduces a filtering obligation on online platforms that allow users to upload content. The proposal fails to establish clear rules for internet users that make it clear how they can share and remix content legally. Instead it introduces a filtering requirement for online platforms that can potentially serve as a censorship machine and will violate users’ fundamental rights and distort the existing legal framework. From COMMUNIA&#039;s perspective article 13 and the related recitals should be deleted from the proposal. You can download a pdf version of the position paper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.communia-association.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/170109COMMUNIA_position_paper_art_13.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-agrees-to-remove-geo-blocking-barriers-to-e-commerce</id>
      <title>EU Council agrees to remove geo-blocking barriers to e-commerce</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-council-agrees-to-remove-geo-blocking-barriers-to-e-commerce" />
      <updated>2017-01-11T08:49:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Union Council of member states today agreed on draft regulations to prevent blocking of cross-border e-commerce, but appears to retain copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tv-viewing-in-hotel-rooms-doesnt-need-copyright-licence-feetop-e</id>
      <title>TV viewing in hotel rooms doesn’t need copyright licence fee</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/tv-viewing-in-hotel-rooms-doesnt-need-copyright-licence-feetop-e" />
      <updated>2016-10-26T19:53:56+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CJEU advocate general says TV is an essential part of a hotel&#039;s activity.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euipo-instagram-trademark-application-for-gram</id>
      <title>Instagram trademark application for “GRAM”</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/euipo-instagram-trademark-application-for-gram" />
      <updated>2016-10-25T14:15:47+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Instagram trademark application for “GRAM” in the EU, including downloadable computer software for modifying and enabling transmission of images, audio-visual and video content; downloadable computer software for viewing and interacting with a feed of images, audio-visual and video content and associated text and data; computer software for social networking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/academics-stress-importance-of-preserving-consistency-and-integr</id>
      <title>Academics stress importance of preserving consistency and integrity of EU framework on content monitoring</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/academics-stress-importance-of-preserving-consistency-and-integr" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:04:35+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;A group of EU-based academics has just published a letter addressed at a number of EU institutions&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;in the aftermath of the release by the EU Commission of the second copyright package.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-commissions-dsms-and-cjeu-case-law-what-relationship</id>
      <title>The Commission&#039;s DSMS and CJEU case law: what relationship?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/the-commissions-dsms-and-cjeu-case-law-what-relationship" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:40:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;O&lt;span&gt;n 14 September the EU Commission unveiled its second&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/rapid/press-release_IP-16-3010_en.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;copyright package&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aimed at improving the existing EU copyright framework as part of its&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/priorities/digital-single-market_en&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Digital Single Market Strategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(DSMS).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Discussion has been focusing on the relationship between the new proposed directive and the existing body of legislation &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and the economic/legal rationale of the various initiatives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; What however appears to have been left partly out of the debate is what relationship the DSM Directive has and will have with the existing body of case law of the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-of-justice-of-the-european-union-tobias-mc-fadden-v-sony-m</id>
      <title>CJEU judgement in case Tobias Mc Fadden v Sony Music</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/court-of-justice-of-the-european-union-tobias-mc-fadden-v-sony-m" />
      <updated>2016-09-19T15:20:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The operator of a shop who offers a Wi-Fi network free of charge to the public is not liable for copyright infringements committed by users of that network. More information &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/jcms/upload/docs/application/pdf/2016-09/cp160099en.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-court-blocks-brazilian-company-from-trademarking-sound-of-a-r</id>
      <title>EU court blocks Brazilian company from trademarking sound of a ringing phone</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-court-blocks-brazilian-company-from-trademarking-sound-of-a-r" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T15:20:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU General Court judgment held that distinctive sounds can be trademarked, provided that they may be represented graphically. However, because the ringtone sound is so familiar and so universal, the court decided that a general consumer in the European Union would be &quot;unable, without prior knowledge, to identify that ringing sound as indicating that the goods and services come from Globo.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unlocking-copyright-for-users-make-law-not-licenses</id>
      <title>Unlocking copyright for users: Make law, not licenses</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/unlocking-copyright-for-users-make-law-not-licenses" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T15:25:28+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of COMMUNIA and EDRi the leaked drafts of the Commission’s proposal presents a grim picture, where all ambitious attempts to adjust copyright to the challenges of the digital economy were replaced by a focus on propping up existing revenue streams. If the leaked proposals are measured against EDRi’s list of copyfails, almost none of the points identified as necessary to address are covered by the draft legislation. Those that are addressed are only superficial fixes to the existing state of affairs. The leaked proposal is like the new ACTA, as EDRi’s Diego Naranjo put it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wikimedia-edri-and-others-call-for-eu-copyright-package-to-uphol</id>
      <title>Wikimedia, EDRI, and others call for EU Copyright Package to uphold DSM fundamental principles</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/wikimedia-edri-and-others-call-for-eu-copyright-package-to-uphol" />
      <updated>2016-09-13T15:29:17+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://edima-eu.org/pdfs/latest_news/high%20level%20joint%20letter%20copyright%20FINAL%20with%20logos%20EC.pdf&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; published on 9 September, the signatories request the EU Commission not to create a new ancillary right for publishers, to maintain the E-Commerce Directive safe harbour and not to limit the Text and Data Mining exception to &#039;public interest research institutions&#039; only.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-ruling-on-hyperlinking-shows-publishers-hypocrisy</id>
      <title>CJEU ruling on hyperlinking shows publishers hypocrisy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-ruling-on-hyperlinking-shows-publishers-hypocrisy" />
      <updated>2016-10-15T12:46:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CJEU conceded that under certain circumstances the mere act of hyperlinking to a work that has been published elsewhere – without the consent of the rightsholder – constitutes a copyright infringement. The decision introduces a lot of legal uncertainty for anyone who uses links online, and goes directly against a common sense understanding of how the internet works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/super-breaking-liberal-cjeu-says-that-linking-to-unauthorised-co</id>
      <title>CJEU says that linking to unauthorised content is NOT a communication to the public unless one seeks financial gain and has knowledge of illegality</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/super-breaking-liberal-cjeu-says-that-linking-to-unauthorised-co" />
      <updated>2016-09-08T13:17:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This morning the Court of Justice of the European Union has issued its judgment in&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;GS Media&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; This was a reference for a preliminary ruling from the Dutch Supreme Court. It had been made in the context of proceedings between Sanoma (the publisher of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Playboy&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;magazine) and GS Media, concerning the publication by the latter on a website that it operates&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://geenstijl.nl/&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;GeenStijl.nl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;nbsp;of hyperlinks to other websites hosting unpublished photographs&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;of Dutch starlet&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Britt_Dekker&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Britt Dekker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. These photographs were due for publication in a forthcoming issue of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Playboy&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-draft-of-new-copyright-directive-leaked</id>
      <title>EU: Draft of new Copyright Directive leaked</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-draft-of-new-copyright-directive-leaked" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:50:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, a first draft of the new Copyright Directive became public. It deals with, among other points, new and mandatory limitations to copyright (text and data mining, cross-border teaching, and preservation of cultural heritage). Furthermore, a new neighbouring copyright for publishers of news publications is about to be established at European level. The draft also contains provisions concerning the use of out-of-commerce works. The Commission further cautiously touches upon regulating video-on-demand platforms and their use of audiovisual works. Last but not least, the fair remuneration of authors and performers is part of the draft directive.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/latest-leak-confirms-european-copyright-plans-offer-little-for-u</id>
      <title>Latest Leak Confirms European Copyright Plans Offer Little for Users</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/latest-leak-confirms-european-copyright-plans-offer-little-for-u" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T20:20:22+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In EFF&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2016/08/european-copyright-leak-exposes-plans-force-internet-subsidize-publishers&quot;&gt;previous piece&lt;/a&gt; about a leaked European impact assessment on copyright, they described how the foreshadowed changes to European copyright law would place onerous new responsibilities on Internet platforms to scan your uploaded content on behalf of large entertainment companies. EFF also described how the changes would give news publishers a new, copyright-like veto power over the publications of snippets of text from news stories, even if these are merely by way of linking to the publisher&#039;s website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since then, there has been a further leak; this time, of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Directive.pdf&quot;&gt;draft text of the Directive&lt;/a&gt;—that is, the new law—that the European Commission proposes to introduce to enact its plans. The new leak is mostly consistent with the impact assessment, but with a little more detail. In particular, we learn that the new veto power (or &quot;link tax&quot;) for news publishers over the online publication of snippets would last for 20 years from the date of publication of the news story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here EFF runs down some of the other proposed changes, including new rules to facilitate access to television broadcasts online, new copyright exceptions for education, data mining, and archival, and new measures to broaden access to out of commerce works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-a-corporate-copyright-reform-in-the-eu</id>
      <title>Towards a corporate copyright reform in the EU?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/towards-a-corporate-copyright-reform-in-the-eu" />
      <updated>2016-09-07T21:37:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 24 August, Statewatch leaked the draft Impact Assessment of the European Commission on the copyright reform. Impact Assessments are an essential part in the decision making process.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statewatch-published-a-draft-of-the-commissions-own-impact-asse</id>
      <title>Statewatch published a draft of the Commission’s own Impact assessment on the modernisation of EU copyright rules</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/statewatch-published-a-draft-of-the-commissions-own-impact-asse" />
      <updated>2016-10-11T15:51:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Statewatch published a &lt;a href=&quot;http://statewatch.org/news/2016/aug/eu-com-copyright-draft.pdf&quot;&gt;draft of the Commission’s own Impact assessment on the modernisation of EU copyright rules&lt;/a&gt; which clearly states that the Commission will indeed propose the introduction of an EU wide ancillary copyright for news publishers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While nobody expected the EU commission to come forward with a proposal for a literal “link tax”, the “introduction in EU law of a related right covering online uses of news publications” is exactly what &lt;a href=&quot;https://openmedia.org/en/what-heck-ancillary-copyright-and-why-do-we-call-it-link-tax&quot;&gt;civil society groups like Save the Link are criticising as a link tax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-reform-unlocking-copyright-for-users-1</id>
      <title>Copyright reform: Unlocking copyright for users?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-reform-unlocking-copyright-for-users-1" />
      <updated>2016-08-24T19:38:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 8 September 2016, only a few days before the European Commission will announce its plans for a copyright reform, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.communia-association.org/&quot;&gt;Communia&lt;/a&gt; and EDRi will be organising an event to discuss some of they key issues, namely the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edri.org/copyfails/&quot;&gt;failures&lt;/a&gt; of the current EU copyright law, and the situation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.communia-association.org/2016/06/06/bcs-copyright/&quot;&gt;exceptions and limitations&lt;/a&gt;. The event “Copyright Reform: Unlocking copyright for users?” takes place at the European Parliament, room 6G1.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-calls-time-on-geo-blocking-in-new-regulation-propo</id>
      <title>EU Commission calls time on geo-blocking in new regulation proposal</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commission-calls-time-on-geo-blocking-in-new-regulation-propo" />
      <updated>2016-09-05T15:48:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 25 May 2016, the European Commission published a draft new Regulation which will prohibit geo-blocking and various related acts by traders which discriminate by reference to nationality or country of residence or establishment within the EU. The scope of the proposed Regulation is broad and would prevent geo-blocking and discrimination in pricing, sales or payment conditions for online sales.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ecj-advocate-general-opines-internet-hyperlinks-do-not-infringe</id>
      <title>ECJ Advocate General opines Internet hyperlinks do not infringe copyright</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ecj-advocate-general-opines-internet-hyperlinks-do-not-infringe" />
      <updated>2016-04-08T15:15:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A link to a website which publishes photos without authorisation of the author does not in itself constitute a copyright infringement, an adviser to Europe&#039;s top court said on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-publishes-issues-paper-with-initial-findings</id>
      <title>European Commission publishes issues paper with initial findings from e-commerce sector inquiry on geo-blocking practices</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-commission-publishes-issues-paper-with-initial-findings" />
      <updated>2016-09-05T15:46:24+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 18 March 2016, the European Commission published an issues paper on geo-blocking in e-commerce containing its initial findings from the e-commerce sector inquiry it launched on 6 May 2015. The Commission stated that geo-blocking practices are widespread and reconfirmed its intention to assess such practices under the EU antitrust rules and to propose further legislative action to address what it sees as unjustified barriers to cross-border e-commerce.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gs-media-hyperlink-case-under-cjeu-analysis</id>
      <title>GS Media hyperlink case under CJEU analysis</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/gs-media-hyperlink-case-under-cjeu-analysis" />
      <updated>2016-02-05T14:23:43+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Europe&#039;s highest court is considering whether every hyperlink in a web page should be checked for potentially linking to material that infringes copyright, before it can be used. Such a legal requirement would place an unreasonable burden on anyone who uses hyperlinks, thereby destroying the web we know and love.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current GS Media case examining hyperlinks builds on an earlier ruling by the European Union&#039;s Court of Justice (CJEU) in 2014. In that case, known as Svensson, the court decided that netizens did not need a licence from the copyright holder to link to an article that had already been posted on the Internet, where previous permission had been granted by the copyright owner.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-few-eu-governments-are-blocking-blind-peoples-access-to-knowle</id>
      <title>A few EU governments are blocking blind people’s access to knowledge</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-few-eu-governments-are-blocking-blind-peoples-access-to-knowle" />
      <updated>2018-01-20T00:09:45+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few European governments – including Germany and the UK – are currently playing a leading role in denying people with visual impairments urgently needed access to knowledge and culture for no defensible reason. Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//TEXT+MOTION+B8-2016-0168+0+DOC+XML+V0//EN&quot;&gt;the European Parliament is calling on these governments to end their obstructionism&lt;/a&gt; in an unusually strongly-worded resolution.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-ancillary-copyright-20-the-european-commission-is-pre</id>
      <title>The European Commission is reconsidering introducing ancillary copyright</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-ancillary-copyright-20-the-european-commission-is-pre" />
      <updated>2016-02-15T11:35:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Commission is preparing a new attempt to force search engines and news portals pay media companies for promoting their freely accessible articles. Earlier attempts at establishing this principle resulted in Germany’s and Spain’s ancillary copyright laws for press publishers. These attempts backfired – with tremendous collateral damage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a draft &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B6d07lh0nNGNaXFzUFBPaE0tY0E/view&quot;&gt;communication on copyright reform&lt;/a&gt; leaked yesterday (via &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipkitten.blogspot.co.uk/2015/11/kat-exclusive-eu-commission-due-to.html&quot;&gt;IPKat&lt;/a&gt;), the Commission is considering putting the simple act of linking to content under copyright protection. This idea flies in the face of both existing interpretation and spirit of the law as well as common sense. Each weblink would become a legal landmine and would allow press publishers to hold every single actor on the Internet liable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/validation-of-european-patents-in-moldova</id>
      <title>Validation of European patents in Moldova</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/validation-of-european-patents-in-moldova" />
      <updated>2015-11-02T22:19:58+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It will soon be possible to validate European patents and European patent applications in the Republic of Moldova. Following Morocco earlier this year, the validation agreement between the EPO and Moldova will enter into force on 1 November 2015. Similar to Morocco, Moldova is not a contracting state of the EPC, but will now recognise a European patent.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epo-makes-patent-registers-more-easily-accessible</id>
      <title>EPO makes patent registers more easily accessible</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/epo-makes-patent-registers-more-easily-accessible" />
      <updated>2015-09-24T13:27:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Patent Office (EPO) extended its Global Dossier Service to include file wrapper data from the US Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) in June this year. This means that registers at the world’s five largest intellectual property offices (USPTO, the Chinese Patent Office (SIPO), the Japanese Patent Office (JPO) and the South Korean Patent Office (KIPO)) – which together handle around 80% of the world’s patent applications and 95% of PCT applications – are now all easily accessible through the EPO.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-opinion-of-the-european-copyright-society-on-reprobel-case-c</id>
      <title>New opinion of the European Copyright Society on “Reprobel”- Case (C-572/13)</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/new-opinion-of-the-european-copyright-society-on-reprobel-case-c" />
      <updated>2015-09-19T23:52:09+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 5 September 2015, the European Copyright Society&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ceipi.edu/fileadmin/upload/DUN/CEIPI/Documents/Opinion_in_Case_C572_13_HP_Belgium_Reprobel_2015-1.pdf&quot;&gt; issued an Opinion&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=164949&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=FR&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=510908&quot;&gt;conclusions presented on June 11, 2015 by the Advocate-General &lt;/a&gt;Pedro Cruz Villalón in the &lt;em&gt;HP Belgium v. Reprobel&lt;/em&gt;-case pending before the Court of Justice of the EU (case C-572/13), following a &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=146240&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=lst&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=97500&quot;&gt;request for preliminary ruling&lt;/a&gt; from the Brussels Court of Appeal (Belgium) lodged on 8 November 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-adopts-reda-report-on-copyright-reform</id>
      <title>EU Parliament adopts Reda report on copyright reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-parliament-adopts-reda-report-on-copyright-reform" />
      <updated>2015-07-21T16:37:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament during its last plenary meeting before the summer break today adopted a non-legislative report on copyright reform prepared by Pirate Party Member Julia Reda. The report calls for an adaptation of the EU 2001 Copyright Directive to the digital market.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/freedom-of-panorama-what-is-going-on-at-the-eu-level</id>
      <title>Freedom of panorama: what is going on at the EU level?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/freedom-of-panorama-what-is-going-on-at-the-eu-level" />
      <updated>2015-06-28T21:05:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Article 5(3(h) of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=OJ:L:2001:167:0010:0019:EN:PDF&quot;&gt;InfoSoc Directive&lt;/a&gt; allows Member States to introduce into their own national copyright laws an exception to the rights of reproduction, communication/making available to the public and distribution to allow &quot;&lt;i&gt;use of works, such as works of architecture or sculpture, made to be located permanently in public places&lt;/i&gt;&quot; - the so called freedom of panorama.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;In light of a possible reform of the legislative framework in the area of copyright&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;the draft Report prepared by MEP and Pirate Party member Julia Reda on the implementation of the&lt;span class=&quot;apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;InfoSoc Directive mentioned &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;freedom of panorama be made mandatory (rather than merely optional) for Member States to implement into their own legal regimes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;the amended version of the Report, which has received &lt;a href=&quot;https://juliareda.eu/2015/06/reda-report-adopted-a-turning-point-in-the-copyright-debate/&quot;&gt;the approval of the Legal Committee&lt;/a&gt; of the European Parliament, currently includes a recommendation that &quot;&lt;i&gt;the&amp;nbsp;commercial&lt;span style=&quot;background: white;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;use of photographs, video footage or other images of works which are permanently located in&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;ins&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border: none windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0cm; padding: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-image-outset: initial; border-image-repeat: initial; border-image-slice: initial; border-image-source: initial; border-image-width: initial; font-stretch: inherit;&quot;&gt;physical&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;public places&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;ins&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border: none windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0cm; padding: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-image-outset: initial; border-image-repeat: initial; border-image-slice: initial; border-image-source: initial; border-image-width: initial; font-stretch: inherit;&quot;&gt;should always be subject to prior authorisation from the authors or any proxy acting for them&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ins&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background: white; border: none windowtext 1.0pt; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0cm; padding: 0cm;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-image-outset: initial; border-image-repeat: initial; border-image-slice: initial; border-image-source: initial; border-image-width: initial; font-stretch: inherit;&quot;&gt;&quot;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-secrets-could-undermine-fundamental-rights-i-voted-against</id>
      <title>Trade secrets could undermine fundamental rights</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/trade-secrets-could-undermine-fundamental-rights-i-voted-against" />
      <updated>2015-06-19T23:18:14+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The European Parliament’s Legal Affairs committee on Tuesday voted on draft legislative proposals on the protection of trade secrets. The European Commission states that its proposals were necessary because of the need to harmonise rules across the EU, without creating new intellectual property rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the statements, Julia Reda believes that this new legislation would introduce substantial changes into European law, which currently does not protect trade secrets. While the member states have national legislation regarding the protection of trade secrets, their definition of what can be considered a trade secret is often much more narrow. The adoption of the European directive could therefore significantly broaden companies‘ abilities to keep certain information away from the public eye.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-legislation-is-pushing-people-to-piracy</id>
      <title>EU: copyright legislation is pushing people to piracy</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-legislation-is-pushing-people-to-piracy" />
      <updated>2015-06-18T15:29:29+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Speaking at Midem yesterday, Andrus Ansip of the European Commission shared his vision for the Digital Single Market. Noting that geo-blocking is bad for business, Ansip said that opening up content across borders and providing good legal options is the best way to tackle piracy. &quot;Our legislation is pushing people to steal,&quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/commissioner-oettinger-plaids-for-a-unified-eu-digital-market-to</id>
      <title>Commissioner Oettinger plaids for a unified EU digital market to resist internet giants such as Amazon, Google, Microsoft</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/commissioner-oettinger-plaids-for-a-unified-eu-digital-market-to" />
      <updated>2015-06-10T13:29:15+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the framework of the Cannes Festival a symposium on copyright was organized with the participation of Günther Oettinger Commissioner for Digital Economy and Society. The European Commission put forward an extensive action plan to create a unified EU digital market and a reformed and unique EU copyright instead of having 28 national ones.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-and-italy-want-to-expand-the-geographical-indications-pro</id>
      <title>France and Italy want to expand the geographical indications protection system</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/france-and-italy-want-to-expand-the-geographical-indications-pro" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T08:53:07+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A small number of World Intellectual Property Organization members this week are negotiating to expand a the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/lisbon/en/legal_texts/&quot;&gt;Lisbon System&lt;/a&gt; for the International Registration of Appellations of Origin to protect geographical indications, products like Champagne.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The treaty is administered by WIPO, which keeps the International Register of Appellations of Origin. Under the Lisbon system, once registered in the international register, an appellation of origin grants protection in all member countries, without any need for renewal, for as long as the appellation is protected in the country of origin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lisbon members are currently seeking to approve a new act of the agreement, extending the protection granted by the system to geographical indications. They are holding a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wipo.int/meetings/en/details.jsp?meeting_id=35202&quot;&gt;diplomatic conference&lt;/a&gt; within WIPO from 11-21 May (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ip-watch.org/2015/05/14/substantive-work-on-amendment-of-lisbon-system-starts-new-language-proposed/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;IPW&lt;/em&gt;, WIPO, 14 May 2015&lt;/a&gt;) to that effect.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ec-research-finds-shutting-down-of-pirate-sites-ineffective</id>
      <title>EC research finds shutting down of pirate sites ineffective</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/ec-research-finds-shutting-down-of-pirate-sites-ineffective" />
      <updated>2015-05-19T21:39:05+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New research from the European Commission’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/jrc/&quot;&gt;Joint Research Centre&lt;/a&gt; shows that shutting down pirate website such as The Pirate Bay is relatively ineffective and potentially counterproductive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2604197&quot;&gt;working paper&lt;/a&gt; entitled “Online Copyright Enforcement, Consumer Behavior, and Market Structure” researchers examined clickstream data to see how legal and illegal consumption habits changed in response to the shutdown. Results show a short-lived decrease in piracy (after which piracy levels return to normal) and only a small increase in the use of legal services.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo</id>
      <title>Leaked Digital Single Market strategy addresses copyright and geo-blocking, e-privacy and the role of ISPs</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/politico-leaks-draft-digital-single-market-strategy-tackling-geo" />
      <updated>2015-05-18T11:17:10+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leaked copies of the upcoming Digital Single Market Strategy and its supporting Evidence file show the European Commission is ready to propose vast regulatory reforms that could affect everything from sales taxes and e-privacy to Internet searches and big data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commissioners-at-odds-over-geo-blocking-1</id>
      <title>EU commissioners at odds over geo-blocking</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-commissioners-at-odds-over-geo-blocking-1" />
      <updated>2015-04-06T15:21:34+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Less than a week after EU digital commissioner Andrus Ansip announced he wants to end geo-blocking, his fellow commissioner Gunther Oettinger indicated he was in no rush to abolish the practice of restricting online content based on someone&#039;s location.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-landmark-decision-from-the-cjeu-on-private-copying-levies-case</id>
      <title>CJEU preliminary ruling on private copying levies: Case C-463/12 Copydan Båndkopi</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/a-landmark-decision-from-the-cjeu-on-private-copying-levies-case" />
      <updated>2015-03-07T18:05:31+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This morning the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) issued its &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=162691&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=530739&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: red;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;in Case C-463/12 &lt;i&gt;Copydan Båndkopi&lt;/i&gt;, a reference for a preliminary ruling from Denmark, seeking clarification on key questions relating to the so-called ‘private copying’ exception under Article 5(2)(b) of the Information Society Directive &lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=celex:32001L0029&quot;&gt;2001/29.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-news-cjeu-says-that-member-states-are-free-to-determine</id>
      <title>CJEU says that Member States are free to determine who must pay droit de suite royalty</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/breaking-news-cjeu-says-that-member-states-are-free-to-determine" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T14:12:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;This morning the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) issued in fact its decision&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;in Case C-41/14 &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?language=en&amp;amp;td=ALL&amp;amp;num=C-41/14&quot;&gt;Christie&#039;s France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, a reference for a preliminary ruling from France seeking clarification as regards that peculiar creature of EU copyright known as artist&#039;s resale right, or&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;droit de suite&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;within&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:32001L0084:EN:HTML&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Directive 2001/84/EC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;(the Resale Right Directive).&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-report-on-copyright-is-the-eu-really-a-beacon-of-human-rights</id>
      <title>UN report on copyright – is the EU really a beacon of human rights?</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/un-report-on-copyright-is-the-eu-really-a-beacon-of-human-rights" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:12:48+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Copyright has seen a spectacular rise in importance, both politically and legally, in recent decades. The digitisation of cultural and scientific goods has led many rights holders to see strengthened copyright protection as the only means of ensuring the survival of the cultural industry. To a large extent the rights holders’ quest for more legal protection has succeeded – today’s copyright protections are as strong and broad as never before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Farida Shaheed, the United Nations (UN) Special Rapporteur in the field of cultural rights, this has caused increasing tension between copyright law and human rights law. Her report on “Copyright policy and the right to science and culture” is diplomatically worded but argues strongly that we need to pay more attention to the human rights repercussions of granting authors – and rights holders – exclusive rights over authorial works.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-failing-to-support-copyright-reform</id>
      <title>European Parliament failing to support copyright reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-parliament-failing-to-support-copyright-reform" />
      <updated>2015-02-27T16:09:20+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone is talking about EU copyright reform. However, in the European Parliament, everyone is having the same discussions on enforcement that they were having ten years ago – and talking about stopping any reform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Draft Report “Towards a renewed consensus on the enforcement of Intellectual Property Rights: An EU Action Plan” (2014/2151(INI)) presented by Member of the European Parliament (MEP) Pavel Svoboda reacts supportively to the rather bland, regressive and unimaginative Commission Communication of the same name. Sadly, Mr Svoboda seems to be choosing to support the mistakes that the Commission’s view that the failures of the last ten years should be the model for the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-share-your-opinion-on-copyright</id>
      <title>Julia Reda: Share your opinion on copyright</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-share-your-opinion-on-copyright" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:04:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, a reform of the Copyright-legislation will be started. On behalf of the European Parliament, Julia Reda is currently working on an evaluation of the current Copyright directive. The stakeholders who are loudest so far are the collective societies but creators themselves are heard much too seldom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do the plans of the collecting societies really reflect the interests of all&amp;nbsp;artists? Are they satisfied with the legislative status quo? Do they really want to re-negotiate the rights for their works for each country or would they prefer&amp;nbsp;a single European market? Are they really opposed to&amp;nbsp;remixes? What would their priorities be&amp;nbsp;when it comes to updating the&amp;nbsp;copyright&amp;nbsp;framework?&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/launching-of-the-orphan-works-database</id>
      <title>Launching of the orphan works database</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/launching-of-the-orphan-works-database" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:56:37+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EU’s Office for Harmonisation in the Internal Market (OHIM) has recently launched the online Orphan Works Database. The database was created and is managed by the OHIM in accordance with Directive 2012/28/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 25 October 2012 on certain permitted uses of orphan works).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Orphan Works Database is a single EU-wide publicly accessible online database that provides information related to orphan works located in publicly accessible libraries, educational establishments and museums, as well as in archives, film or audio heritage institutions and public-service broadcasting organisations, established in all EU Member States (beneficiary organisations).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-reform-responses-to-julia-redas-draft-report-and-what</id>
      <title>Copyright Reform: Responses to Julia Reda&#039;s draft report and what comes next</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-reform-responses-to-julia-redas-draft-report-and-what" />
      <updated>2015-02-17T18:22:04+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The draft European Parliament report on the InfoSoc Directive, sometimes also called the Copyright Directive, has generated an enormous wave of responses. It was presented by the Member of the Parliament (MEP) responsible for leading the file, Julia Reda, to the Committee on Legal Affairs (JURI) on 20 January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the next steps and what is the report’s ultimate significance? After all of the relevant Committees have transmitted their opinions, JURI will vote on the report and transmit it to the Plenary. If it is adopted there, it becomes a non-legislative and non-binding resolution in which the Parliament states its current position on certain matters of copyright reform. The Parliament hereby communicates to the Commission what it expects of future copyright legislation. This in turn can shape the Commission’s proposal for copyright reform, which is expected within this year. The Parliament has a notoriously short memory, especially of its own positions, so it will not consider itself bound by anything it decides upon now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/exhaustion-of-rights-the-broader-implications-of-the-cjeus-rulin</id>
      <title>Exhaustion of rights - the broader implications of the CJEU&#039;s ruling in Art &amp; Allposters</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/exhaustion-of-rights-the-broader-implications-of-the-cjeus-rulin" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:32:03+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The principle of exhaustion is a hot topic in copyright with important commercial ramifications, particularly in relation to &#039;online exhaustion&#039; and the viability of a second-hand market in digital content.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A key aspect of the CJEU’s ruling is its view that the exhaustion of the distribution right under the InfoSoc Directive covers the tangible object into which a work (or a copy of it) is incorporated. In other words, it is inherently tied to the physical medium (e.g. paper, canvas) on which the work is expressed.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-confirms-accessibility-criterion-to-determine-jurisdiction</id>
      <title>CJEU confirms accessibility criterion to determine jurisdiction in online copyright infringement cases</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-confirms-accessibility-criterion-to-determine-jurisdiction" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:56:59+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;The general rule of jurisdiction in Article 2 of the Brussels I Regulation is that &quot;&lt;i&gt;persons domiciled in a Member State shall, whatever their nationality, be sued in the courts of that Member State&lt;/i&gt;&quot;. However, &quot;&lt;i&gt;in matters relating to tort, delict or quasi-delict&lt;/i&gt;,&quot; one may be alternatively sued &quot;&lt;i&gt;in the courts for the place where the harmful event occurred or may occur&lt;/i&gt;&quot;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Locating such &quot;&lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;&quot; has not always been an easy task when it comes to unregistered rights such as personality rights or copyright. Indeed, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the Court of Justice of the European Union has struggled with the interpretation of Article 5(3) Brussels I/Article 7(2) Brussels I Recast, and has adopted a number of different criteria. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;When an unregistered right has been allegedly infringed online, what court is competent to hear and decide the resulting case?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-exhaustion-only-applies-to-the-tangible-medium-of-a-wo</id>
      <title>CJEU says exhaustion only applies to the tangible medium of a work</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-exhaustion-only-applies-to-the-tangible-medium-of-a-wo" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T18:56:11+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Today CJEU ruled that w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; text-align: justify; text-indent: -26.95pt;&quot;&gt;ith regard to the adaptation right, it is true that the InfoSoc Directive does not mention it. However, a situation like the one at hand, &lt;i&gt;ie &lt;/i&gt;paper poster and canvas transfer of copyright-protected works,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; text-align: justify; text-indent: -26.95pt;&quot;&gt;falls within the scope of Article&amp;nbsp;4(1) of the InfoSoc Directive. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Also, exhaustion of the right of distribution under&amp;nbsp;under Article 4(2) of the InfoSoc Directive&amp;nbsp;only applies to the tangible support of a work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-pirate-mep-kicks-off-eu-copyright-debate</id>
      <title>German Pirate MEP kicks off EU copyright debate</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/german-pirate-mep-kicks-off-eu-copyright-debate" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:48:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;German pirate MEP Julia Reda presented her report on copyright reform to journalists on Monday (19 January). According to her, there should be one copyright law that applies to all EU member states, fixing the legal “absurdities” of the current regime.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-rules-maladapted-to-the-internet-upcoming-parliamen</id>
      <title>EU copyright rules maladapted to the Internet, upcoming Parliamentary report finds</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-copyright-rules-maladapted-to-the-internet-upcoming-parliamen" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:46:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU copyright rules are maladapted to the increase of cross-border cultural exchange facilitated by the Internet&lt;/strong&gt;, an upcoming European Parliament own-initiative report evaluating 2001’s copyright directive finds. The &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://pub.juliareda.eu/copyright_evaluation_report.pdf&quot;&gt;draft released today&lt;/a&gt; by Julia Reda, MEP for the German Pirate Party, lays out an ambitious reform agenda for the overhaul of EU copyright announced in the Commission’s 2015 work programme.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/monaco-devoid-of-distinctive-character-rules-eu-court</id>
      <title>Monaco &quot;devoid of distinctive character&quot;, rules EU court</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/monaco-devoid-of-distinctive-character-rules-eu-court" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:49:55+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Judgment was delivered today by the General Court&amp;nbsp;in &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/documents.jsf?num=T-197/13&quot;&gt;Case T-197/13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Monaco v OHIM&lt;/i&gt;. The Principality of Monaco cannot benefit from the protection of the trade mark MONACO in the EU in respect of certain goods and services. The word ‘MONACO’ designates the origin or geographical destination of the goods and services concerned and is devoid of distinctive character.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-that-owner-of-an-online-database-not-protected-by-copy</id>
      <title>CJEU says that owner of an online database not protected by copyright or sui generis right may restrict its use by contract</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-says-that-owner-of-an-online-database-not-protected-by-copy" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:49:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#039;Trebuchet MS&#039;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;The CJEU has just issued its 46-paragraph&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/document/document.jsf?text=&amp;amp;docid=161388&amp;amp;pageIndex=0&amp;amp;doclang=EN&amp;amp;mode=req&amp;amp;dir=&amp;amp;occ=first&amp;amp;part=1&amp;amp;cid=331775&quot;&gt;decision&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Case C-30/14&lt;span class=&quot;apple-converted-space&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ryanair&lt;/i&gt;, a reference for a preliminary ruling from The Netherlands seeking clarification as regards the&lt;span class=&quot;apple-converted-space&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:31996L0009&amp;amp;from=EN&quot;&gt;Database Directive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &#039;Trebuchet MS&#039;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;The CJEU ruled that the Database Directive only&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot; lang=&quot;FR-BE&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;applies to databases protected by copyright or the sui generis right, and that the holder of a publicly accessible database is free to determine by contract&amp;nbsp;and in compliance with the applicable national law the conditions of use of its database.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-judgments-in-2015-whats-in-the-pipeline-from-the-cjeu</id>
      <title>Copyright judgments in 2015: what’s in the pipeline from the CJEU</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/copyright-judgments-in-2015-whats-in-the-pipeline-from-the-cjeu" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T00:57:39+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2015 will be another busy copyright year for the CJEU, starting with Case &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?num=C-30/14&quot;&gt;C-30/14&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Ryanair&lt;/i&gt; (copyright/database rights) this Thursday, followed a week later on 22 January by &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?num=C-419/13&quot;&gt;C-419/13&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Art &amp;amp; Allposters&lt;/i&gt; (exhaustion of rights) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?&amp;amp;num=C-441/13&quot;&gt;C-441/13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hejduk &lt;/i&gt;(online jurisdictional issues). Later this year, we expect to see rulings in &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?num=C-279/13&quot;&gt;C-279/13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;C More Entertainment&lt;/i&gt; (hyperlinks) and 3 cases on the scope of the private copying exception: &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?&amp;amp;num=C-463/12&quot;&gt;C-463/12&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Copydan&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?&amp;amp;num=C-572/13&quot;&gt;C-572/13&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Hewlett-Packard&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?language=en&amp;amp;jur=C,T,F&amp;amp;num=C-470/14%20P&amp;amp;td=ALL%20%E2%80%9CC-470/14%E2%80%9D&quot;&gt;C-470/14&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Egeda&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-negotiating-texts-in-ttip</id>
      <title>EU negotiating texts in TTIP</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/eu-negotiating-texts-in-ttip" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:52:18+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP) between Europe and the United States have been published by the European Commission.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-is-asked-preliminary-questions-on-ford-case</id>
      <title>CJEU is asked preliminary questions on Ford case</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-is-asked-preliminary-questions-on-ford-case" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:06:57+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?language=en&amp;amp;jur=C,T,F&amp;amp;num=C-500/14&amp;amp;td=ALL&quot;&gt;Case C-500/14&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ford Motor Company &lt;/i&gt;is a reference &lt;/b&gt;made by the Tribunale ordinario di Torino, Italy, for a preliminary ruling by the Court of Justice of the European Union (CJEU) on a matter that has been raised before the Italian courts on a number of occasions in recent years -- the unauthorised manufacture of &quot;spare part&quot; wheel trims bearing the trade marks of the original manufacturer in order to enable the purchaser to make sure that his purchase matches the appearance of the rest of his car. The subtle twist here is not however whether there is an infringement of any trade mark rights but whether there is a defence based on European design law.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-is-in-charge-of-fixing-the-eu-copyright-law</id>
      <title>Julia Reda is in charge of fixing the EU Copyright Law</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/julia-reda-is-in-charge-of-fixing-the-eu-copyright-law" />
      <updated>2015-03-16T23:53:16+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Julia Reda, the MEP representative for the Pirate Party from Germany is the rapporteur for the European Union copyright reform dossier - that is the report on the implementation of the previous directive on this matter from 2001 (the so-called &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32001L0029&amp;amp;from=EN&quot;&gt;“Infosoc Directive”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/advocate-general-says-the-distribution-right-includes-right-to-p</id>
      <title>Advocate General says the distribution right includes right to prevent offer for sale of a work</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/advocate-general-says-the-distribution-right-includes-right-to-p" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:22:44+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;The Advocate General&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt; held that&amp;nbsp;Article 4(1) of the InfoSoc Directive must be interpreted in the sense that the right to distribution within the meaning of that provision includes the right of the copyright owner of the original or copies thereof to prohibit anyone from offering for sale to the public said original or the copies without his/her consent, provided that such offer displays a clear intention to conclude a contract that would involve the transfer of ownership over the original or the copies of a work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-patent-office-strike</id>
      <title>European Patent Office strike</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/european-patent-office-strike" />
      <updated>2014-12-04T10:55:50+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the 2nd of December, the European Patent Office employees took to the streets of Munich to express their extreme anxiety and disquiet at the state of governance of the office that, if things go according to plan, will soon be responsible for administering the unitary patent system that will provide patent protection across almost all of the European Union&#039;s Member States. More unrest and anxiety is building up &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Trebuchet MS, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;regarding the running of the European Patent Office, its staff relations, finances and other issues.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-case-on-liability-for-copyright-infringements-if-offering-p</id>
      <title>CJEU case on liability for copyright infringements if offering password-free free internet access</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/cjeu-case-on-liability-for-copyright-infringements-if-offering-p" />
      <updated>2015-06-09T13:00:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://curia.europa.eu/juris/liste.jsf?pro=&amp;amp;lgrec=en&amp;amp;nat=or&amp;amp;oqp=&amp;amp;dates=&amp;amp;lg=&amp;amp;language=en&amp;amp;jur=C%2CT%2CF&amp;amp;cit=none%252CC%252CCJ%252CR%252C2008E%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252C%252Ctrue%252Cfalse%252Cfalse&amp;amp;num=C-484%252F14&amp;amp;td=%3BALL&amp;amp;pcs=Oor&amp;amp;avg=&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;mat=or&amp;amp;jge=&amp;amp;for=&amp;amp;cid=98207&quot;&gt;Case C-484/14 McFadden&lt;/a&gt;, a reference for a preliminary ruling from Germany is seeking clarification as regards the liability of internet service providers (ISPs) for third-party copyright infringements.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;If a person offers free non-password-protected access to the Internet, and an unknown user passes a piece of copyright-infringing music over that Internet connection, then can the person offering the Internet access be absolved of legal liability on the basis that he is but a ‘mere conduit’ under [Article 12 of] the EU’s ‘E-Commerce’ Directive 2000/31/EC [read in light of Recital 42 in the preamble to this very directive]?&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;More facts about the case are available &lt;a href=&quot;http://eulawradar.com/case-c-48414-mcfadden-a-mere-conduit/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/community-trade-mark-applications-will-now-only-be-examined-afte</id>
      <title>Community trade mark applications will now only be examined after they are paid for</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/community-trade-mark-applications-will-now-only-be-examined-afte" />
      <updated>2014-11-15T13:25:00+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify&quot;&gt;From November 24, OHIM will only examine trade mark applications and process any mail related to them after they are paid for. This means the Office can be more efficient, as it will no longer examine applications that ultimately will never be paid for. OHIM is a European Union agency that serves businesses across the EU.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-and-french-copyright-laws-ban-photos-of-ep-buildings-1</id>
      <title>Belgian and French copyright laws ban photos of EP buildings</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/belgian-and-french-copyright-laws-ban-photos-of-ep-buildings-1" />
      <updated>2015-03-17T01:25:33+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;color: rgb(68, 68, 68); line-height: 20px; margin-top: 0px; font-family: arial;&quot;&gt;An obscure clause in EU copyright rules means no one can publish photos of public buildings in Belgium, like the Atomium, or France’s Eiffel tower at night without first asking permission from the rights owners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;color: rgb(68, 68, 68); line-height: 20px; margin-top: 20px; font-family: arial;&quot;&gt;The optional rule extends to the buildings of the European Parliament in Brussels and in Strasbourg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;color: rgb(68, 68, 68); line-height: 20px; margin-top: 20px; font-family: arial;&quot;&gt;“Every website of every MEP that uses [an image of] the parliament building on it is a copyright infringement in the sense of the law,” said Dimitar Dimitrov, a so-called Wikimedian or policy expert for the European Wikimedia chapters in Brussels, on Tuesday (4 November).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;color: rgb(68, 68, 68); line-height: 20px; margin-top: 20px; font-family: arial;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/our-single-market-is-crying-out-for-copyright-reform</id>
      <title>Our single market is crying out for copyright reform</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/our-single-market-is-crying-out-for-copyright-reform" />
      <updated>2014-09-23T11:47:38+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our duty as lawmakers is to find a balance between creators and the justified interests of society. Yet that balance is changing. Transforming technology is changing how people use and re-use information. And disrupting a longstanding legal framework. What should a sound EU copyright system do?&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
      <entry>
      <id>http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/summary-report-of-the-responses-to-the-copyright-public-consulta</id>
      <title>Summary report of the responses to the copyright public consultation</title>
      <link href="http://observatory.mappingtheinternet.eu/item/summary-report-of-the-responses-to-the-copyright-public-consulta" />
      <updated>2014-09-22T16:59:02+02:00</updated>
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On 23 July 2014 the European Commission Directorate General Internal Market and Services (DG MARKT) published Summary Report of the Responses to the public consultation on the review of the EU copyright rules. The consultation held between 5 December 2013 and 5 March 2014 was part of the European Commission’s effort to review and modernise copyright rules in the EU and to adapt the current system to the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    </entry>
  </feed>
